<TEI xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="jwgarri_12010">
  <teiHeader xml:id="jwgarri1201"><fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Garrison Gossip, an electronic edition</title>
        <author><name><choice><sic><name type="person">John Strange Winter</name></sic><reg>Stannard, Henrietta Eliza Vaughan Palmer</reg></choice></name></author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent>400kb</extent>
      <publicationStmt><publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher><pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace><date>2005</date><availability>
          <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301">© 2005, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original contributions made by the Women's Genre Fiction Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA 30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email: beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability><idno type="ark">http://pid.emory.edu/ark:/25593/17337</idno></publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>Women's Genre Fiction, 1860-1920</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Sheila T. Cavanagh</name>
          <name>Charles D. Spornick</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        <name/></respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl><author><name><choice><sic/><reg/></choice></name></author>. <title>Garrison Gossip</title>. <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>:
<publisher>F. V. White &amp; Co.</publisher>, <date>1888</date>.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc><encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1302">This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part of the Women's Genre Fiction Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes. This project is funded by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1303">The title page, selected front matter, and body text of novels and
stories have been transcribed and encoded. Paratextual elements such
as covers, illustrations, front matter, and advertisements are
provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1304">Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF images
of each page using either a flatbed scanner or a PowerPhase FX digital
camera. Text pages were captured in grayscale at 400dpi while
illustrations and covers were captured in color at 300dpi. These
digital images were converted to an electronic text file by Optical
Character Recognition (OCR) software.  The text files produced by the
OCR software have been proofread against the original novel or TIFF
images of the original novel. This proofread text file has then been
encoded using the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries
Guidelines. For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the
webpage for TEI Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/. Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes. Page numbers displayed in brackets have been
added by the encoder and do not appear in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc><profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Genre Fiction</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Unedited</rs>
        <rs type="genre">Short Stories</rs>
        <rs type="geography">Great Britain</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="#lcsh">
          <list>
            <item>British literature--19th Century--Fiction.</item>
            <item>Women authors, British--19th Century.</item>
            <item>Short stories.</item>
            <item>Military life.</item>
            <item>Romance.</item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc><revisionDesc><change><date>2005-June-24</date><label>project manager.</label><name>Erika Farr, </name>XML tags inserted in compliance with TEI guidelines.</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>
  <text xml:id="jwgarri_1209">
    <front xml:id="jwgarri_1202">
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_000" type="covers">
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarrifc" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>Front cover of Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarribc" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>Back cover of Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarrisp" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>The spine of Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
      </div>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_001" type="adverts">
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarriad1" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>Advertisement included inside the front cover of Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1305"/>
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarriad2" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>Advertisement included in the front of Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1306"/>
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarriad3" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>Advertisement included in the front of Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
      </div>
      <pb pages="Title Page" facs="jwgarritp"/>
      <titlePage xml:id="jwgarri_1308" type="full">
        <docTitle>
          <titlePart type="main">GARRISON GOSSIP</titlePart>
          <titlePart type="sub">GATHERED IN BLANKHAMPTON.</titlePart>
          <titlePart type="sub">A Novel.</titlePart>
        </docTitle>
        <byline>BY <lb/><docAuthor>JOHN STRANGE WINTER,</docAuthor><lb/>Author of <lb/>"ARMY SOCIETY," "BOOTLES' BABY," "HOUP-LA,"
<lb/>"ON MARCH," "IN QUARTERS," "CAVALRY LIFE," "PLUCK,"
<lb/>"MIGNON'S SECRET," "THAT IMP," "MIGNON'S HUSBAND,"
<lb/>"CONFESSIONS OF A PUBLISHER," &amp;c., &amp;c.</byline>
        <docEdition>FOURTH EDITION.</docEdition>
        <docImprint>
          <pubPlace>LONDON:</pubPlace>
          <publisher>F. V. WHITE &amp; CO.,</publisher>
          <pubPlace>31, SOUTHAMPTON STREET, STRAND, W.C.</pubPlace>
          <docDate>1888.</docDate>
        </docImprint>
      </titlePage>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1309"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_002" type="advert">
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarriad4" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>Advertisement included in the front of Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13010"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_005" type="table of contents">
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarritc1" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>Table of contents for Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13011"/>
        <figure><graphic url="ENTITY_jwgarritc2" rend="inline"/>
          <figDesc>Table of contents for Strange's <hi rend="italic">Garrison Gossip</hi>.</figDesc>
        </figure>
      </div>
    </front>
    <body xml:id="jwgarri_1207">
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13012" n="1"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_011" n="1" type="chapter">
        <head>GARRISON GOSSIP: <lb/>Gathered in Blankhampton.
<lb/>CHAPTER I.<lb/>"SHE'S A' I' THE WARLD TAE ME."</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_13013">"Marriage is like a man taking a leap in the dark, in which he may chance to alight upon his feet, and be in comparative safety or, on the contrary, be dashed to pieces."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—BALZAC.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13015">WHEN Lord Charterhouse came to the conclusion that he did not want to marry Polly Antrobus, he also decided that he would send in his papers forth-with, go up to Town and ask his cousin, Lady Nell Temple, to marry him at once. But, when morning light came upon him, he did not quite carry out that programme; he changed his mind. Not about Lady Nell. No. His mind had in reality been made up about <hi rend="italic">her</hi> for ages, ever since they had been tiny dots of bairns. But his people and her people had both found out that such a marriage would be a very desirable end for the two families to <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13014" n="2 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>work to, and as this fact had been dinned into his ears ever since he left Eton and began to think about the army, Lord Charterhouse had, not unnaturally, been rather against the scheme than for it. Not against Lady Nell! Oh, no! <hi rend="italic">that</hi> he had never been at any period of his two-and-twenty years of existence.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13016">But he did change his mind about leaving the army.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13017">"Hang it all!" he said to himself as he felt the edge of his razor that morning, "Hang it all! it's downright mean to go clearing out of the service before I say a word to Nell. She was always so keen on 'following the drum,' as she called it. No; I thinly I'll give her the chance of a year or two's service before I send in my papers."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13018">So he went straight off to the office and asked Urquhart for three days' leave, which he got, where-upon he went gaily off to Town and made his way to a certain pretty little creeper-covered house in Queen's Gate, where he put the question to Lady Nell, plump and straight, and then went more gaily off to New Bond Street to buy an engagement ring. For Lady Nell said "Yes!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13019">And then—Lady Nell having utterly scouted the idea of leaving the service for at least a year or two—he returned to Blankhampton, and neither said nor, for the matter of that, thought anything more about sending in his papers.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13021">He arrived about half-an-hour before dinner-time, to find, naturally, the ante-room deserted. So <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13020" n="3 SHE'S A' I' THE WARLD TAE ME."/>he went off to his quarters and dressed for mess, and then, having ten minutes to spare, looked in upon Lester Brookes, who said:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13022">"Hullo, Winks! Is that you? How are you, old chap?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13023">"Pretty fit, thanks," returned Mr. Winks—they invariably called him "Mr. Winks" or "Winks" among themselves in the Black Horse—"What's the news?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13024">"News? Oh! well—er—Orford's done it at last."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13025">"Done what?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13026">"He's going to be married."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13027">"Orford? By Jove! you don't mean it. And a very good thing, too, for him. Who's the lady?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13028">"Miss Trafford."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13029">"<hi rend="italic">Miss</hi>—Traff—ord? Nonsense! That must be about as true as the Colonel's engagement to the little mother," cried Mr. Winks, incredulously.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13030">"It's true enough. Orford announced it himself the other night after dinner; but it's not one of Mrs. Traff's daughters. It's the niece."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13031">"Oh! the niece. Ah! well, of course that makes it rather different. Still, I shouldn't exactly care to marry into that family myself."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13032">"Blankhampton families are all pretty much of a muchness," remarked Brookes with a meaning air.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13034">"Yes; I daresay. I shouldn't quite care to marry into any Blankhampton family," said Mr. <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13033" n="4 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>Winks coolly. "By-the-bye, I <hi rend="italic">am</hi> going to be married, almost at once."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13035">"The deuce you are? And who's the lady?" asked Brookes, who, like many another of the units constituting "Sassiety" in the old city, had been wondering for weeks past whether Lord Charterhouse really would take the plunge and raise Polly Antrobus to the peerage or not, and now felt not a little surprised to hear that there was a rival in the field "Who's the lady?" he asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13036">"My cousin, Lady Nell Temple," answered Lord Charterhouse promptly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13037">"By Jove! Well, old fellow, I heartily congratulate you, hope you'll be awfully happy and all that," Brookes cried; and then they shook hands over the news, and Mr. Winks said:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13038">"Thanks—thanks old fellow, I'm sure."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13039">There was the usual little pause, half of shyness half of awkwardness, which always seems to fall upon Englishmen after any little touch of sentiment or small display of feeling, the sort of pause which a couple of Frenchmen would fill up by kissing one another. And then Mr. Winks suggested that they would be late for mess, whereupon they went off to the mess-room with a sigh of relief, each of them.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13040">It still wanted ten minutes to the dinner-hour when they reached the verandah of the ante-room, where they found seven or eight officers, who hailed Mr. Winks with a sharp fire of chaff.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13042">"Why, Winks," cried Orford gaily, "what joy to <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13041" n="5 SHE'S A' I' THE WARLD TAE ME."/>see you back again. My dear chap, she's been looking for you morning, noon, and night like the personification of Ophelia. She only needed her yellow hair hanging in dishevelled masses about her fair cheeks, and a few straws and wild flowers, to be quite perfect for the part."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13043">"I'm sorry for that, whoever she is," returned Mr. Winks coolly, "for I am not at all inclined to take the part of Hamlet, in fact, I'm cast for another <hi rend="italic">rôle</hi> altogether."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13044">The remark was taken up and commented upon instantly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13045">"Cast for another <hi rend="italic">rôle</hi>?" repeated Dayrell. "Why, Mr. Winks, you don't mean——"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13046">"Of course he does," cried Staunton with a laugh. "Have you been home to ask your mother's leave, Winks?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13047">"You shouldn't have gone up and asked her," laughed St. Maur. "You should have got her to come to Blankhampton, and be introduced to the whole family here. Lady Charterhouse would then have been able to take the whole bearings of the proposition."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13048">To all of which Mr. Winks listened with unruffled demeanour, and presently electrified everybody at the dinner table, excepting Lester Brookes, by rising in his place and saying:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13049">"Gentlemen, I have the honour to announce to you my engagement to my cousin, Lady Nell Temple."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13051">By which the officers of the Black Horse became <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13050" n="6 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>aware that Poly Antrobus had had one more practical experience of the old saw which says, "There's many a slip 'twixt the cup and the lip."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13052">"By-the-bye," said Marcus Orford, after a while, to Lester Brookes, "I heard a piece of news in the town to-day. The second Miss Antrobus is going to be married."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13053">"By Jove! Going to be married? You don't say so. To whom?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13054">"Some man called—er—Brentham; Herrick Brentham."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13055">"Not a Blankhampton man, surely?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13056">"Oh, no. Someone she's met away from here. And, I hear, an awfully good match; fellow seems to be rolling in money, and desirable in every way; six feet high, and very handsome—so the old lady says—utterly devoted to To-To, and they're going to be married in about six weeks."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13057">"By Jove! Imagine any fellow <hi rend="italic">wanting</hi> to marry that little bag of bones. Of course she's very pretty—I don't know if she isn't almost as pretty as her sister. But I always thought she was booked to Devreux of the Yellow Horse."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13059">"Not a bit of it," with a laugh. "I met him in St. James's the last time I was in Town, and asked him outright—because, you know, it seemed to me, knowing him well, about the most unlikely marriage, or at least engagement, I'd ever heard of. Well, Devreux simply laughed in my face, asked me if my wits had gone wool-gathering, or if I thought he was a lunatic? Oh, no, I fancy the Brentham man <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13058" n="7 SHE'S A' I' THE WARLD TAE ME."/>had quite a clear field. Anyway, he's going to marry her, that's certain."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13060">"You haven't seen him yet?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13061">"No; I only heard of it this afternoon," Orford answered.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13062">"I see. Well, I think I shall go and call to-morrow and hear all details. By-the-bye, did you ever hear that joke about Sinclair of the 28th?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13063">"No, I've heard of Sinclair, of course," Orford replied, "but never in connection with the fair Polly. What was it?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13065">"Mrs. Fairlie told me—she don't care much about Mrs. Antrobus; by-the-bye, I don't fancy she cares much about anybody in Blankhampton, at least, one always seems to get the last bit of gossip and the least-known stories about everyone from her. Well, it seems that after Mrs. Antrobus's bad shot at the Trelawneys and Taff Pierrepoint, she determined to eschew officers' wives entirely for the future, and therefore, sent old Antrobus to call on the mess of the 28th and stayed at home herself, just like a fat old spider in a web. You know the style of thing—'Will you walk into my parlour?' and all that! Well, in time, two very likely-looking flies made their appearance and inspected the parlour, admired the fair Polly, of course, and took stock of the benignant old lady in the corner. Then one backed out, and thought he didn't feel inclined to go in any urther—must have been a cautious young gentle-<pb xml:id="jwgarri_13064" n="8 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>man, who felt himself safest just then outside the web of holy matrimony.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13066">"But the other, a big, overpowering bluebottle, as full of importance as you please (and, between ourselves, doesn't that hit off Sinclair to a T?)—and as Mrs. Fairlie put it, 'a big, well set-up fellow, with a straight nose, and a pair of melancholy eyes,' not only ventured in, but fell down at Polly's feet and—<hi rend="italic">grovelled!</hi></p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13067">"Mrs. Hugh, as Mrs. Fairlie calls her, was radiant at the result of her skilful generalship. What mattered past defeats, when they were swallowed up in victory? What mattered the bygone fogs and mists, when the glorious sunshine of achievement had come to sweep them away for ever? What did she care for the failures of yesterday, when the successes of to-day amply compensated for all unpleasantnesses and vexations? In short, to put Mrs. Hugh's reflections into less grandiloquent but more everyday language than she generally goes in for, she evidently didn't care a little hang for all that was gone by, the Cardellas, the Trelawneys, and Taff Pierrepoint all put together; but she just worked away at her parlour and cleared away every relic—wings and legs, so to speak—of former victims, escaped or defunct. And she gathered dew-drops to brighten odd corners, and coaxed in little rays of sunshine to brighten big bluebottle's eyes, while Polly looked pretty and said nothing.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13069">"'Such a <hi rend="italic">comfort</hi> to me, said Mrs. Hugh one <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13068" n="9 SHE'S A' I' THE WARLD TAE ME."/>day in her blandest tones to Mrs. Fairlie, as they sat under the veranda in sweet <hi rend="italic">al fresco</hi> friendship and watched big Bluebottle philandering about the garden with Polly, 'that Polly has never been in-duced to avail herself of the really may-nificent opportunities that have been held out to her of establishing herself. Captain Sin-claiah is so charming, such a per-fect gentleman, and <hi rend="italic">madly</hi> in love with her, that I feel he is the <hi rend="italic">only</hi> man in the world who would be able to make her happy. Indeed, I am per-fectly satisfied in ev-ery way.'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13070">"'Then they are engaged?' said Mrs. Fairlie, wondering that she hadn't heard of it earlier.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13071">"'No; <hi rend="italic">not</hi> yet,' Mrs. Hugh replied. 'He has not yet spoken <hi rend="italic">plainly</hi> to her; but we are <hi rend="italic">quite</hi> satisfied. He is negotiating for the Willoughbys' house, just as it stands. He means to use it as a hunting-box after the regiment leaves Blankhampton, and, of course, that will be very pleasant for us.'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13073">"Well—it really was too bad; but you've seen a great, big, blundering bluebottle go bang into a delicate web, and after knocking about for a time, go buzzing and blundering out again, leaving Madame Spider with her web all torn and ruined and never a morsel of dinner—you've seen that, old fellow, haven't you? Well, that's just what Sinclair did with Mrs. Hugh. For no sooner had he satisfactorily concluded his negotiations for the purchase of the house Mrs. Hugh had spoken of, and got her to find him servants and other things, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13072" n="10 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>than he just went quietly off to Cannes on a ten days' leave, and came back at the end of it with a pretty, delicate wife, and two pretty little children to live in it! And after that, Mrs. Fairlie declares that, so far as Army society was concerned, Mrs. Hugh threw up the sponge."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13074">"It's a very fine story," said Orford laughing; "but, all the same, Mrs. Fairlie has got mixed somewhere, for we relieved the Yellow Horse here; and you know Sinclair was in the Line, he was D.A.Q.A.G."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13075">"So he was. Well, but that was the tale as she told it to me. I thought it uncommonly good."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13076">"Oh! uncommonly good. Mrs. Fairlie is a good hand at that sort of thing. She'll tell 'em about you and me when we've gone. Bless me, how I do dislike that woman, to be sure."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13077">"She's not a very attractive woman. By-the-bye, I wonder what fun she can find in going long country walks with old Coles?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13078">"I wonder what fun old Coles can find in going with her?" Orford growled.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13079">"That's all right enough, but, hang it all, old Coles is so bad on his feet. It's quite painful to walk down the street with him," said Brookes, feelingly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13081">"Yes, he is queer about his feet," returned Orford, then laughed outright. "By Jove! but the two must be a study to follow down the road. I've never seen them together. Why, her feet are just like Mrs. Hugh's, and Mrs. Hugh's are a feature—a feature! It was only the other day that Mr. Winks and <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13080" n="11 SHE'S A' I' THE WARLD TAE ME."/>I were going to the club together, when Mrs. Hugh fell foul of us and marched him on in front, leaving Polly to me. We hadn't gone many yards when Polly suddenly exclaimed: 'Dear me, Captain Orford, doesn't mamma look just like a tortoise?' I was struck all of a heap, for I didn't like to say yes, and my conscience wouldn't let me say no. 'Pon my word, Mrs. Fairlie and old Coles must be a study!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13082">"They got old Coles to sing at the Residence last night," said Brookes, chuckling over his comrade's remarks.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13083">"Old Coles?—by Jove!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13084">"And he sang 'Annie Laurie.'"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13085">"No!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13086">"Yes—true.</p>
        <q>
          <lg type="stanza">
            <l>"'Like dew on the gowan lying</l>
            <l>Is the fa' of her fairy feet,</l>
            <l>And like winds in summer sighing,</l>
            <l>Her voice is low and sweet.</l>
            <l>Her voice is low and sweet,</l>
            <l>And she's a' i' the warld tae me,</l>
            <l>And for bonny Annie Laurie,</l>
            <l>Wad I lay me doun an' dee.'"</l>
          </lg>
        </q>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13087" n="[12]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_012" n="2" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER II.<lb/>A WOMAN OF ACTION.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_13088">"A virtuous mind in a fair body is indeed a fine picture in a good light, and therefore it is no wonder that it makes the beautiful sex all over charms."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—ADDISON.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13089">PERHAPS never had the good folk of Blankhampton been so tickled by curiosity as they were about the latest bit of news that had spread over the town, or so really awed as they were by the details which came to light concerning the engagement and approaching marriage of To-To Antrobus.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13090">The event was not made less important by the information given by the Antrobus family. In the first place, Mr. Herrick Brentham belonged to the higher walks of the legal profession, and, except at Assize times, barristers were not commonly met with in Blankhampton.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13092">It was true he had never held a brief, but then, as Mrs. Hugh put it, a man who has a <hi rend="italic">large</hi> private property does not care to be tied by the working part of his profession, and, according to her, he held the position of a barrister very much as certain ladies of—of—well, let us say fashion, claim the reputation of being actresses, and think themselves superior to the great heads of the profession because <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13091" n="13 A WOMAN OF ACTION."/>they do not get their living by it. And in the second place, Mrs. Hugh declared he was wonderfully handsome—at least, not perhaps handsome, but exceedingly distinguished-looking; he was reported to be capable of picking To-To up bodily, and putting her on the top of a tall cabinet or shelf, there to learn good behaviour, or at least such as pleased him best.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13093">He was very rich—indeed, rolling in money—and could not lavish enough attention and—and promises upon his beautiful little betrothed, whom he described as being like a bit of Dresden china. They intended to live in London eventually, but immediately after the wedding they were going abroad for a year, or at least until the next autumn's yachting season, when they meant to go to the Mediterranean for the winter.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13094">And then somebody asked who Mr. Herrick Brentham was, and of what family he came? Upon which Mrs. Hugh rose up to the rescue, and elaborately explained matters thus——</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13096">The Brenthams were rich—oh! enormously rich, quite small millionaires!—with her oiliest laugh. Oh, without doubt To-To was a very lucky girl—every whim would be gratified, every caprice satisfied. Mr. Brentham's father? Oh, well—er—-the fact was, he was—er—a little eccentric—a little—<hi rend="italic">odd</hi>—with an emphasis upon the word, as if to be a little—<hi rend="italic">odd</hi> was a rare distinction to which common people could not attain. "But a very charming old gentleman, and all the family are so <pb xml:id="jwgarri_13095" n="14 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>delighted with the engagement, for Mr. Brentham—Herrick, that is—is quite a Bohemian, has <hi rend="italic">the</hi> most Bo-hemian ideas about everything, that he has always declared that, if he fell in love, even with a bar-maid, he should marry her at once. So, of course, the whole family are only too thankful to get him safely married as they would like."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13097">"But what or who <hi rend="italic">is</hi> Mr. Brentham—the father, I mean?" persisted the seeker after information.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13098">"He is—a—a manufacturer; he has very large brickfields, and, I believe, a most extensive property," Mrs. Hugh answered.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_13099">Eventually it oozed out that the Brentham, senior, had begun life with the proverbial and traditional twopence-halfpenny, from which all rich self-made men start, that, happily for the social status of his one son and his five daughters, he had become distinctly <hi rend="italic">odd</hi>, and was therefore saddled by an extra body-servant and kept in the retreat of his own elegant mansion in the neighbourhood of Idle-minster; which was a convenient arrangement for all immediately concerned, he being of the good old-fashioned sort who insist upon drinking of out their saucers, and saving their forks at the expense of their knives.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130101">It oozed out, too, that Mrs. Brentham could neither read nor write; but then, as Mrs. Hugh charitably remarked when she came to hear of it, that was no fault of Herrick's, poor fellow, and she, for one, should never make any difference in her manner to him on account of it—which, between <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130100" n="15 A WOMAN OF ACTION."/>ourselves, was not only very sweet and motherly, but it was also very nice of her to bear in mind the old saying, "The likes of me knows the likes of you."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130102">However, in spite of any little drawbacks in the way of bygones, there seemed to be no reasonable doubt as to the money, for, as Blankhampton people assured themselves and one another, the money must be all right, the entire family of the Antrobuses seemed so pleased with the engagement.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130103">And To-To bore herself as young ladies who are on the eve of a brilliant alliance often do; she became all at once exceedingly delicate and fragile—very Dresden-china-ish, some people said. And she gave herself airs—Oh! didn't she? And did not poor Polly suffer by reason of not having pulled off the matrimonial stakes before her! I think no one but herself ever quite knew how much.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130104">Perhaps the one who came nearest to knowing was Mrs. Hugh, who did not think To-To fit to be named in the same street with Polly for beauty, and therefore while she was highly elated at her good fortune in getting her second daughter off her hands, she still retained a fixed idea that Polly would rank as a Peeress in the end, and elevate the family for all time; but she was powerless to avert the little shafts of sisterly spite which the bride-elect was able, aye, and willing too, to let fly at the hapless Polly at all hours of the day.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130106">"Yes; embroidered muslin would be very sweet for the bridesmaid's frocks," was the way in which she goaded Polly into a state of frenzy one day, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130105" n="16 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>"but I think it's rather <hi rend="italic">young</hi> for Polly, you know."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130107">Polly was twenty-three! But the shaft told for all that, and she went off to her own room and cried until she could hardly hold her pretty head up, and her blue eyes were past recognition. And then she rose and comforted herself by vowing that if ever she was Lady Charterhouse, she would never let To-To and her spindle-legged husband cross the threshold of her house. Poor Polly! She had just laved her face and tired her head, when Jane came and told her Lord Charterhouse was in the drawing-room, and that the mistress had sent for her.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130108">So, with another look in the glass and a hope that her eyes did not look red, or rather that they would not appear so red and swollen to him as they did to herself, she went down, looking more like Ophelia than any other character you could have chosen out of the entire plays of Shakespeare. So bad, indeed, did she look, so dejected and crushed, that Mr. Winks felt his conscience in a very unpleasant state, and, after staying more than an hour, drinking three cups of Mrs. Hugh's best tea, eating a huge wedge of cake, hearing all the most important details about the approaching wedding, told in Mrs. Hugh's most florid and graphic style, and congratulating the bride-elect in person, he betook himself away without saying a single word of what he had gone on purpose to say.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130110">"Must you go? Well, good-bye, dear Lord Charterhouse," said Mrs. Hugh in her most familiar <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130109" n="17 A WOMAN OF ACTION."/>and motherly accents. "I hope you will come in again soon, in spite of our whole house being upset by this wedding; and next week we want you to come and dine with us. Will you?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130111">"I'm sure I shall be charmed," stammered Mr. Winks, wondering how he should manage to get clear of Mrs. Hugh and her blandishments; "that is if I'm not already engaged."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130112">"I will send you a formal invitation this evening," said Mrs. Hugh, smiling. "And as it is to meet the bridegroom, I hope you will not disappoint us."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130113">"I shall be charmed, I'm sure; charmed," said pool little Mr. Winks again; and then, with profuse bows, such as were dear to Mrs Hugh's soul, he at last got away.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130114">Mrs. Hugh watched him quite out of sight.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130115">"Of course you know, Polly dear," she said to her elder daughter, "Herrick is all very well, and To-To being so extravagantly fond of him makes a great difference, but, all the same, Lord Charterhouse is <hi rend="italic">my</hi> favourite. There is such an air about him, and he is so frank and open and pleasant. I <hi rend="italic">like</hi> frankness and openness above <hi rend="italic">all</hi> other qualities in a man," she wound up.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130116">Meantime, the frank and open Mr. Winks was just passing along the High Street, where he was hailed by Marcus Orford on his way to St. Eve's.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130117">"Hallo, Winks, where have you been?" he asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130119">Mr. Winks looked up the street and down the <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130118" n="18 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>street, pulled his moustache and smoothed the back of his head, took his hat off and looked carefully at the lining thereof, set it jauntily upon his fair head, and shook it until it settled at the right angle.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130120">"Been calling at the Antrobuses'," he said at length.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130121">"H'm! Rather an ordeal, eh?" suggested Orford, with a laugh in his eyes.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130122">"Oh, devilish!" returned Lord Charterhouse ruefully.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130123">"Did you tell them?" Orford asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130124">"Tell them! What?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130125">"Why," with an amused look, "that you're going to be married."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130126">"No, I didn't."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130127">"Why, how was that?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130128">"Well, I hadn't a chance," Mr. Winks answered.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130129">"Hadn't a chance? Why, did you stop long?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130130">"A pretty fair time."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130131">"H'm! Ah, well, you'll be getting yourself into trouble, young man, if you don't look out," Orford remarked. "Well I suppose you're going to the club. You'll hear the very latest about the wedding there. The last I heard was that the young couple are going to St. Petersburg to see the Royal wedding. Pretty chance they'd have of seeing it when they got there."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130132">"Yes—well—to-ta," and thus they parted, one for the club, the other for the house of the widow Trafford, in St. Eve's.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130134">"I wonder," ran Marcus Orford's thoughts, as he <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130133" n="19 A WOMAN OF ACTION."/>stood on, the doorstep waiting for his knock to be answered, "whether Lady Nell or Mrs. Oily-Tongue will get the best of that young gentleman. Fancy the young fool going there and sitting an hour—he must have been an hour from the time I saw him going out of barracks dressed like a tailors' dummy—and never saying a word about Lady Nell. 'Pon my word, if I see the old lady I'll not utter a single syllable about it. By Jove, if Charterhouse is such a fool about the business, the old girl deserves a chance," and then Mrs. Trafford's neat maid opened the door and Marcus Orford walked into the house and straightway forgot all about the latest bit of gossip.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130135">As the maid told him Miss Madge was in the drawing-room, he went into that room, where he found his aunt-by-marriage-elect surrounded by a select group of friends, all busy retailing scandal to the crispest of muffins and the most fragrant of tea.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130136">"My dear boy," cried Mrs. Trafford, beaming at him with her sweetest smile, "you are just in time, for the fresh tea and newly-toasted muffins are but just brought up. Pray have you heard anything up at the barracks about the very latest <hi rend="italic">on dit</hi>?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130137">"I've heard that the second Miss Antrobus is going to marry the Czar of Russia," replied Orford promptly, as he took the little widow's hand.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130139">"Oh, yes, I heard all about <hi rend="italic">that</hi> the day before yesterday," said the little woman, with an accent of faint scorn, which was very lowering to the <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130138" n="20 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>Antrobus family in general and to the impending marriage in particular. "Of course, poor things, they are quite carried away by their good fortune. My dear boy, Mrs. Antrobus came here yesterday," she went on in a hurried whisper, "and caught me at home, more was the pity; and I do asshaw you I had the whole story from beginning to end. I was perfectly exhausted, as Madge will tell you; in fact, the girls all came in together, and I was so faint and worn out that Madge insisted—insisted on giving me a little wee cognac and soda."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130140">"Ah, I suppose you were bored to death. That old lady is an infliction, particularly when she gets on to family subjects. I wonder you don't deny yourself to her, Mrs. Traff?"—yes, they were such good friends that he had began to call her Mrs. Traff, being probably almost the only man in the wide world who would or could have taken such a liberty without being severely rebuked for it.—"'Pon my word you're too good-natured to live. Why on earth should you be bothered with all that old woman's oily glorification of herself?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130141">"Well, truth to tell," whispered or rather murmured. Mrs. Trafford, in her most confidential tones, "I did tell Cox not to admit her; but the fact was that Mrs. Fairlie was just going out as Mrs. Antrobus reached the door.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130143">"'Oh! how do you do, Mrs. Antrobus?' she said sweetly. 'How I wish you had come half-an-hour earlier. I've been having a long chat with Mrs. Trafford, and I'm obliged to hurry away now. <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130142" n="21 A WOMAN OF ACTION."/>Good-bye.' And, as Cox said: 'What could I do, but let the lady know you were at home, ma'am?"'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130144">"Ah! I see—I see. Then what is <hi rend="italic">the</hi> news?" Orford asked, with some curiosity.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130145">Mrs. Trafford drew him a step nearer to the tea-table, and further away from the company.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130146">"They say that Captain Graham has run away with Mrs. Hildersley."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130147">"Run away with Mrs. Hildersley?" Orford repeated. "Oh! that can't be true, for he was lunching at our mess to-day."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130148">"Really?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130149">"Yes, quite true, and some of our fellows went back with him; his wife's got an afternoon-tea on to-day."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130150">Mrs. Trafford looked a shade incredulous.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130151">"Well, for poor Mrs. Hildersley's sake, I sincerely hope it is so; but it was given to me as a positive fact, and, as all the world knows, there's never smoke without fire."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130152">"Well, Mrs. Hildersley certainly has seemed utterly gone on Graham lately," said Orford. "I can't tell what she sees in him myself. I'm sure he's not half as good-looking as her husband is. I call Hildersley a very decent-looking fellow."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130154">"Oh! a good many ladies in Blankhampton seem to be equally smitten with Captain Graham's charms," said Mrs. Trafford, with a contemptuous air. "I call him a little, ill-looking fellow, with his one-sided eye-brows and his cadaverous face; perhaps <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130153" n="22 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>it is that sweeping-brush of a moustache they admire so much. By-the-bye, what regiment was he in before he became on the Staff?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130155">"The 9th Hussars."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130156">"You don't say so? I should never have taken him for a cavalry officer," in great disdain.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130157">"Oh! that's because his knee lets him down."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130158">"What about his knee?" suspiciously.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130159">"Nothing particular—only that he has a game knee, which every now and again gives him a wrench in walking and prevents him from being so smart as he once was," Orford answered. "By-the-bye, Mrs. Traff', do you know where Madge is?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130160">"Oh! my dear boy, be patient," Mrs. Trafford exclaimed, with her most playful and kittenish air. "Madge will come as soon as ever she escapes out of the hands of torture. She is having frocks fitted on her upstairs."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130161">"Why couldn't the dressmaker come in the morning?" asked Orford impatiently.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130162">"She was to have done so, but <hi rend="italic">good</hi> dressmakers have to be taken when they can be had, and, if Madge is to look presentable when your father and mother come to see her, she must not quarrel with her bread and butter now. See?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130163">"Oh! yes, I see," with a dismal groan. "Mrs. Traff', don't you think it would be a good idea to have a model made, so as to do for all time?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130164">"An excellent idea, if one could afford it," the little lady answered.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130165" n="23 A WOMAN OF ACTION."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130166">"I'll have one made for Madge at once. May I order one for you at the same time?" he asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130167">"Oh! thanks, many. Well, I must go and talk to some one else a little while. Possess your soul in patience until Madge comes."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130168">So Marcus Orford set himself to do Mrs. Traff's bidding, and possess his soul in patience until his divinity should appear; and as he waited, idling with his tea and muffins, he overheard a great deal of what two ladies nearest to him were saying.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130170">"My dear," one was saying in a low tone to the other, "I can't tell how Mrs. Trafford can have got hold of the story, nor who can have told her; and if you were not my own sister, I wouldn't tell you for the world—even now I tell you as the profoundest secret. <hi rend="italic">It's quite true!</hi> I got an inkling from something she let out the other day, and I went to Captain Graham and taxed him with it straight—straight! And, my dear, he was as cool as ice, and as brazen as Satan about it. Cut me short altogether, and asked me to be good enough to mind my own business and not interfere with his. Well, I went home baffled. I didn't know what to do, and with Charlie away too. However, I determined to stop it if I could, for I'm fond of her; so I never set foot outside my house, except when I saw her come out of hers and go toward the town. I just haunted her house when she was in it. And at last, after ten days' of waiting and watching, she asked me to dine and spend the evening quietly with her. I noticed that she seemed nervous and <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130169" n="24 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>restless, and she kept the children up at dessert a long time; then she took me to see them in their little beds. She'd never done that before, and altogether I felt sure that <hi rend="italic">the</hi> night had come. So, at last, I went home, but kept my things on and watched until I saw a cab creep quietly up to the corner. And then I went out, and asked the man if he wasn't waiting for a lady from the end house; and he said: 'Yes, for Mrs. Hildersley,' and then I knew I was on the right track. So I waited in the shadow until she came out, and then, when she got into the cab, I jumped in after her.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130171">"'Emily,' I said, 'you're going to do this night what you'll rue to your dying day. Come back.'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130172">"Well, she said she wouldn't, that she loved Graham better than her life—</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130173">"'Better than your husband, Emily?' said I, and she just laughed in my face—</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130174">"'A thousand times better than my <hi rend="italic">husband</hi>, Georgie,' she answered.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130175">"'Better than your soul?' I asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130176">"'Oh, my soul—how do I know I have a soul?' she said lightly, or what she tried to make sound so.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130178">"'But you know you have <hi rend="italic">children</hi>,' I said,
and I held her arm fast as we rattled over the cobbles, so as to make
sure she should hear me. 'Five little, helpless, motherless children,
whom you are going to brand with disgrace this miserable night. Five
little, motherless girls, who will blush at the sound of your name,
whom you have seen for the last <pb n="25 A WOMAN OF ACTION." pages="25" facs="jwgarri025"/>time—Do you realise it, my poor girl?—<hi rend="italic">for the last time!</hi>'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130179">"And then, poor thing, she began to cry, and cowered down into my arms, for she couldn't bear the mention of her children, and so I got her at last to promise she would go home and forget this dreadful night for ever. Oh! it's true enough, my dear, true as gospel, and that despicable villain, Graham, is flourishing at his wife's tea this afternoon, and trying to do devoted husband, and all that! But mind, Constance, that I tell you this as a profound secret. I shall not breathe it to another soul."</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130180" n="[26]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_013" n="3" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER III.<lb/>STEADFAST.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130181">"Nothing is so oppressive as a secret: it is difficult for ladies to keep one long, and I know even in this matter a good number of men who are women."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—LA FONTAINE.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130182">HOWEVER the story had got afloat, the reported elopement of Mrs. Hildersley with Captain Graham was the chief topic of conversation with everybody who came into Mrs. Trafford's drawing-room that afternoon, and everybody was equally positive that they had had the information as a fact, and that there was no doubt whatever of its truth. Each one had had it from an exceedingly intimate friend of one or the other of the families most immediately concerned in the matter. Each one had noticed something very particular in the manner or bearing of the two delinquents during the past few days, and each one had been quite sure for several weeks that things could not go on much longer at the rate at which they were then progressing without a dreadful scandal coming to light.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130184">"Well, now, I have been wondering which one of them he meant to go off with," remarked one jovial little lady, who seemed to be thoroughly <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130183" n="27 STEADFAST."/>"up" in the latest details. "I'm sure his attentions to that Mrs. George Greene have been beyond belief, but then, poor, vulgar, over-dressed, mindless thing, I've always pitied her for having that horrid old husband, with his yellow, weazened face, like those dried-up bodies we saw when we were staying at Munich last year, and who takes no interest in anything but his money-bags. I dare say to her, Captain Graham seems quite an Adonis, although a woman with any <hi rend="italic">pride</hi> wouldn't condescend to know a man whose wife lives in the same street, and who would as soon think of visiting her charwoman as her—but then, of course, who could expect a woman like Mrs. George Greene to have any pride? Where was she to get it?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130185">And then Mrs. Trafford came to the rescue.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130186">"<hi rend="italic">I</hi> think scandal terrible," she said in her most suave tones, "and really, my dears, you are all talking scandal dreadfully. Will you believe me if I tell you that you are all quite wrong, that Captain Graham has no more eloped with Mrs. Hildersley or anyone else, any more than he has eloped with me? My dears, Captain Orford tells me he lunched at his mess to-day, and several of the officers have gone back with him to Mrs. Graham's afternoon party."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130188">There was a moment's silence, and then a volley of questions was directed at Orford. "Was it really true?" Had he himself <hi rend="italic">seen</hi> Captain Graham, or did he only happen to know that he had been invited to lunch at the mess of the Black Horse? <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130187" n="28 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>Oh, he really had seen him! Well, of course that was very conclusive evidence that he could not have run away with Mrs. Hildersley. Captain Orford was <hi rend="italic">quite</hi> sure that it was to-day Captain Graham had lunched at the Black Horse mess. Oh, he was! Well, of course, that left nothing to be said on the subject; but—but, by-the-bye, did anyone happen to have seen Mrs. Hildersley that morning? For the life of him, Orford could not resist stealing a glance at the two blooming sister matrons on the sofa. For a moment there was dead silence, then Mrs. Farquhar (the "Georgie" who had played such a bold part the previous night) looked up, catching the full gaze of Marcus Orford's eyes as she did so; she blushed scarlet, but made haste to give evidence for her friend.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130189">"I happen to have seen Mrs. Hildersley twice to-day, once before breakfast, and again as I was coming out this afternoon. She has not been seen in the town because her second little girl is ill with bronchitis!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130190">She was so nervous and flurried at having to speak up aloud, that Mrs. Trafford and Orford both made haste to her rescue.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130191">"That surely leaves no more to be said on the subject," said Orford.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130193">"My dear Marcus, we will close the discussion," said Mrs. Trafford with dignity. "Here is Madge! My dear girl, as the greatest favour to me, take no notice of Captain Orford for a moment, but go to the piano and sing us a song." And then she added <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130192" n="29 STEADFAST."/>in a rapid undertone, "Don't say a word, dear; it's to fill an awkward gap."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130194">Bidden likewise by Orford's smile and nod, Madge went straight to the piano and seated herself at it. It was a handsome piano—a grand—and she sat so as to face the audience. And she sang? Well, this:</p>
        <q>
          <lg type="stanza">
            <l>"In the gloaming, oh! my darling,</l>
            <l>When the lights are dim and low,</l>
            <l>And the quiet shadows falling,</l>
            <l>Softly come and softly go.</l>
            <l>When the winds are sobbing faintly,</l>
            <l>With a gentle unknown woe,</l>
            <l>Will you think of me, and love me,</l>
            <l>As you did once long ago.</l>
          </lg>
          <lg type="stanza">
            <l>"In the gloaming, oh! my darling,</l>
            <l>Think not bitterly of me;</l>
            <l>Though I passed away in silence,</l>
            <l>Left you lonely, set you free,</l>
            <l>For my heart was crushed with longing,</l>
            <l>What had been could never be;</l>
            <l>It was best to leave you thus, dear,</l>
            <l>Best for you and best for me.</l>
          </lg>
        </q>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130195">She had a rich and full voice, which had been admirably trained, and as the plaintive words stole through the room, Marcus Orford could not for the life of him resist glancing at Mrs. Farquhar again; she blushed more vividly than before as their eyes met, blushed so deeply, in fact, that anyone might have fancied that she was the unfortunate woman whom they had been discussing and condemning so unmercifully.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130196" n="30 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130197">"Captain Orford," she whispered presently to him, "did you hear anything of what I was saying just now?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130198">"Yes, I did," Orford answered. "But you may make your mind easy about it, Mrs. Farquhar, I will never breathe it to a single soul."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130199">"Oh! thank you," she said, with a sigh of relief, "I ought not to have been talking about it, for I am most anxious that not a word of the truth shall creep out, and I was bound to tell somebody," she added with a burdened air, "for I never was able to keep a secret all to myself in my life, and my husband is away, you know."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130200">"I have forgotten all about it already," said Orford, solemnly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130201">"That is a blessing," she declared—and then Orford went back to Madge Trafford's side, and Mrs. Farquhar went away, if the truth be told, not because she <hi rend="italic">wanted</hi> to go, but for fear she should be betrayed into letting anyone but the two who had heard it, share her secret.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130202">She had but just gone when another of the Black Horse—Sir Anthony Staunton—made his appearance.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130203">"I say, Orford," he said, taking the opportunity of whispering to his comrade when Madge Trafford was carried off to the piano, "I say, there's the devil's own fuss going on about Mrs. Hildersley."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130204">"What about her?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130205">"Oh! they say she went off with Graham last night, and that Mrs. Farquhar brought her back."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130206" n="31 STEADFAST."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130207">"Really! What had Mrs. Farquhar got to do with it?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130208">"That's more than I can say. Anyway they came home together from some place or other in the small hours of the morning."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130209">"Ah!—can't say anything about it, I'm sure," returned Orford, with profound indifference and stolidity. "Have you been at the Grahams'?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130210">"Yes."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130211">"Many people there?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130212">"Good many—yes."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130213">"Mrs. Graham look much the same as usual?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130214">"Ye-es. Well, no, I can't say she did. The fact was, he was so attentive to her that she looked as if she was hardly sure whether she was herself or not."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130215">"Ah!" remarked Orford again. "By the way, Miss Trafford and I have been talking about a trip up the river—sort of water-picnic, you know. Would you like to join it?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130216">"Yes; I should awfully—be charmed, in fact. What a good idea. I suppose we couldn't cajole Urquhart into going?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130217">"Hardly—not under the circumstances."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130218">"No; but we might get old Coles. I should like to see old Coles attached to——" with a look at the lady of the house.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130219">Orford laughed.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130221">"Yes, he would be in a mortal funk the whole of the time. However, that's neither here nor <pb n="[32]" pages="32" facs="jwgarri032"/>there. I am to include you in the thing if it's got up?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130222">"Oh! yes, certainly," said Staunton. And then Mrs. Trafford's eldest flower, Julia, began to sing, so they were, perforce, obliged to be silent.</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130223" n="[33]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_014" n="4" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER IV.<lb/>A BOHEMIAN PAST.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130224">"True love can no more be diminished by showers of evil-hap, than flowers marred by timely rain."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—SIR PHILIP SIDNEY.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130225">THE post-corporal had just brought in the afternoon post-bag, and most of the officers of the Black Horse who were in barracks were gathered in or near the ante-room, discussing the letters and the news.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130226">Orford was sitting on one end of the big, double, leather-covered sofa, with several letters in his hand. At that moment he was reading one from Mrs. Trafford.</p>
        <q>
          <text xml:id="jwgarri_1204">
            <body xml:id="jwgarri_1203">
              <opener>
                <salute>"MY DEAR MARCUS,"</salute>
              </opener>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130227">—it ran—"I want you to ask a gentleman to your picnic for me; he is a Mr. Vyvyan. If I may bring him with us to-morrow, will do.</p>
              <closer>
                <salute>"Yours affectionately,</salute>
                <signed>"MARION TRAFFORD."</signed>
              </closer>
            </body>
          </text>
        </q>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130228">"Any of you fellows know who Mr. Vyvyan is?" Orford said aloud.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130229">"Vyvyan? Well, there are the Vyvyans of St. Michael's, and the Vyvyans of Stormount—and——"</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130230" n="34 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130231">"Oh, yes, yes—but I mean here in Blankhampton."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130232">"Don't know at all. Never met anyone of the name here," said the first who had answered his question.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130233">"Oh! you mean that chap that's staying at the 'Golden Swan,'" exclaimed another.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130234">"Yes; that's the man, I believe."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130235">"Man about forty," his informant went on.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130236">"Ah! Yes?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130237">"Drives a Stanhope-phæton and a chestnut mare?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130238">"Well?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130239">"Rather good-looking and big, but scarcely quite the right stamp on him. Such a good imitation of a sovereign that it puzzles you, though you <hi rend="italic">feel</hi> it ain't a good one—that's about the man."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130240">"Ah!—otherwise a cad?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130241">"Scarcely! What about him?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130242">"Oh, nothing—only that Mrs. Traff' wants to take him up the river with us to-morrow. I suppose he must have had a letter of introduction to her or someone she knows. I wanted to know what sort of a chap he was, that's all."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130244">"I saw him at the Parish on Sunday," put in Dayrell. "Reminded me awfully of a very pleasant Yankee chap I met out in Norway. By Jove! he was about the most amusing chap I ever came across. Had been all through the Civil War, was badly wounded, too, more than once. Told me he was once in hospital with a Southerner, a prisoner, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130243" n="35 A BOHEMIAN PAST."/>who was very sick and had got lower even than his bottom dollar; in fact, he had got to such a low ebb financially, poor devil, that he was going without tobacco because he had no money to buy any. So the other one lent him twenty pounds, never thinking to hear any more of it. For a good many weeks they were the best of friends and then they parted, my friend never dreaming he would hear of the Southerner again. However, about a year after he got a huge box of oranges from Florida, and a note from the Southerner returning the twenty pounds, and saying he was 'very glad to be out of debt to a d—d Yankee!'"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130245">"By Jove!" muttered three or four voices.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130246">"Yes; good story. I daresay it wasn't true, but that, of course, is neither here nor there; anyway, this American was something like Vyvyan."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130247">The result of this was that, when Orford went to St. Eve's to see his sweetheart, he told Mrs. Trafford that they—that is, the givers of the pic-nic—would be delighted to see Mr. Vyvyan or any friend she might care to bring.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130249">"My dear boy," said Mrs. Trafford—and, by-the-bye, I may as well remark here that, having grown attached to her niece's <hi rend="italic">fiancé</hi> in so great a degree that sometimes Orford wondered what she could find in him to make so much fuss about, she never missed a chance of calling him her dear boy—"My dear boy, I should not dream of inundating your party with my friends, nor should I have asked for Mr. Vyvyan had I not been begged to show him <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130248" n="36 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>some kindness and make the town—which, as <hi rend="italic">you</hi> know, Marcus, is insufferably dull to most people, especially if they are strangers—a little pleasant to him."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130250">"I'm sure you made it very pleasant to me," said Orford, looking at Madge and thinking, without the least feeling of satire, how much trouble Mrs. Trafford had given herself in order that he might have a good time. "But, Mrs. Traff, where did you first meet with this Vyvyan, and who is he?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130251">"We met him at the Archdeacon's."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130252">"Oh, really; where did he pick him up?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130253">"I don't think he picked him up at all," said Mrs. Trafford, with a certain accession of dignity in her tones—"he is a great friend of theirs."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130254">"Oh, really? I didn't mean anything slighting to him, Mrs. Traff', only it's rather a marked name, you know, and generally one hears at once what part of the world they come from, or what family they belong to Vyvyans, I mean."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130256">"Yes, yes, of course. I'm sure," said Mrs. Trafford, in her most important tones, "that no-body <hi rend="italic">can</hi> be <hi rend="italic">more</hi> alive than I am to the advisability of admitting no one into your house until you know everything there is to know about them, I am shaw"—and in her desire to give a due amount of impressiveness to her words, Mrs. Trafford's accent began to get distinctly pronounced. "I am shaw nobody can be more particular about her acquaintances than myself. When you and dear Madge are married, I think it <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130255" n="37 A BOHEMIAN PAST."/>will be far the best for us to leave Blankhampton and live in Town; it is quite impossible to avoid having a very mixed acquaintance here, or in any such place, in fact. All these doctors and lawyers and professional people are all very well in their way, but—er—one doesn't want to <hi rend="italic">visit</hi> them, you know."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130257">"My father was a professional man, Auntie," Madge put in gently.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130258">Her aunt had been particularly kind to her of late, tender and motherly to a degree; but, for all that, Madge was obliged to make her protest.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130259">"Your father was an Art-ist," said her aunt, in a tone of dignity mingled with reproof. "If he had lived he might, and probably would, have been President of the Academy."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130260">Madge shook her beautiful head sadly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130261">"Never, Auntie."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130262">"He might have been," persisted Mrs. Trafford; "at any rate he was a most <hi rend="italic">distinguished</hi> artist."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130263">"He gave drawing lessons," said Madge.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130265">"Oh! I've no doubt he had ups and downs, my dear," returned Mrs. Trafford, who could have killed her niece at that moment for being what she called in her thoughts 'so ridiculously plain-spoken,' so unnecessarily explicit about the past, which, after all, was or the bygones now and could never be changed or altered; which was all over and done with, and which was a past distinctly to be regretted because Francis Trafford had been a handsome genius, an artist by nature, with brains enough not <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130264" n="38 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>only to have reached the very top of the tree, but also to have kept there if he had made the effort to do so, but who yet had married a sweet, pretty, lady-like girl, who had been a governess in a school where he taught—a woman who had many lovable qualities, and a shy steadfast nature which had made her worship him to the last day of her life, and work her fingers to the bone to keep little Madge as a Trafford child should be kept, but who was yet emphatically <hi rend="italic">not</hi> the wife to help such a husband as Francis Trafford on in society or the world, and had so, in Mrs. Traff's opinion, ruined his life.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130267">In a certain way, Mrs. Traff was right enough. She had no sympathy with the Bohemian of the art-world, who was too great a genius to work. In fact, Mrs. Trafford did not care much about genius at all—the genius which persists in painting a picture which is too peculiar or too startling to sell. She would much have preferred the talent patient and careful to watch the taste of the buying classes, as a speculator watches the tapes at the Stock Exchange, which would only paint what would sell. In truth—and let me only breathe it in a whisper—I believe Mrs. Trafford would infinitely have preferred the talent which produces chubby children gathering fruit, more chubby children disporting themselves in basin and bath, beautiful young ladies exclaiming in delight at the contents of a box just arrived from their milliners, or beautiful but less youthful ladies trying in vain to cover up a bald patch on the top of <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130266" n="39 A BOHEMIAN PAST."/>their heads, which we see adorning the covers and advertisement sheets of our periodical literature now-a-days, to the genius which would paint a picture, which, though it might rouse the world of a hundred years hence to enthusiasm as a masterpiece, would not sell, and die in a garret of hunger. So she had but small sympathy with Francis Trafford, who had distinctly mistaken his day and generation.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130268">She went on speaking without giving Madge time to reply.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130269">"But we need not rake up bygones, particularly bygones that were decidedly unpleasant, my dear. I was saying that really Blankhampton is <hi rend="italic">very</hi>professional, and professional people are not the most pleasant in the world to cultivate—they are so pretentious."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130270">"Do you think they are?" asked Orford, who liked to get Mrs. Trafford what he called "on," when he did not happen to be too moved by gratitude to her for having been the means of his meeting Madge.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130271">"Oh! my dear boy,"—and here Mrs. Trafford was obliged to stop and take breath, as if his remark had quite deprived her of it—" My <hi rend="italic">dear</hi> boy! Why there's that Mrs. Antrobus—did you ever meet with such a mass of pretentiousness and assumption in all your life?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130272">"Well, she is rather a caution," Orford admitted.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130273">"And there's that Mrs. Fairlie—horrid woman!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130275">"Yes; there's Mrs. Fairlie., but I really don't think you ought to include her, Mrs. Traff'. Why, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130274" n="40 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>she goes for long country walks with old Coles, and no lady, I'm sure, with any <hi rend="italic">pretence</hi> about her, would do that. Of course, he's a dear old chap, and, in a certain way, I've got the greatest respect for him, but if I were a lady I should draw the line at long country walks. I should indeed."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130276">"I call that very thing most pretentious," cried Mrs. Trafford. "She is pretending all the time to be a sort of professional beauty, with always a cavalier in attendance upon her—horrid woman! And there's Mrs. Manson."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130277">"Don't know her."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130278">"Ah! it is no loss to you; but they are all alike, these professional people, and I shall be very glad to leave Blankhampton and have done with them altogether."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130279">"Yes, I daresay. I think you're right, Mrs. Traff', and all the people here are pretty much alike. There's the Mauleverers now—they <hi rend="italic">will</hi> pretend that they're pretty young ladies a man wants to flirt with. I don't know what you think," he ended gravely, "but <hi rend="italic">I</hi> call it wicked for a woman of forty to pretend she wants a <hi rend="italic">chaperon</hi>."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130280">Mrs. Trafford laughed, but did not allow herself to be drawn into a discussion for or against the Mauleverers, who were to her, as Orford very well knew, as Mordecai was to Haman as he sat in the king's gate. Ah! but she was a clever little woman, and knew better than to say a single word derogatory to the Mauleverers, though they positively declined to have her at any price.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130281" n="41 A BOHEMIAN PAST."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130282">As a matter of fact, the Mauleverers were accustomed, among themselves, to speak of her as "that pushing little person at No. 7, who will persist in wanting to know us," and although Mrs. Trafford had never heard or become aware of the actual words, she yet recognised the tone—<hi rend="italic">and</hi> its meaning—but too well—<hi rend="italic">and resented it</hi>.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130283">"But, Mrs. Traff," Orford went on, finding she would not enter upon the Mauleverer question at all, "you haven't enlightened me yet as to who is Mr. Vyvyan. Don't you think it would be just as well for me to know before to-morrow? Then I may be able to talk to him about his own people."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130284">"Oh! to be sure. I'll tell you all about him. He is one of the Cornish Vyvyans, a cousin of the Stormount people. He hadn't any money of his own, but he married—yes, he's a widower—a rich Lancashire girl, a manufacturer's daughter, who brought him a fortune of over a hundred thousand pounds. She died several years ago, leaving him all her property. They had no children. And that is all that I know about him, except that he is an exceedingly pleasant and agreeable man. By-the--bye, Marcus, when are we to expect Lord and Lady Ceespring?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130285">"Some day next week—Tuesday, I believe, unless anything happens to prevent their coming, such as a fit of the gout or something of that kind."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130286">Oh! I hope that won't happen," cried Mrs.Trafford and Madge together.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130288">"So do I," rejoined Orford, "for my—er—father <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130287" n="42 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>really is a terror when he's got the gout. I daresay most men are."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130289">"Oh! yes," answered Mrs. Trafford, going to the window. "Oh! here are the girls coming back, with several of your officers with them."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130290">"Then I know you'll excuse us," said Orford promptly. "Madge, my bird, come along."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130291">As Julia and Laura Trafford entered the house and crossed the hall to the stairs, Marcus Orford and Madge slipped across the landing into Mrs. Trafford's little sanctum, commonly called "the boudoir," and he shut the door behind them just as the merry voices of the new-comers reached the conservatory-landing half-way up the stairs.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130292">"I hope Mrs. Traff will be merciful and send us our tea in here," Orford said. "Oh! my darling, what a treat it is to get you to myself for five minutes!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130293">"Never mind; you will have me all to yourself by-and-bye," said the girl softly. "If you don't get tired of me before then."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130294">"Tired of you?" he echoed with scorn.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130295">"Well, I don't suppose you'll do that; anyway, I hope not," she said smiling. "But, Marcus, supposing your people don't like me?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130296">"I can't help that. Not that I'm the least afraid of it—my people know a good thing when they see it. My mother will love you because you make me happy, and my father will adore you because you are the loveliest woman in the world."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130297">"But I am not."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130298" n="43 A BOHEMIAN PAST."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130299">"No, perhaps not; but I think so, and he will think so, which is the same thing, don't you see? Besides, what objection could they possibly have to you?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130300">"I don't know; but—but—oh! I don't like to say all that comes into my head—but, we were so poor, so often 'hard up'—and—and—oh, I can't tell you exactly what I mean. But, auntie often talks about being Bohemian—Bohemian! I tell you she doesn't know what it is, what it mans to be Bohemian, any more than she knows what it is to be a Choctaw Indian. To hear her talk, you might think it was something distinguished, pleasant, out of the common; but in real life, <hi rend="italic">in London</hi>, it means riding in 'buses and third-class—it means salt butter and stale bread, because the new cuts away so soon."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130301">"Don't," cried Orford; "you hurt me, Madge, you hurt me."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130303">"I must; I've been trying to tell you for weeks past, and couldn't screw up my courage to do it; now that I have broken the ice, let me go on. It means one little scrub of a servant—rent over-due—summonses for taxes—it means boots down at heel and frocks out at elbow—it means going into mourning for your own hat—Oh! Marcus, Marcus!"—suddenly dropping upon her knees and flinging her arms about him—"I've been so grateful to Auntie for some things, but I've hated myself and her for deceiving you. She always says I didn't care to go out here because I went out so much in <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130302" n="44 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>town. I didn't—I didn't, for we were so poor; so poor, like all the other <hi rend="italic">Bohemian</hi> people. Oh! I can't tell you how miserable I have been. I wanted to tell you all along, though Auntie said I wasn't to breathe it, but I will now. I'm not fit for you, I'm not indeed, Marcus—I've been to the pawn-shop dozens of times!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130304">It would not be true if I did not admit that at this revelation, Marcus Orford started, aye, and started violently; but he stooped and raised her from the ground as tenderly as—as—well, any other man who was desperately in love with her would have done.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130305">"And pray, what were you doing there?" he demanded; "and why didn't you tell me all this ages since?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130306">"Because I was afraid," lifting her lovely eyes deprecatingly to his; "and because I knew you would think, and," with a choking sigh, "it's true enough, that I'm not a fit wife for you."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130307">Marcus Orford drew her very near to him, and kissed every doubt away from the lovely flushed face.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130308">"My dear, honest love, whom nothing can ever spoil," he said, "I thank you from the very bottom of my heart for telling me this. All the same, I don't want you to carry your honesty so far as to tell my people all these little details. As they don't either of them want to marry you, they might look at things somewhat differently."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130309">"But if they ever find me out?" she cried.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130310" n="45 A BOHEMIAN PAST."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130311">"Find <hi rend="italic">you</hi> out!" he laughed. "Who is to tell them but ourselves, and, after all, what is there to tell? It is no disgrace, my love, to be boor, any more than it is any credit to be rich. If you did visit with your avuncular relative—well, let us thank our lucky stars, that, owing to circumstances mind, not through any good effort of my own, I have never had to do the same, and that you will never have to do it again. But I thank you for telling me, my darling—it has made me love you, if possible, a thousand times more than I ever did before."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130312">"Auntie never knew quite all, she never knew that," Madge told him, "only that we were awfully poor; and that was only the last year or two, after poor dear Pater could not teach any longer. She's been awfully good to me, you know, Marcus, oh! so good, and I shall never, never be able to forget it or to repay it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130313">"I hope you will never try to forget it, my love," said Orford, "<hi rend="italic">I</hi> never shall. As to repaying it—well," with a smile, in a measure that will be an easy matter now. You will have the power to be very kind to Mrs. Traff 'now, if you choose."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130314">"You may be sure I shall choose," returned Madge, with a sigh of ineffable contentment and happiness.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130316">Dear, good Madge; to the very lowest depths of her honest arid grateful heart she was filled with gladness; she was glad that her sweetheart, who was to her a very king, a very God among men, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130315" n="46 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>knew all about the dark days of the past, and she was utterly thankful to him for his wish that she should try to repay the kindness of the aunt—only her aunt by <hi rend="italic">marriage</hi>, as she reminded herself—who had come forward at once as soon as she knew of her desperate situation, to stand between her and the hard and cruel world wherein, as Madge had learnt but too surely during the past few years, there is very little room for such workers as she would be, and none at all for those who have neither purse nor scrip.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130318">And it was not, as she invariably reminded both herself and anyone else to whom she told her thoughts, it was not as if Mrs. Trafford was a rich woman, to whom a member more or less to her household made little or no difference. Mrs. Trafford had—and nobody was better aware of it than Madge, nor, for the matter of that, half so well—all her work cut out to make her income stretch out sufficiently to meet at both ends. She had had barely enough for comfort—that is, living in St. Eve's, and doing her three weeks in Town every spring and calling it the "Season;" giving pleasant little afternoons after "the Parish," and three or four nice little dinners every year, and a big dance every January; dressing her two daughters very daintily, and herself—well, well, the less we say about that the better; and generally taking her place in Blankhampton "Sassiety" as one of its bright particular stars and leaders. But, when she bade Madge never, as long as she possessed a roof over her <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130317" n="47 A BOHEMIAN PAST."/>head, to think of or hint at anything so horrible as going out into the world to earn her own living, and had said, freely and kindly: "Come to us—you are a Trafford, one of us—come and share what we have," Madge soon found that her coming had made a decided difference in the household of No. 7.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130319">She had taken from the first the place of a poor relation—had <hi rend="italic">preferred</hi> the legs of the dickey-birds and the tail ends of the soles—had at once declared she did not care to go into society (which was true enough, for she, hated the pretentiousness and humbug of the Blankhampton people, who to her always seemed more like children playing at being grown-up ladies and gentlemen than like men and women of the world), and had from the first given the best fruits of her clever artistic fingers to the creation of pretty and dainty toilettes for her cousins, feeling more than repaid when once or twice Mrs. Trafford had, when in high good-humour, declared that Madge had made her and the girls quite independent of the dressmaker's vagaries. Oh! yes, there was no doubt—nobody in their senses could doubt it—that her aunt had been very generous and good to her; and now she was going to be Mrs. Marcus Orford, with the right to put three magic letters before her name, which would be, she knew, as dear to Mrs. Trafford's soul as her hopes of heaven, and must all her life remind herself of what she was, and what, but for her aunt's intervention, she might have been.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130320" n="48 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130321">"Darling," said Orford, suddenly, "have you seen this Vyvyan?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130322">"Oh! yes."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130323">"What sort of fellow is he?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130324">Madge roused herself from a calculation as to the probable cost of her trousseau. "What sort of man is he? Oh—not at all the kind of man you would like; a very florid sort of person."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130325">"To look at?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130326">"Oh! no,—his looks are the best part of him. No,—I mean he's florid in manner; not exactly ill at ease, but always as if he was trying to give you a good impression of himself, though he expected you to have a bad one."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130327">"What has he come to Blankhampton to do?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130328">"Ah! that is more than I carp tell you. He does not hunt, nor, apparently, shoot, though he says he is very fond of fishing. He does not know any people here except the Archdeacon, who met him abroad. I think he has lived abroad a good deal—he seems to know Italy very well."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130329">"H'm! An artist, perhaps?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130330">"Oh! I don't think so. I asked him about some of the galleries in Florence, but he seemed quite at sea about them, though he knew, and intimately too, all abort the hotels, and streets, and drives. Ah!" with a sigh, "Father and I were <hi rend="italic">always</hi> going to beautiful Italy. We used to talk about it, and dream about it for hours, but we never realized it. We never got there."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130331">"You shall go, my love," said Orford tenderly.</p>
        <pb n="49 A BOHEMIAN PAST." pages="49" facs="jwgarri049"/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130333">"Yes; I shall have everything now," smiling up at him. "And I have only one regret now—that he did not live to see it. It would have made him so proud and so happy."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130334">"Perhaps he does see it—who knows?" Orford said.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130335">"Yes; perhaps he does," said she. "I hope so."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130336">There was a moment's silence, then the door opened and Laura Trafford came in.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130337">"Marcus," she said, "that Mr. Vyvyan is here. Do you mind coming? Mother would like to make you acquainted."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130338">So Orford rose,—with an inward groan,—and went into the next room. The stranger, Air. Vyvyan, was standing on the hearthrug, with his back to the fern-filled fireplace, talking to the lady of the house, who was occupied among the teacups.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130339">"Now, where the devil," said Marcus Orford to himself, as his eyes fell upon him, "have I seen you before?"</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130340" n="[50]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_015" n="5" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER V.<lb/>A VYVYAN OF STORMOUNT.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130341">"Weeds grow sometimes very much like flowers, and you can't toll the difference between true and false merely by the shape."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—&gt;PAXTON HOOD.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130342">MRS. TRAFFORD looked up with a smile at Orford as lie entered the room—she generally did smile at him, but that is neither here nor there.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130343">"Oh! my dear Marcus," she said, rising from her chair as she spoke, "let me make you and Mr. Vyvyan known to one another. Mr. Vyvyan, this is Captain OR—ford."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130344">The two men met in distinctly different ways. Marcus Orford stood upright and stiff, looked straight at the other man, and said, "How d'you do?"—but in a tone which did not betray any anxiety to be enlightened as to the state of Mr. Vyvyan's well-being.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130345">Vyvyan, on the other hand, bowed, really bowed, bowed all over him, so to speak; and again the thought flashed into Orford's mind:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130346">"Where <hi rend="italic">have</hi> I seen you before?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130348">But memory did not come to aid him, and, although he felt an uncomfortable sensation of familiarity with this man's appearance, he yet could not in anyway fig time or place where lie had seen <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130347" n="51 A VYVYAN OF STORMOUNT."/>him before. Then, as Vyvyan evidently met him as a stranger, he dismissed the idea as unlikely after asking one question.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130349">"Do you know my regiment at all?" he asked abruptly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130350">"Not at all. I never knew it at all until the last few days," Vyvyan answered. "I have seen several of your officers since I have been in Blankhampton."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130351">"Ah! yes, yes, I see,"—and then, after one or two commonplace remarks about the weather and the place generally, he felt he had done his duty to Mrs. Trafford's visitor, and set himself to hand tea-cups with such vigour that in less than two minutes he was free to carry his own to the sofa where his love sat.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130352">Time had been when Madge was tea-maker, but Mrs. Trafford now would not hear of her doing it any longer.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130353">"No, no, my dear; when you had nothing else to occupy your thoughts, it was all very well, and it relieved me a little; but now it is different, and remember, you will have to pour out your husband's tea for the rest of your life. No; enjoy your idle time, dear, whilst you have it, and Laura will help me if I am very busy," she said, soon after the engagement.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130354">"I assure you, Auntie," protested Madge, "that I am still quite capable of pouring out tea, even though I am engaged to be married."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130356">"I don't doubt your capability, my dear," Mrs. <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130355" n="52 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>Trafford returned, "either on that or any other point, but I wish you to enjoy your engagement as much as possible; so pray say no more about it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130357">Well, Marcus Orford sat beside his beautiful sweetheart, enjoying himself very much indeed, but every now and then he sent the same puzzled, scrutinizing glance in the direction of Mr. Vyvyan that he had favoured him with on their introduction, and the same question kept cropping up in his mind:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130358">"Now, where the devil have I seen you before?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130359">But instead of becoming more clear to him, the likeness, or rather the familiarity of the face, seemed to fade away somewhat, so that he became more and more puzzled, though he still felt certain that he had seen him somewhere or other before.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130360">"You don't like him?" murmured Madge at his elbow, as she watched his brave grey eyes again and again seek the stranger's face.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130361">"Can't say I do."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130362">"Neither do I," she said with decision. "I can't tell what Auntie sees in him. If I were her I would never have let him inside my house."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130363">"Oh, I don't know that he's so bad as that," said Orford indulgently, pitying Vyvyan in his heart for his misfortune in having raised Madge's dislike. "He's not quite the right stamp, perhaps, but he's rather decent-looking than otherwise."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130365">"Good-looking," echoed Madge. "Yes, if you call a wag dummy out of a barber's shop good-<pb xml:id="jwgarri_130364" n="53 A VYVYAN OF STORMOUNT."/>looking perhaps he is. But, for my part, I can't bear that pink and white and black type."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130366">"No? What type do you like?" Orford asked, and then they went off into a conversation on the merits of black eyes or blue, which is not essential to this story, therefore I will not repeat it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130367">"But as for him," Madge ended, turning her large and lovely eyes towards Mr. Vyvyan in order to indicate that she was speaking of him, "he will be a deal better-looking when his hair is grey. I shouldn't wonder if he isn't rather a distinguished-looking <hi rend="italic">old</hi> man."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130368"><hi rend="italic">Grey hair! Grey hair!</hi> Why,—all the feeling of familiarity with this man came back with tenfold force! Of course, he had seen the face before,—and then a sudden recollection of a Vyvyan of Stormount came to him, and the mystery was solved. He remembered it all so well, how, when he was a little lad of ten years old or so, one of the Vyvyans of Stormount had come to pay his father a visit, a handsome, fresh-complexioned, vigorous, man with a profusion of grey hair. Yes, of course, that was the face he had been thinking of.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130369">"Were you a son of John Vyvyan of Stormount?" he asked, crossing the room and putting the question to him point-blank.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130370">"No, I was Gregory's son," answered Vyvyan politely.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130371">"Oh, you were Gregory's son!" in surprise. "But I always thought he went out to Australia and died?"</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130372" n="54 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130373">"I was his son, nevertheless," the other said composedly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130374">"But the Stormount people know nothing about that, do they?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130375">"Very likely not. My father has been badly treated by his relatives, who did not approve of his marriage to my mother. I have never claimed any acquaintance with the Vyvyans of Stormount, because my father never forgave them, and never wished me to do so."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130376">"But you claim the family?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130377">"Oh, yes; because that <hi rend="italic">is</hi> my family, and I have the same right to be proud of belonging to it that they have."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130378">"Yes, I see. Well, I must say you have surprised me," Orford said, "because I had not the least idea that Gregory Vyvyan ever got wrong with his people at all. By-the-bye, you never met John Vyvyan?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130379">"No, never."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130380">"Ah! you are very like him, you might be his son."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130381">"I am his brother's son," said Vyvyan, with dignity.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130382">"Yes, yes, exactly," murmured Orford, and them he went back to Madge once more. He was intensely interested now in Mrs. Trafford's new friend, and he watched him closely from the moment that he had declared himself to be the son of Gregory Vyvyan of Stormount, who had gone out to Australia and died.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130383" n="55 A VYVYAN OF STORMOUNT."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130384">"Mother must have been rather a howler," he said to himself, "and she's set the stamp of it on him, without his being exactly a howler either."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130385">Orford could not help wondering what the circumstances of this man's life, his early life, that is, had been. Not such as it was now, that he could swear; for there was a certain formality about his speech, a care in pronouncing his words, a tendency to double his aspirates which told Orford plainly enough that he did not speak now as he had been accustomed to speak as a child. There was a good deal of that peculiar swagger about it, such as used to be commonly given and accepted as the particular jargon of the cavalry officer, although it was about as true to life as the idea which used to be, I believe, equally prevalent in France, that all English women have splay feet and long horse-teeth, and the effect of the whole was distinctly odd,—the swagger and the formality and the elaboration of the aspirates, all taken together, being quite sufficient to account for the verdict Dayrell had given of him, "such a good imitation of a sovereign that it puzzles you, though you <hi rend="italic">feel</hi> it ain't a good one."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130386">In effect it was something like this—he was speaking to Mrs. Trafford then:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130387">"Oh!—er—ah—ya-as. I—er—know Giberaltah very well indeed—ah! Ya-as, an interesting little place—ah! And—er—we had several trips into the interior—ah—though I nev-ah went really into the—ah—heart of the country."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130389">"'Pon my soul," muttered Orford to his sweet <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130388" n="56 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>heart, "it's a funny thing to hear a Vyvyan of Stormount talking about 'Giberalta."'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130390">"I don't believe he's a Vyvyan of Stormount at all," asserted Madge. "Does he look like a Vyvyan of Stormount?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130391">"Well, yes, he does, he's as like them as two peas," Orford answered, "but the mother must have been a howler—must have been."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130392">"Oh! yes, that I can quite believe," said Madge, who had taken a thorough dislike to the man, and was not to be argued out of it, Vyvyan of Stormount, or no Vyvyan of Stormount.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130393">"Hallo, what's the joke?" Orford asked, seeing that Laura Trafford and Staunton were watching, with evident amusement, something that was going on in the street below.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130394">Laura looked across at them, and beckoned them to come, and when they got there they saw what Laura called a, procession on the opposite side of the way, consisting of To-To Antrobus and her young man, Herrick Brentham, a yard or two behind them Polly, looking prettier and more foolish than ever, yet very proud because Lord Charterhouse was in attendance upon her, and, bunging up the rear, Mrs. Hugh and Baby, her youngest hope and but a little stick in the shortest of petticoats, with legs like a hen.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130396">Staunton and Orford positively chuckled with delight to see Charterhouse thus under convoy; as for Mrs. Hugh, she was a sight to see—she seemed to be treading air, as she waddled along, and her <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130395" n="57 A VYVYAN OF STORMOUNT."/>smile, larger, fuller, more beaming and more triumphant than perhaps anybody in the memory of man had ever seen it before, shed the full measure of its effulgence and glory upon the very stones of the street as she passed!</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130397">"I wonder how Lady Nell would like that?" remarked Staunton, as the last of the procession turned the corner, and passed out of sight. "I should think she——" but there, a sharp kick from Orford froze the words upon his lips and he stopped short.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130398">"I say," he asked, as they went back to barracks together, "why did you shin me so terrifically, when I mentioned Lady Nell?</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130399">Orford laughed.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130400">"Well, if Mr. Winks is such a young ass, as to be going constantly to the Antrobuses', without ever mentioning Lady Nell or his engagement to her at all, I think it's only fair that the old lady has a chance, without any outsider telling her anything about Lady Nell."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130401">"What old lady?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130402">"Mrs. Antrobus;, of course."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130403">"But why should not the Traffords——?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130404">"Know anything about it?" ended Orford. "Why, my dear chap, because Mrs. Traff don't care any too much about Mrs. Antrobus,—it ain't in reason she should—and she would revel in letting her know it. No; I have never mentioned it, because I didn't want to spread the news. I wanted the old lady to have a fair chance."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130405" n="58 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130406">And it happened at that very moment that Laura Trafford strolled into her cousin's room, where Madge was just making herself presentable for dinner.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130407">"Madge," she said abruptly,"you know when we were standing in the window watching Mr. Winks and the Antrobuses go by?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130408">"Yes."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130409">"Why did Marcus give Sir Anthony such a frightful kick?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130410">"Did he?" in surprise.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130411">"Rather; my shin positively ached out of sympathy for him. It was something about a Lady Nell, that Marcus didn't want us to know."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130412">"I wonder what?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130413">"I wish you would try and find out."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130414">"Yes, I will," returned Madge. "But who is Lady Nell?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130415">"Ah! that's what I want to know. I wonder if Mr. Winks is engaged all this time? Somehow, I never cared much about him."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130416">"Oh! he's a mere baby!" cried Madge, with fine scorn. "A very nice boy and all that, but a mere baby; give me a <hi rend="italic">man</hi>."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130417">"Like Marcus Orford," cried Laura, with a gay laugh.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130418">"Or Sir Anthony Staunton," retorted her cousin teasingly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130419">And just at that moment too Mrs. Hugh was saying to Mr. Winks:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130421">"Oh! <hi rend="italic">must</hi> you go, Lord Charterhouse? Don't; <pb n="59 A VYVYAN OF STORMOUNT." pages="59" facs="jwgarri059"/>do stay and have high tea with us and go to the Winter Gardens. The Royal Engineer band plays there to-night; and it's the <hi rend="italic">best</hi> string-band in England, you know."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130422">I—I should like to, awfully, many thanks, Mrs. Antrobus," answered Mr. Winks, with a downward glance at his clothes.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130423">"We are not going to dress, it is <hi rend="italic">only</hi> high tea," answered Mrs. Hugh, with her airiest tone and laugh.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130424">So it was settled, and Mr. Winks slipped so many inches deeper into the mire, which would end in landing him,—<hi rend="italic">where?</hi></p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130425" n="[60]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_016" n="6" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER VI.<lb/>ANTE-ROOM GOSSIP.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130426">"In the adversity of our friends we always find something which is not wholly displeasing to us."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—ROCHEFOUCAULD.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130427">"NOT a word to Mr. Winks, mind," said Orford to Sir Anthony Staunton, as they parted at the door of his quarters.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130428">"Oh? not a word, of course," Staunton answered.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130429">The precaution was, however, unnecessary so far as that evening was concerned, for instead of being found among those who assembled for the mess dinner, Lord Charterhouse was seated comfortably between his hostess and the fair Polly, enjoying himself thoroughly if the exact truth be told, and highly edified in watching—as was Polly—to see how many times the turtle doves,—as the whole family of the Antrobuses usually called To-To and Herrick Brentham—would contrive during the course of the meal to touch hands under cover of the table-cloth.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130431">He admired little To-To very much, admired her pretty eyes, and her bright complexion, and her pretty, bronze gold hair, and he wondered what she could see in "such a sulky, ill-conditioned beast," as he called Herrick Brentham—who seemed to <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130430" n="61 ANTE-ROOM GOSSIP."/>think he had got engaged to the girl in order to scowl at every man, no matter what might be his age or calling, who came within a dozen yards of her. Mr. Winks, somehow, did not much care about Mr. Herrick Brentham, a feeling which was shared by everybody in Blankhampton, who happened to cross that scowling gentleman's path.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130432">"The brute's so insufferably impudent!" he exclaimed to Orford the next day. "Now, last night, I was sitting on the other side of the table as far away from him as I could very well get, and this brute, who had only been introduced to me half-an-hour before, bawled out:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130433">"'Aw! Charterhouse,' said he, 'can I give you some of this chicken?'"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130434">"'Thank you, <hi rend="italic">Mr</hi>. Brentham,' said I—and I said to myself: 'Charterhouse! H'm! that's like your d—d cheek.'"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130435">"Did he take the hint?" Orford asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130436">"Well, no, confound him! I can't say he did," Mr. Winks replied; "but then, how could you expect an under-bred brute like that to see anything in the shape of manners. Can't tell myself what that pretty little girl sees in him. He's as ugly as sin, and as mean as the grave, if her engagement rings are any guide on the subject, and, by Jove! the fellow's legs are after the same pattern one sees in the penny illustrated papers."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130437">"I suppose there's money?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130439">"Money! Oh, a little, doubtless; but I know if I was a pretty girl I should want a devil of a lot of <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130438" n="62 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>money to gild a fellow of his class. Her people say it's such a pity he's so jealous. Jealous! By Jove! in his case it's only another word for an all-round bad-temper. By-the-bye, have you heard the latest about Graham?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130440">"No; what about him?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130441">"Well, it seems he's been going on any pace with Mrs. Farquhar, and his attentions to Mrs. Hildersley and that other fat, yellow-haired woman were nothing but a blind. Mrs. Farquhar is the one, and they're saying that Mrs. Graham was only in the nick of time to stop them from going off together."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130442">"Where did you hear that?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130443">"Oh, I heard it last night," meaning that he had heard it from Mrs. Hugh.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130444">"Ah! If I were you, Winks, I shouldn't repeat it," observed Orford coolly. "I happen to know—not from hearsay, but really I know—that there isn't any truth in it. Besides, is it likely Mrs. Farquhar would leave a handsome husband like hers, to go off with a grubby little rat like Graham?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130445">"Well, it isn't altogether; but, you know, there is never any accounting for a woman's taste. All the women here seem more or less gone on Graham, at least, they're always abusing him, and that, I take it, is about the best sign one could have that it is so."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130447">"Likely enough; but, all the same, Mrs. Farquhar will never throw Farquhar over for Graham. <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130446" n="63 ANTE-ROOM GOSSIP."/>'Pon my soul, I don't believe she'd touch him with a pair of tongs. She's a good little woman, that."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130448">"Yes, I daresay. Well, it's to be hoped it won't get round to Farquhar's ears, that's all."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130449">"Yes; but in any case Farquhar would hardly be such a fool as to believe it; a man could never pay himself such a poor compliment as to be uneasy or jealous on account of a Graham. Well, are you coming on the river with us to-day?</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130450">"What's your programme?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130451">"Simple enough. Two tubs—Mrs. Traff' and her daughters, Miss Trafford and Miss D'Arcy, myself and Staunton, Bowers and that fellow Vyvyan. I must have another man for Miss D'Arcy."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130452">"Oh! I don't know that I care very much about Miss D'Arcy," returned Lord Charterhouse coolly. "I daresay she was very pretty ten years ago, but you know, Orford, that ain't now, and somehow I don't seem exactly to care about it. Can't you ask Brookes instead?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130453">"Yes, I can; but I know Brookes won't go.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130454">"Why not?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130455">"Because he don't like Miss D'Arcy—won't have her at any price. No, I'd better see if Cunliffe won't come."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130456">"Your very man; best fellow in the world for a river party. By-the-bye, where are you going and what are you going to do?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130458">"We're going to row up as far as Applegarth, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130457" n="64 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>where there's an idyllic inn, all honeysuckle and roses and such-like."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130459">"Rather late in the season for those," laughed Lord Charterhouse, who had been brought up a good deal more in the country than Orford had been.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130460">"Well, but they've got cream and fresh eggs, and all things of that kind, at any time. Anyway, we row up to Applegarth, get tea at the 'Queen of the Roses'—yes, that's the name of mine inn—go to see a wonderful old ruin near the village, and then to see a wonderful wishing well, and after we've all consulted an old personage who is going to tell us our fortunes, we shall quietly slip down stream in the gloaming, and wind up with a supper at Mrs. Traff's."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130461">"And very delightful it will be, my dear chap, particularly for you; but, I don't think I care about it this time. Cunliffe's your very man, and I wish him and Miss D'Arcy joy of one another."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130462">Thus foiled in his attempt to secure a man to complete the party, Orford went off to the ante-room in search of Cunliffe, who was young and flippant, being of that gay and jovial disposition which would cheerfully accept an invitation to dine with Old Nick himself, did nothing else present itself in the way of a change.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130464">There were a good many officers in and about the ante-room, but Cunliffe was not one of them. Those who were there, however, were so busy picking to pieces a man of the Artillery, whom most of them knew, and whom Orford knew perhaps most intim-<pb xml:id="jwgarri_130463" n="65 ANTE-ROOM GOSSIP."/>ately of all, having been at the same crammer's before one went to Sandhurst and the other to Woolwich, that he really felt obliged to stay and hear the conversation out, instead of going straight away in search of Cunliffe.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130465">"They say he's going into Parliament. Yes, it's really true. oh, the beggar's clever enough in all conscience, in fact, a deuced sight too clever," said Dayrell. "I remember being over one night in their camp, when we were out in Suakim; for a wonder the fellows weren't too wrapped up in their own importance or their scientific studies or what not to go in for a little innocent recreation in the shape of larking, and I must say for a set of well-behaved, stiff and starved prigs like Artillery generally are, they'd got a very tidy programme together; a very—ti—dy—pro—gramme—in—deed. A good many of 'em had been fired by what had been going on in our camp, and, being all cleverish sort of chaps, they were anxious to improve on it. They'd got a superb trap for the Colonel, which, as I told them, was dangerous and disrespectful. And there were all sorts of odds and ends for the delectation of the youngsters, but the chief attraction of the evening was the drawing of De la Motte. De la Motte himself had been rather more disagreeable than usual—"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130466">"Then he must have been charming," broke in one of the audience.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130467">"Disagreeable brute, enough to aggravate anyone into drawing him," cried another.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130468" n="66 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130469">"Did you sit next him, George?" asked a third.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130470">"No; I didn't. I sat just opposite, so that I had the full benefit of the various and delightful play of expressions which passed over his hawk-like countenance. The others tried to toast him into exceeding his usual quantity of liquor, but Motty was too wide-awake for that."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130471">"Ah! he's just one of those wide-awake brutes that's never caught napping for a single moment," exclaimed a man who evidently bore the absent Motty no good-will. "I believe he sleeps with one eye open, like a weazel."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130472">"Like enough—his eyes are just like a weazel's. However, this night, although they <hi rend="italic">all</hi> wanted to drink wine with him, Motty wasn't to be caught, for after the third message had been taken to him, Motty just filled his glass to the brim, and said:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130473">"'Gentlemen, I pledge you all!' and then he turned to his next neighbour, and said with a disagreeable laugh: 'Bless me! how popular I have become all at once. I wonder what good fortune I have to thank for that?'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130474">"Well, it happened to be an awfully hot night, and the flies and other creepy-crawlies were uncommonly bad—they were terrific in fact. Sleep without a mosquito-net, you couldn't. The idea was to do Motty out of his sleep for that night. He was begged to take a hand at whist, and, to the general surprise, took it at once. What was more, he all at once began to make himself agreeable."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130475" n="67 ANTE-ROOM GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130476">"H'm! I know Motty in that stage," put in Orford. "He shows his teeth and the whites of his eyes, and draws up his breath with a sort of hiss. Yes, I know him then. <hi rend="italic">If</hi> possible, he is more unpleasant then than at any other time."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130477">"Yes—however, I didn't stay to see him. I went off with the others to demolish his tent. First they took the mosquito-net, hammock and his pyjamas, made them into a bundle, and sent them off to be deposited under the shelter of the Colonel's tent-canvas; then they took the pole up and let the tent down, and just carried the pole as far away as they very well could, and then they went back to the mess-tent and entertained him (among others) with an account of shaking young Trevor in a blanket, and made a display of Trevor in a very ruffled condition, both of mind and body.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130478">"Apparently, Motty was utterly taken in and went off to his tent after a—for him—lavishly cordial exchange of good-nights and other jollity. We sat down to cards so as to be ready, when he came back to swear at us, with an appearance of festive innocence. We played a few games of Van-John, and then we took to Nap—but there was no sign of Motty. In fact, he never came back at all. We bore it for a good bit, and then when flesh and blood could stand it no longer, we sallied out and cautiously went to reconnoitre.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130480">"It was a still, hot, sultry night; there was not a sound but our own footsteps as we sneaked along over the sandy ground. It was pitch dark overhead. <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130479" n="68 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>We crept along cautiously—cautiously—feeling our way like blind men, hand in hand. And at last we got to the place, expecting to hear Motty ramping and swearing after his own peculiarly boisterous and fluent fashion; but there was not a sound, all was still as death on the desert, and there lay the tent like a played-out balloon just as we had left it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130481">"One of the fellows had a little bull's eye lantern, and turned it on for us to examine the place—but there was no Motty there, not so much as a sign of him. After that, there was a search for him, but he was not to be found, not even though we searched in every officer's teat except the Colonel's. We did take a peep into his, but he caught a glimpse of the bull's eye and swore at us with such earnestness that we concluded that if Motty had taken shelter there, he'd better be left to enjoy it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130482">"Well, finally, we all went to roost, thoroughly sold, feeling that Motty, the brute, had got the best of us this time, somehow; and then, in the morning, it turned out that my fine fellow had got an inkling of what was on, had quietly sent his servant to sleep in another tent, and had rigged up his spare hammock and mosquito net in his servant's tent; so the fellow had actually gone straight to bed after he bade us 'good-night' in the mess tent, and had had an excellent night, with the pleasure of getting up in the morning to jeer at us."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130483">"How was it we never heard of this before?" somebody asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130485">"I'll tell you. I stayed over in the Artillery <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130484" n="69 ANTE-ROOM GOSSIP."/>camp that night, and in the morning old Bellamy, the Colonel, you know, happened to find Motty's belongings hidden under the flap of his tent. It was quite a chance his doing so; out he kicked up such a devil of a shine at <hi rend="italic">his</hi> tent being made a convenience of for any such d—d ungentlemanly conduct, that I concluded along with the others that we had better hold our tongues about it, and that the fewer people knew anything about it the better chance there would be of escaping a court-martial. Old Bellamy swore he would court-martial the whole lot who had taken part in it, and I knew—as I wasn't a bold Artilleryman, but only a humble Dragoon, and a visitor in the camp—I should get into a devil of a mess for taking liberties with a full-blown swell like him; so I just kept quiet about it. But, by George! didn't Motty take it out of us just! I should like to have rammed his teeth down his jeering and sneering throat."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130487">"I fancy he would sneer pretty well, and on the whole his temptation was strong," said Orford, laughing. "But do you know, I saw him the other day in the Park, and you fellows all know what a spick and span chap he is, when he's got up to kill? Well, he was got up immensely that morning—black clothes, white cravat, white gaiters, and new gloves, all as smart as smart could be—when up walked Dirty Van, and thrust his hand under his arm. 'Well, old boy,' said he, 'how are you? How do, Orford?' said he to me. Motty's face was <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130486" n="70 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>a study, I can tell you, and he walked in that unwilling way that a child lets himself be shoved along by a nurse when he doesn't want to go and daren't say no.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130488">"'What's the news?' bawled Van.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130489">"'Why, you've heard the last?' snaps Motty.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130490">"'No, I haven't,' says Van.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130491">"'Well, what's the driest spot in Great Britain? You know?'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130492">"'No, I don't. Give it up,' cries Van.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130493">"'Dirty Van's bath,' says Motty. 'Heard it at the club yesterday.'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130494">"And," ended Orford, "poor old D. V. left in a hurry."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130495">"'I should think so," laughed Brookes. Even D. V. can see some things."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130496">"And that was plain enough for a blind man to see clearly," returned Orford. "Well, I must be off. I want Cunliffe. Does anyone happen to know where Cunliffe is?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130497">"He went out of this half-an-hour ago," answered Brookes. "I don't know, but I think he's going to afternoon tea at the Palace."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130498">"Oh, no he isn't, he's coming up the river with me," said Orford, coolly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130499">And so it was. When he reached Cunliffe's room, he found that cheery young gentleman enjoying a pipe, while watching his servant lay out his clothes for the afternoon.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130500">"Hullo, Orford," he said, as he caught sight of his visitor. "What's the news?"</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130501" n="71 ANTE-ROOM GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130502">"'I want you to come up the river with us to day."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130503">"Awfully sorry, I can't, I'm going to have tea with ME at the Palace."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130504">"Quite impossible—you're coming up the river with me," responded Orford coolly. "If ME wants you to go over there, he should ask you to dinner in a decent, respectable way. It's preposterous to expect us to go over there in the afternoon, except for tennis or a garden-party."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130505">"It is tennis," said Cunliffe.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130506">"Yes, I know. It always is tennis—and a nice condition the lawn will be in after the rain we've had the last fortnight. Oh! don't you go, my child—you'll have Miss Victoria inviting you to walk round the forcing houses, and unless you want to be saddled by the shadow of 'ME' for the rest of your life, you'd better keep clear of the Palace, except a lot of us are going. Anyway, you're coming up the river with us to-day, so you can't possibly go any where else." And then he explained the scheme for the afternoon's entertainment.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130507">"Miss D'Arcy," repeated Cunliffe, who like most other fellows in the regiment, gave in under pressure from Orford. "Who is she? I never met her anywhere that I know of."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130508">"She's the Canon's daughter."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130509">"Oh! really—pretty?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130510">"Yes, awfully pretty; quite one of the prettiest girls about Blankhampton."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130511" n="72 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130512">"Ah! Then I think I'll come," as deliberately as if he had decided the question for himself.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130513">"That's right. By-the-bye, we may as well go down together. The trap will be round in half-an hour—you'll be ready?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130514">"Oh! yes."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130515">And sure enough, half-an-hour later, the young gentleman made his appearance at the front door of the officers' quarters, where Orford and a very tall dog-cart were awaiting him. And three minutes later came Staunton with a rush, who drew down his lips when he saw the lad, and said feelingly:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130516">"Poor devil! Are you paying him out, Orford?'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130517">"Hush—sh!" said Orford.</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130518" n="[73]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_017" n="7" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER VII.<lb/>A SLIP.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130519">"What women would do if they could not cry, nobody knows What poor, defenceless creatures they would be."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—DOUGLAS JERROLD.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130520">ON the whole, the water-party passed off very well, and was a decided success. If anybody had a right to be dissatisfied or to grumble, it was young Cunliffe, who had been distinctly deluded into going by the representation of Miss D'Arcy as a pretty and attractive young lady; but Cunliffe did not grumble at all; on the contrary, he enjoyed himself fairly well, and admitted that the afternoon's entertainment was an improvement on the stiff and stately hospitality of Blankhampton Palace.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130522">For the every-day life of "ME," otherwise John, by Divine Providence Lord Bishop of the Diocese, partook always, more or less of the nature of a pageant, something like a court ceremonial in miniature, very satisfying no doubt to the lordly mind, which had in the days of his boyhood looked up to his parish priest, as far as now he looked down upon the same dignitary, but a little tiresome to gay young subalterns, who had been born to the luxuries of plush and silken hose, to serving giants <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130521" n="74 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>gliding about ancestral halls, and to the comforts of shiny carriages and high-stepping horses, even if they had never ridden in such an <hi rend="italic">ark</hi> as the episcopal omnibus, which daily blocked up the narrow streets of the old city, causing more accidents and bad language than some of my readers might think credible. As Mr. Winks said one day to Orford:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130523">"Somehow the Palace always makes me feel as if I'd got to the Heavenly Jerusalem before my time, which is uncomfortable."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130525">"Really. Ah! never feel that way myself," returned Orford, "there's much too worldly a savour about the whole business to suggest anything so spiritual to my mind. No, it's to be hoped, when the Palace people get to the Heavenly Jerusalem, that Mrs. Jones will be able to forget her profile, and John Blankhampton to remember that he's no better off than his father, and perhaps not quite so well. Now, I'll tell you what it makes me think always—of the times when I used to have to go and pay duty visits at my godmother's, old Lady Screwell. Lord, what a time I used to get! However, she's dead and gone now, poor old soul, so I needn't bear malice for past sufferings. But, Gad, what a life that old woman led! She belonged to the Plymouth Brethren—used to make me go to chapel with her too, and I had to shake hands with all the brethren, greasy old chaps I'd never been introduced to! However, that don't matter now, and the poor old soul left me every penny she had—saddled, by-the-bye, with a desire that, it my <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130524" n="75 A SLIP."/>principles would let me, I'd become a P. B. myself."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130526">"And did you?" enquired Mr. Winks with interest.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130527">"Not quite! No, I took an affidavit or whatever you call it—made a declaration, yes, that's better—that my principles would not allow me, and I gave five hundred to the chapel fund, and never heard any more of 'em. Oh! I daresay they were very decent sort of people in their way.—but their way wasn't my way, and I can't say I found 'em interesting as acquaintances."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130528">Well, to return to the water party; it was, as I have just said, a success, a decided success, and perhaps the one who really enjoyed it more than anyone else was Sir Anthony Staunton, who remained the whole time a fixture at Laura Trafford's side.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130530">Naturally enough Laura was in the most brilliant spirits and looked as pretty a little plump edition of her piquant little mother (yes, it was becoming the fashion in Blankhampton, since Orford had expressed his intention of marrying into the Trafford family, to call Mrs. Trafford "piquant;" it was a mere detail, a merely trifling difference in the choice of words, for it conveyed very much the same impression as the word "pert," which had been in general use up to the time of Madge Trafford's engagement) as you could wish to see in a day's march, and on his part, Staunton got spoonier and spoonier, and more inclined to think Orford a downright clever fellow for having made <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130529" n="76 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>up his mind to marry into the Trafford family, than he had ever done in all his life for any reason.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130531">And Mrs. Trafford, merry little soul that she was, enjoyed herself like a child, looked after everybody, saw everything done for the comfort of all, and flirted with her new friend, Mr. Vyvyan—well, as Madge said with a laugh, to Orford—scandalously.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130532">But Orford scarcely responded to the laugh, in fact he was too busily occupied in watching the proceedings of Mrs. Trafford's new friend, Mr. Vyvyan, with the result of being more firmly convinced than ever that if he was the son of Gregory Vyvyan of Stormount, his mother must of necessity have been what he called "an out-and-out howler."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130533">It would have been difficult for Marcus Orford to define exactly what was amiss with the man or his manners; he was big and good-looking, had a good straight nose and a good square resolute chin, he had black, level eye-brows above full black, or I should say dark brown, eyes, and his complexion was brilliantly florid. Altogether he was a handsome man, and an uncommon-looking one into the bargain; but though he was as like the Vyvyans of Stormount as one of a dish of peas is like to the others, he lacked the air of distinction which above all things distinguished the members of that family from the common herd, and he bad one or two tricks of manner—not vulgarisms—for which Orford would dearly like to have shaken him.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130534" n="77 A SLIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130535">One of them was a way of standing with his arms hanging down to their full length, with the hands crossed one over the other with the backs of both hands uppermost; and another was a certain air of attention, intended to be very deferential, to the ladies who addressed him, an attitude in which the chin was held in, while he looked out from under his eye-brows in a furtive way, which made Orford positively long to kick him.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130536">"Why the devil can't the fellow look out of his eyes like an honest man who's got nothing to be ashamed of?" he said to himself irritably.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130537">The contrast between the two men was singularly marked, in truth, it was as great as could be between two men of the same race, and height, and weight, which they were, as nearly as possible. For Orford's head rose straight and bold above his broad shoulders, the chin was generally thrust a little outward, and his bonny, bold grey eyes looked straight and true at anybody or thing that he wanted to see. Yes, he was a marked contrast to Mr. Vivian Vyvyan, and he gave his verdict on that gentleman freely but briefly to anyone who mentioned him—" Goodish-looking chap and uncommonly like the Vyvyans; all the same, his mother must have been an out-and-out <hi rend="italic">howler</hi>."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130539">After the day of the water-party, however, he did not trouble himself about Mrs. Trafford's new friend or take any notice of him, except to give him a nod, and an "Er, how d'do?" on meeting, or an "Er, good-day," on parting; and if Mr. Vyvyan had any <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130538" n="78 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>idea of knowing the Black Horse through Captain the Honourable Marcus Orford, why he perforce gave the idea up, for Orford never noticed him any further than as I have just explained.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130540">Naturally they did not see very much of one another, although Vyvyan made tremendous running with Mrs. Trafford, and gossiping tongues in Blankhampton were soon at work concerning them; for Orford was taken up body and soul, one might say, with his sweetheart Madge, and when he was not lancing attendance on her in the various shops in the High Street—which, by-the-bye, was not very often, since she was able to do most of her shopping in the mornings—they passed their time in a secluded corner of the Winter Garden or in the obscurity of Mrs. Trafford's boudoir, where a little tea-tray set for two used to go when the larger one, at which Laura now presided, was taken into the drawing-room for the rest of the family.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130541">And it was wonderful how much envy that little tea-tray caused, among the very few people who knew of its existence.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130542">"Orford always was a lucky beggar," Sir Anthony Staunton grumbled one day to Laura, "he always gets spoilt wherever he goes. Now, why shouldn't, I be indulged with a special tea-tray all to myself?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130543">"I'll send your tea down to the library if you like," returned Laura, laughing, only you'd find it rather tiresome, wouldn't you?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130544">"Oh! by myself, yes," he answered.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130545" n="79 A SLIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130546">"Well, we cannot indulge you with Madge, you know, unless Marcus——"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130547">"He wouldn't. Besides, with all due respect to Miss Madge, whom I admire beyond everything, I shouldn't thank him if he would. But why shouldn't you and I have the library and a separate tea-tray as our own special privilege?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130548">She turned scarlet from chin to brow.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130549">"Well, because——" she began, stammering.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130550">"Yes, I know; but why shouldn't we?" he asked anxiously.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130551">"Oh! I don't know. I—I—Oh! what did you say, Mr. Vyvyan? Another cup of tea for Mrs. Fairlie? Oh, certainly! She takes sugar and cream, does she not?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130552">Yes, Mrs. Fairlie did take sugar and cream—"and the devil take her," as Staunton said, when he heard Vyvyan's formal smooth voice at Laura's elbow. And then, when Mrs. Fairlie had got her tea, sugar and cream and all, Vyvyan came back for another cup for Mrs. Trafford—who, to do her justice, would have thirsted for a week rather than have interrupted Staunton at such an important moment—then to fetch one for Miss Adair, then to have his own cup replenished, and in his wake came the inveterate old gossip, Colonel Coles, who stayed at the table to drink it, and contrived to put an end to Sir Anthony's opportunity altogether for that day.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130554">And after that it seemed as if everybody in the room was in league to prevent the implied question <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130553" n="80 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>being answered. Dever for a single moment was Laura left alone; and at last, when the little horse-shoe clock,—the emblem of "good luck" by-the-bye—on the mantel-shelf, struck the hour of seven, and not a soul had made the smallest attempt to say good-bye, Staunton got up in a fury, and bade Mrs. Trafford farewell.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130555">"Oh! are you—<hi rend="italic">going?</hi>" faltered Laura, who was being pestered by unwelcome attentions and compliments from old Coles.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130556">"Yes—good-bye," savagely, and without looking at her. "There's not a chance—at least, that is—good-bye," and the next moment, in spite of her entreating looks—which he did not see—he was gone.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130557">How shall I describe the girl's feelings? She felt as if she had missed Paradise, as if the world might come to an end as soon as it would, as if she could kill all these people who moved smilingly to-and-fro, treading the happiness of her whole life into its grave, with their careless, unheeding feet.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130558">It was by a great and brave effort that she kept her composure until the last to take leave had gone. It happened to be Colonel Coles, who fired off one of his antique and florid compliments upon her as he took her hand in farewell, and him she watched to the door with the last smile that she could summon to her poor, trembling lips.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130560">And then, when he was gone, when the closing of <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130559" n="81 A SLIP."/>the door in the hall below told them that he was really out of the house, she gave way altogether, and fell down beside her mother, and hid her face against that little woman's gown, and cried, and cried, and cried as if her very heart would break.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130561">"My dear—my dear child!" cried little Mrs. Trafford, in the utmost consternation and dismay—for this was a new and distressing departure from Laura's usual way—" What is the matter? You are ill, surely. Tell me, dear, what is it?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130562">But poor Laura was not able to stop her convulsive sobs in order to give an explanation to her sudden outburst of grief; on the contrary, she clutched her mother's gown tighter and tighter and sobbed on with such hysterical passion, that her cousin, attracted by the sound, ran in from the adjoining room, followed by Orford who stood aghast at the unusual sight and felt like a brute, though he didn't know why, and Mrs. Trafford, finding that neither she nor Madge, who had dropped upon her knees beside her cousin as soon as she saw something was grievously wrong with mind or body, could elicit a word from Laura, just took her in her arms, and, holding her head against her bosom, let her grief exhaust itself on that comfortable haven, taking no steps to soothe her save by an occasional There, there—there, there——"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130564">Marcus Orford helplessly watching them—Laura, sobbing, Madge gently smoothing one of her hands, and Mrs. Trafford swaying to and fro with the indescribable air of comfort the actions of a tender-<pb xml:id="jwgarri_130563" n="82 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>hearted woman are capable of showing—said to himself that Urquhart had proved himself no such fool when he wanted to marry her.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130565">"By Jove! she's a right good sort, and no mistake about it," his thoughts ran, "and as bonny a little woman as a disappointed chap of Urquhart's age has any need to go for,"—and then, Laura's sobs having suddenly come to an end, he said aloud:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130566">"Mrs. Traff, give her a brandy and soda—there's nothing on earth like it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130567">"The very thing, my dear boy," she exclaimed, "you always suggest a sensible course. Do you mind going into the dining-room and ringing for Cox?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130568">But not even the brandy and soda loosened Laura's tongue. She sat up on the floor beside her mother when Orford appeared at her elbow and prepared to add the soda to the brandy, and dried her eyes and said with a piteous catch of her breath, that she'd been 'an awful donkey to make such an exhibition'—but that really she couldn't help it, and—and—she thought the heat of the room had been too much for her, and that the people had upset her or—or—something. Anyway, she didn't feel very well;—and then she drank the draught which Orford had prepared for her, and dried her eyes again, after which she said she felt better, and tried to smile by way of proving her words; but it was a poor, miserable attempt at a smile, and Orford saw that it was so.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130570">"Oh, you're upset Laura, that's what it is," he said, in his jovial, off-hand tones. "And if old Coles <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130569" n="83 A SLIP."/>has been here all the afternoon, I'm not surprised at it. You'll be better when you've had dinner, and, by-the-by, Mrs. Traff', that reminds me, I must be off to mine."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130571">"Oh! you'll dine here?" she cried.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130572">"Not to-night, Mrs. Traffa', a thousand thanks all the same," he answered, "I must dine at mess to-night."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130573">Mrs. Trafford followed him down into the hall.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130574">"Why won't you stay?" she asked. "Madge will be so disappointed."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130575">"Oh, no, she won't; she gave me a look which. meant 'Go away.' Laura's upset and seedy, and will eat her dinner all the better for being without me. No, I won't stay to-night, thanks. I'll come down in the morning and see how she is. Good-bye."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130576">He bent—aye, and he had to bend—down and kissed her as her son might have done, and the next moment was off, going at a sharp pace along St. Eve's, his toes well turned out and his head held high in air; and more than one society-girl, on her way home to dinner, looked at him with admiring eyes, and thought what a shame it was that one of "the Trafford lot" should have secured such a splendid fellow, and have the prospect of being Lady Ceespring into the bargain—not that they had anything against Madge personally, but she was one of "the Trafford lot"—people who had just come to Blankhampton, and were nobody knew who or what.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130578">As for Mrs. Trafford, she watched him out of sight <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130577" n="84 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>and murmured "Dear boy" as he turned the corner, and then she went back to her drawing-room to try and find out what had been the cause of this unusual outburst of grief. With a little trouble she got at the bottom of the mystery, and Laura, with more sobs and tears, poor girl, told them—and surely never, since the foundation of the world itself, did three more sympathetic pairs of ears listen to a tale of woe—how cruel Fate had been to her that miserable day!</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130579">"He will never ask me again," she sobbed, casting herself into Madge's sympathetic arms. "I know he thought I was—was—trying to avoid answering."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130580">"Oh! no—no—he could not, my dear," said Mrs. Trafford, in her most soothing voice, though in truth she could have knocked her pert little head, with all its wonderful arrangement of coils and plaits and its dainty little make-believe cap, against the wall for her stupidity in not having left Laura free for that afternoon. "Don't worry about it," she went on, "it will be all right. We will give him an opportunity of speaking out, without any fear of an interruption. It will be all right; but don't distress yourself, darling, that won't do any good and will only make you look ill and wretched."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130581">"He won't come again," sobbed Laura.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130583">"He must come to the wedding, for he has promised to be best man," put in Madge. For a moment Laura was pacified by this solid and substantial bit of comfort; the next she said with a <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130582" n="85 A SLIP."/>dejected sigh, "But I shall not be near him, Julie will be first bridesmaid."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130584">"Oh! I'll give up that honour if it will secure me such a brother-in-law," cried Julia, with her little cracked laugh.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130585">"You cannot; it would look too pointed. All Blankhampton would be talking about it, and saying we had arranged Madge's wedding, so as to catch Sir Anthony; and," she added, with a mournful air, "they would never know or believe he had once gone so near to asking me, would they?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130586">"What matters what Blankhampton thinks of any of us?" cried Madge, with hearty contempt. "They bear us no goodwill now, and I'm sure I get such black looks that sometimes I feel quite nervous when I'm out alone."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130587">"And if that was all, I'll retire from the office of bridesmaid altogether," cried Julia. "Madge wouldn't be offended under the circumstances, would you, Madge?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130588">"Certainly not—far from it," answered Madge, with alacrity. "But there—long before the wedding it will be all right and straight between you."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130589">"Meantime, Marcus Orford had, thanks to his long legs, got quickly back to barracks. He had not much time to spare, but he made enough to go into Staunton's quarters—where, by-the-bye, he noticed a photograph of Laura Trafford set up against one of the ornaments on the mantel-shelf.</p>
        <pb n="86 GARRISON GOSSIP." pages="86" facs="jwgarri086"/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130591">"I say, old man, why didn't you wait for me? he asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130592">"Didn't know you were coming back," returned Staunton, with anything but a polite tone.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130593">"No more I was; but something's up at No. 7. We went into the drawing-room, Madge and I, and found Laura crying, as if her heart would break."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130594">"Crying?" repeated Staunton, in a curiously strained voice.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130595">"Yes, rather. Did you notice anything amiss?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130596">For a moment or so, Staunton looked things unutterable. "It's that dam fool, old Coles," he burst out savagely—but in a softer voice "and she was crying, was she?" and then he added, "Confound him!"</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130597" n="[87]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_018" n="8" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER VIII.<lb/>A DISH OF SCANDAL.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130598">"I find great numbers of moderately good people, who think it fine to talk Scandal. They regard it as a sort of evidence of their own goodness."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—F. W. FABER.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130599">AT the River House that evening, all was light and gaiety, for the Antrobuses were giving a dinner-party.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130600">The River House was very well adapted for that sort of thing, being a large square house, with fine lofty rooms, and an entrance hall and vestibule which was quite palatial. On this evening the whole place was looking its best. Ferns and flowers were set here and there, Chinese lanterns shed their soft glow among the creepers and jessamine which wreathed the veranda, and garden chairs were set out beneath them, so that the men could enjoy the fragrant and soothing after-dinner cigarette and chat with the ladies at the same time.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130602">In the drawing-room, which was lighted only by candles, there were flowers in profusion, and in the dining-room they were put about wherever space could be found for them, between the sparkling silver and glass. In short, the effect of the whole <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130601" n="88 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>establishment was one to make you think of a celebrated entertainment which took place at the beginning of this century.</p>
        <q>
          <lg type="stanza">
            <l>"There was a sound of revelry by night,</l>
            <l>And Belgium's capital had gathered then</l>
            <l>Her beauty and her chivalry; and bright</l>
            <l>The lamps shone o'er fair women and brave men."</l>
          </lg>
        </q>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130603">It was all thus. There was the sound of revelry, the softly shining lamps, the undeniably fair women, and, let us try to believe, the brave men. Perhaps, as Mr. Winks was the only soldier present, it would be as well to leave chivalry out of the comparison, for, alas! Mr. Winks was drifting, drifting on, over a dangerous sea, full of sunken rocks and breakers, which would probably end in bringing him to shipwreck.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130605">It was unlike him to be torn two ways at once; it was utterly foreign to his nature to be thus playing fast and loose with love, engaged to one girl (and such a girl) and yet be hanging about after another girl (and she such a girl too) with whom he had not the very smallest intention of ever dividing the honours of his title. Moral fear he had none—if he chose to go in a certain direction and believe himself right in going that way, not all the combined chaff and bullying of his brother officers could coax or drive him into going so much as a hair's breadth out of his own line; and yet, here he was, engaged to Lady Nell Temple whom he had loved all his life, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130604" n="89 A DISH OF SCANDAL."/>yet drifting along beside Polly Antrobus, not so much fascinated by the girl, as fallen a victim to the machinations of her astute mother,—for in spite of all bygone failures, Mrs. Hugh was an astute woman, aye, and a game old bird into the bargain.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130606">The soup was just off, ox-tail of the best, and the fish, salmon (if you want to know exactly what fish) was just on, when Mrs. Hugh, in her oiliest tones, began to discuss the gossip of the garrison with Mr. Winks, who sat beside her.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130607">"Lord Charterhouse," she began, "do you think it's true about Colonel Coles?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130608">"I don't know. What about him, Mrs. Antrobus?" he answered. "I don't think I've heard anything particular about him."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130609">"Well, I'm told," said she, with an important air of imparting accurate information, "and I really believe there's something in it, that he is going to be married."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130610">"You don't say so? Poor old chap! It must be on the better-late-than-never principle," observed Mr. Winks indulgently. "And who is the lady?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130611">"Who do you think?" with her little airy laugh.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130612">Oh! I can't say. There's so much They say, What say they? Let 'em say,' in Blankhampton, you know. But it's not Mrs. Trafford, I'll go bail for that—she wouldn't look at him—be a good thing for him if she would."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130614">"Oh! he's done better than Mrs. Traf-FORD," cried Mrs. Hugh smiling, and unconsciously elong-<pb xml:id="jwgarri_130613" n="90 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>ating and magnifying little Mrs. Traff's name into a regular mouthful.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130615">"Really? Oh! do put me out of my misery. Who is it?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130616">"Mrs. Forster."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130617">As a matter of fact, little Mr. Winks very nearly jumped out of his chair with astonishment.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130618">"You don't mean it!" he exclaimed.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130619">Mrs. Hugh nodded.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130620">"Yes, I do. It came to me to-day as an absolute fact—a fa—ct. <hi rend="italic">I</hi> think," she added with a wise, reflective air, "that he has done very, well for himself. It isn't ev-erybody who would care to marry Colonel Coles."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130621">"That's true, Mrs. Antrobus," returned Mr. Winks, "but I should think it isn't any-body who would like to marry Mrs. Forster. I know I'd sooner die first!" he ended emphatically.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130622">Mrs. Hugh beamed upon him with indulgent pride, and Mr. Winks asked a question:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130623">"Where did you hear it?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130624">Mrs. Hildersley was here this afternoon. She told me."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130625">"Oh, really! Did she tell you anything about the Graham affair?" he enquired in a distinctly sarcastic tone.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130626">Mrs. Hugh did not notice it, and replied simply enough:</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130627">"Yes; she did indeed. She told me <hi rend="italic">all</hi> about it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130629">Mr. Winks put his head a shade closer to Mrs. <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130628" n="91 A DISH OF SCANDAL."/>Hugh's smart lace cap, and listened with a very eager air of attention.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130630">"Yes?" he said, in a tone which begged her to go on.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130631">Mrs. Hugh went on.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130632">"I must say I like Mrs. Hildersley <hi rend="italic">very</hi> much," she declared, as if her verdict sealed the fate of Mrs. Hildersley from that time forth and for ever more. "I al-ways did like her, and though I confess for some little time past I have not sought her out at all, in fact, I have rather given her the cold shoulder, yet, when she came and had a quiet talk to me, I quite absolved her in my own mind from the least blame in the miserable bit of gossip which has run from one end of Blankhampton to the other."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130633">"About Graham?" murmured Mr. Winks, helping himself to salt.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130634">"About Captain Graham—yes. Of course, as you know, Lord Charterhouse, in this wicked world we have to be very careful how much or how little we believe. I am not an ill-natured woman always ready and willing to think the worst of everybody, and when I heard this awful report about Mrs. Hildersley, I said not a word—I simply kept out of her way until I had real confirmation for or against it. I thought it was the kindest and most neighbourly and most charitable thing to do."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130635">"Awfully good of you," put in Mr. Winks, in a murmur.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130637">It did not occur to him—as it would have done to <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130636" n="92 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>Orford's keener and quicker mind—that, in truth, Mrs. Hugh had, by her mysterious allusions, her nods, her little oily, yet airy laugh, her dark hints and her self-important air of possessing all knowledge, helped the story on its way quite as effectually as even old Coles, the gossip <hi rend="italic">par excellence</hi> of the whole garrison, had done.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130638">Mrs. Hugh, however, disclaimed the extreme goodness of her actions.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130639">"Well, of course, I like to be kind and charitable as far as I can, but, at the same time, I must admit that I was not altogether disinterested in keeping aloof. I have my daughters to think of," with a certain air of dignity, such as would have tickled Orford's sense of the ridiculous greatly but which rather impressed Mr. Winks than otherwise. "<hi rend="italic">And</hi>—er—I was very glad when Mrs. Hildersley herself set my mind at rest about the matter."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130640">"She did that?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130641">"Oh! perfectly—perfectly. She was so open and simple, and frank about it; in fact, she told me <hi rend="italic">all</hi> about it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130642">"But if it's not true about her, what could there be to tell?" asked Mr. Winks.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130643">"A great deal," said Mrs. Hugh, with an ominously quiet and even tone; then added, with her most portentous nod, "It's all true about Mrs. Farquhar, every word of it. In fact, Mrs Hildersley told me the story we have all heard, just word for word, only that her position and Mrs. Farquhar's were reversed."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130644" n="93 A DISH OF SCANDAL."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130645">"You mean that she went and fetched Mrs. Farquhar back?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130646">"Yes; just so."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130647">"And that Mrs. Farquhar was on the point of running away with Graham?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130648">"Exactly."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130649">"And she told you so positively?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130650">"Oh! yes, positively."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130651">Mr. Winks pondered for a moment.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130652">"She really put it into plain words? She didn't merely let you gather or infer that it was so?" he persisted.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130653">"My dear Lord Charterhouse, she told me in plain English," returned Mrs. Hugh without hesitation.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130654">"H—m!" muttered Mr. Winks, and pondered for another space. "I say, Mrs. Antrobus, don't it seem to you very mean to peach about such a matter, if it's really true?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130656">"There can be nothing mean in telling the truth, Lord Charterhouse," said Mrs. Hugh with dignity. "Besides, as she said herself, poor thing—and she almost burst into tears as she told me—besides, she was obliged to tell the truth in self-defence, for Mrs. Farquhar has done her best to spread the story far and wide. It is really strange," Mrs. Hugh continued reflectively, "that if you do a person a good turn, they seem to become your enemies immediately, and the greater the service you render the more bitter and lasting is the enmity you have in return for it—" and she sighed, as if her whole <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130655" n="94 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>life had been spent in doing good unto others for the wages of thankless ingratitude!</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130657">"But do you know, Mrs. Farquhar stood up for her right and left—I know that for certain. One day at Mrs. Trafford's, she shut everybody up point-blank, and Orford backed her up."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130658">"I have not the least doubt of that," returned Mrs. Hugh, who had not thought very much of Orford, since he had chosen to marry into another family than hers.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130659">"I don't think I altogether trust Mrs. Hildersley," Mr. Winks declared. "And if I were you, Mrs. Antrobus, I should keep clear of her a little longer. Seems to me such a mean thing to go prating about a thing of that kind; sort of thing you'd like to kick a man for, don't you know?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130660">Mrs. Hugh was just about to reply; but her attention was distracted, and the conversation brought to an abrupt close by the scowling frown which sat up aloft on Mr. Herrick Brentham's noble brow, and which Mrs. Hugh perceived at that moment for the first time.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130661">The cause thereof was not far to seek, for To-To, who naturally sat beside her betrothed, was talking in a somewhat interested manner to the gentleman upon her other hand, a circumstance not unusual with a bride-elect in her father's house, but evidently singularly disconcerting to the festive Herrick.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130663">For the rest of the meal Mrs. Hugh sat on thorns, and how fervently she longed for the blissful and <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130662" n="95 A DISH OF SCANDAL."/>convenient moment when, with fan and gloves and lace-bordered broidered handkerchief, she could signal to the ladies to take flight like a covey of startled birds on the wing, would need a more graphic pen than mine to tell. But, alas, a plump pheasant had but that moment been set before her husband, so that she was compelled with smiles and fortitude to endure to the bitter end, still four courses away. Poor Mrs. Hugh! She had had most of the trouble in preparing and arranging for this party, and behold the bride-elect must needs go and spoil it all for her, must needs laugh and coquet—<hi rend="italic">scandalously</hi>, as Mrs. Hugh said afterwards—with this man, who had always admired her, while Herrick grew blacker and blacker, sulkier and sulkier, and neglecting his dinner, gave all his attention to the wine, a course which was foolish, and which, had he been brought up in an atmosphere of good liquor, he would have known better than to take as a haven of refuge, for not being very good wine, a headache was bound to follow in due course.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130664">If Mrs. Hugh had but known it, it would, during those four uncomfortable courses, have been of the greatest comfort to her.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130665">"Oh, dear, dear," she said to herself, with an inward groan, "Why will To-To be so foolish? I believe she wants to tempt Herrick into a display of jealousy."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130667">She said as much to Polly after they reached the drawing-room and To-To had vanished up the <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130666" n="96 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>stairs in the direction of her own room. Polly was not particularly sympathetic.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130668">"I shouldn't worry about it, if I were you, Mamma," she said quietly. "It is better To-To should know exactly what he is, while she has time to change her mind."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130669">"Change her mind!" exclaimed Mrs. Hugh in a whisper of horror. "And what about her trousseau?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130670">"Oh! I don't suppose she will change it—she lilies him well enough; it's a pity he's so terribly jealous."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130671">"A pity!" echoed her mother. "It is simply deplorable—de—plorable, Polly! Ah, that is the worst of these self-made people, they never know how to control their feelings,"—and then she added, with a sigh—"I never thought a child of mine would marry into a <hi rend="italic">new</hi> family. For what is <hi rend="italic">money</hi> in comparison with birth and all that birth brings?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130672">Polly, after her way, looked very wise, but she had nothing to say on the subject, so Mrs. Hugh went back to her guests with the comforting assurance that Polly would never trouble her in that fashion.</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130673" n="[97]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_019" n="9" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER IX.<lb/>DIFFIDENCE.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130674">"The Wheel of Fortune turns incessantly round, and who can say within himself 'I shall to-day be uppermost'?"</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—CONFUCIUS.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130675">WHEN Laura Trafford had been in the depths of distress at the unwelcome circumstances which had occurred to prevent her coming to an understanding with Sir Anthony Staunton, her mother had uttered words of prophecy best calculated to soothe her, and also thoroughly in accordance with her motherly wishes and desires.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130676">"Never mind, dear," she had said when Laura sobbed out that he would never ask her again, "we will give him an opportunity of speaking out without any fear of interruption."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130677">Ah, yes; it had all seemed so easy to accomplish then. She had looked forward to arranging one or two pleasant little entertainments, at one or other of which Sir Anthony would be able to speak his mind and gather from Laura that her heart was his.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130679">But, alas! this is but a contrary and troublous world, which even a little woman, who loves her own way—aye, and will have it by hook or by crook—cannot always arrange to her liking, or bend at her will and pleasure. She planned and contrived, and <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130678" n="98 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>arranged to make the opportunities she had so confidently promised to Laura; she almost proposed in Sir Anthony's stead—and she quite accepted in Laura's—only that Staunton was too dense or too troubled to perceive the drift of her conversation, while Laura was too proud to take advantage of her good offices. For, somehow or other, a wall of constraint and coldness had suddenly grown up between these two, and they met rather as if they had had a quarrel than otherwise; met with the most frigid politeness and ceremonious demeanour, which, as time went on, froze instead of melting under the sunshine of Mrs. Trafford's brightness and gaiety.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130680">The first time they met was one afternoon when Staunton called at the pretty house in St. Eve's. He found Mrs. Trafford alone in her rose-lighted drawing-room, her most becoming confection perched carelessly on the top of her head, her prettiest gown on, and her little bands well-occupied by some knitting-work of crimson silk unmistakably intended for a masculine foot, and that not a particularly small one.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130681">"Oh, how do you do?" she said, in her most cordial tone. "Cox, let us have tea at once, and tell the young ladies Sir Anthony Staunton is here," and then, as the neat maid went her way and left them alone, turned to him again and said, "I had quite given. myself up to a brown study. Oh, no, I am not alone,—not alone in the house, that is—but the girls are very busy, and I think Madge's trousseau is answerable for their seclusion."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130682" n="99 DIFFIDENCE."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130683">Sir Anthony pulled the fingers of his gloves out, one after another, and said that lie supposed a wedding made a good deal of work and worry in a house. If Mrs. Trafford had only given him a good lead—as good as he had given her—he would have gone on to say that he had no doubt one gave so much trouble that a second would scarcely be felt at all.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130684">But Mrs. Trafford, in spite of her being the undeniably clever little woman that she was, did not perceive the drift of his remark, and really did not give him a lead at all. Instead, she entered into a playful and voluble account of the fearful amount of patience this wedding in particular was costing her.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130685">"My dear Sir Anthony," she exclaimed, "it is wearing me to death—to—death. The worry of planning and arranging, the anxiety lest everything should riot be ready by the day, the dreadful way in which the tiresome trades-people upset <hi rend="italic">all</hi> one's plans is really something terrible. And Madge is a perfect slave, poor child, without leisure even to choose her own garments, to say nothing of giving any time to forwarding matters. And if I say a word to Marcus, he just says: 'My dear Mrs. Traff', why worry? I have seen to Madge's wedding gown, and for the rest it really won't matter.' However," with a sigh, "it is a worry and an anxiety which is very pleasant, and I feel amply repaid every time I see the two together."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130687">"Yes, they are a handsome couple," put in Sir <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130686" n="100 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>Anthony, who felt it would an unheard-of piece of cheek to coolly propose to saddle the poor little woman with a second such load of expense and trouble.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130688">"Very. Oh, I am very proud of my niece and my nephew to be, I assure you," and then she smoothed out her handiwork and said, "Is not that a pretty colour? I am knitting Marcus half-a-dozen pairs of socks."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130689">If Sir Anthony had had any sense—that is common sense—he would at once have expressed a wish that he might be lucky enough to get half-a-dozen pairs of lovely silk socks knitted for him. Unfortunately, he had no sense of that kind, only a sense of shame-facedness, which set him thinking about the number of times the little woman's needles would go click-click against one another before those twelve socks would be finished and ready for wearing; and for the very life and soul of him he could not then have hinted to her what in truth was lying so very near to his heart.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130690">After a few minutes Cox appeared with the tea-tray and some delicious-looking hot buttered scones, for Mrs. Trafford knew far too well the heart—and other regions—of man to trust to the fascinations of thin bread and butter, which generally means that the loaf is stale.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130691">"The young ladies are at home, Cox?" Mrs. Trafford asked, wondering why Laura had not made her appearance."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130693">"Yes, ma'am," Cox replied, settling with care the <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130692" n="101 DIFFIDENCE."/>position of the tea-things, "the young ladies will be here directly," and then she departed.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130694">Mrs. Trafford raised her eyes from her work and looked with a smile at Staunton.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130695">"It means bonnets," she said, nodding her head and smiling again. "Whenever I am kept waiting by one of the girls now, I generally find out that bonnets have had something to do with it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130696">"But what do they do with so many bonnets?" he asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130697">"Wear them, my dear Sir Anthony," returned the lady promptly, "or rather Madge will, dear child."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130698">But Staunton was thoroughly mystified and could not imagine what the bonnets which would be worn on some future day by Orford's bride elect, could. have to do with Mrs. Trafford being continually kept waiting by her daughters. As a matter of fact however, one of the chief features of Madge's trousseau was a hat or bonnet to match each one of her dresses, and as that would have meant the expenditure of a great deal of money—to have them all from a good milliner, that is—Madge had chosen to have three or four sent to her from a first-rate woman in Town, and had planned the others herself. But Orford was in St. Eve's so many hours out of the waking ones which went to make up a day, that Madge had but the mornings for work, and her cousins were obliged to help her, so that while she pinned her pretty head-coverings together, Laura had to undertake the secure stitching of them.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130699" n="102 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130700">However, Mrs. Trafford did not enter into all this, and Staunton, not understanding her allusion to bonnets, pursued the subject no further. A few minutes later the girls came in together, when he found his heart beating so furiously that he had scarce breath enough to answer Julia's high-spoken, hail-fellow-well-met style of greeting.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130701">"Ah! how d'do, Sir Anthony," she called out—she was quite close to him, so that there was really no need for this storm-at-sea kind of voice—"Did you think we were never coming? I hope you didn't think us rude. Fact was, Laura and I were awfully busy. You've no idea what a lot there is to do for a wedding."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130702">It was still the same cry—the trouble of a wedding; and Sir Anthony felt absolutely wicked even to be <hi rend="italic">thinking</hi> of putting them all about in this way on his account. He wondered how Orford could have the face to go coolly in and out as he did, with his separate tea-tray and all the other privileges—such as crimson silken socks, and a room set apart for him, which appertained to the position of bridegroom-elect.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130703">"No," he said in answer to Julia's assertion that he had no idea what a lot there is to do for a wedding, "that's very true—and I don't think I particularly want to know."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130705">Almost as the words left his tongue, he repented them, and could have bitten off the end of that blundering and unruly member for saying them. In truth they conveyed quite a different impression <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130704" n="103 DIFFIDENCE."/>to that which he intended, and he made haste to try and repair his mistake.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130706">"At least, that is, I mean—Oh! how do you do, Miss Laura?—I mean that, of course, I should be only too glad to be having the trouble of arranging for <hi rend="italic">my</hi> wedding—what poor, miserable, unmarried beggar wouldn't? Only, it seems that men have such an awful lot of trouble on their own account, lawyers, and settlements, and presents, and bouquets, and orange-blossoms, and the rest, that if he really—er—knew, that is comprehended, all the trouble the bride and her people have, a man would never have the cheek to propose getting married at all."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130707">He felt that it was a lame and a miserable explanation, and stole a glance at Laura to see in what way it had affected her. Apparently she was quite unmoved by it, and was busying herself with the tea-tray, in spite of a despairing protest from Mrs. Trafford to leave that matter to her. But, in truth, she was so deeply wounded by his first speech that, in the effort to control her feelings and hide her pain, she never even heard the second. Julia, on the contrary, did hear, and answered it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130708">"Oh! I don't know—of course it's a lot of trouble, and it's part of the business to make a great fuss, but in reality everybody <hi rend="italic">likes</hi> a wedding."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130709">"Everybody," put in Mrs. Trafford with an indulgent smile; "for my part, I won't hesitate to say I love them."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130711">As far as Sir Anthony was concerned personally, it was an admirably wise little speech; but, unfor-<pb xml:id="jwgarri_130710" n="104 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>tunately, Laura, still stinging under the supposed slight conveyed in Sir Anthony's untimely words, cast at that moment such a look of reproach and fury at her mother, whom she knew was on the watch to help her, that he fairly quailed before it. He could be dense at times, but he understood <hi rend="italic">that</hi>, or thought he did, which amounted to very much the same thing.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130712">Mrs. Trafford, however, did not happen to see the look, and went serenely on.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130713">"I think most people do like them, and though it's really very foolish, they often pretend that they don't. I had Mrs. Antrobus here yesterday, and really," with a gay laugh, "if her wedding does not come off soon, I should not like to be answerable for the consequences. Poor thing, she is so stout and seems to feel exertion so terribly, and yet is so indomitably active in spite of it all. And she says that, really it is <hi rend="italic">most</hi> ex-tra-ord-inary, that while they have five LARGE sitting-rooms at the River House, the engaged couple seem to occupy them <hi rend="italic">all</hi> at once. 'And I assure you, my dear Mrs. Traf-FORD,' she ended, 'I came to see you to-day because I felt sure I should find a sympathetic soul."'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130714">"And did she?" Staunton enquired.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130716">"No, I cannot say that she did, particularly," answered Mrs. Trafford. "Of course, I told her I was very sorry for her being worried in this way, and said I thought it a pity for engaged people not to control their feelings and remember that a great <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130715" n="105 DIFFIDENCE."/>display of affection is always embarrassing and very often distasteful to others. Then she asked me how my love-birds comported themselves; upon which I told her that they comported themselves exceedingly well."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130717">It was good for Staunton's blundering awkwardness, and for Laura's sensitive desire to shrink out of his sight altogether if possible, that at this point they all went off into fits of laughter at the idea of Marcus Orford being called a love-bird.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130718">"What a joke for the fellows," Staunton laughed. "Orford will be known as 'the love-bird' for the rest of his natural life."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130719">"I hope not. Madge will not like that," Mrs. Trafford said, laughing; "and she, dear child, is most punctilious about her manner to him in public."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130720">At that moment the maid, Cox, entered the room, and presented a card to her mistress. Mrs. Trafford took it, and examined it through her double eye-glasses, then turned to Sir Anthony.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130721">"You will excuse me for a few minutes, Sir Anthony, I am sure. It is a matter of important business."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130722">"Oh, certainly," said he, with a bow.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130723">"Thank you."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130724">Her manner was very grave as he held the door open for her to go out, and she gave him an equally grave bend of her head in token of thinks for the courtesy.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130725">Julia looked at Laura with raised eyebrows, as Sir Anthony closed the door, and said:</p>
        <pb n="106 GARRISON GOSSIP." pages="106" facs="jwgarri106"/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130727">"Do you think I had better go, Laurie?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130728">"Mother would have asked you, if she had wanted you," said Laura, mindful of the fact that her sister's departure would leave her alone with Sir Anthony.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130729">So Julia, thus answered and apparently satisfied, sat down again, and applied herself once more to the neat little pile of hot buttered scones.</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130730" n="[107]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_020" n="10" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER X.<lb/>A BURDEN OF SORROW.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130731">"I am a poor, lonely girl, whom God has set here in an evil world, and given her only a white robe, and bid her give it back to Him, as white as when she put it on."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—HAWTHORNE.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130732">THE card which Cox had brought to her mistress bore the name of "Mrs. Charles Farquhar," and below it was written, in pencil: "Can I see you <hi rend="italic">alone</hi> for a few minutes? Of the gravest importance."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130733">Of course she never thought for an instant of denying herself after such an appeal—in fact, I do not think she would at any time have denied herself to Mrs. Farquhar, who was a woman she well-liked and respected. But she rose and went out of the room with a horrible dread knocking at her heart, for an idea had all at once seized her that Mrs. Farquhar had come to tell her that which would put an end to Orford's engagement with Madge; and, I am bound to say, that at the thought of Madge's almost completed wedding outfit, Mrs. Trafford's careful soul was sick within her.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130734">But Mrs. Farquhar had come on no such mission. She rose when Mrs. Trafford entered the little library, and at once blurted out the nature of her errand.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130735" n="108 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130736">"Oh! Mrs. Trafford," she said, "I'm in such horrible trouble—I don't know which way to turn. I've come to you because there's not a soul in Blankhampton I can trust, except you, for my sister has gone to San Remo for the winter, and, with Charlie in Egypt, I am at my wits' end—I am indeed. I don't know which way to turn, except to you."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130737">Mrs. Trafford saw by the poor soul's white and haggard face that her trouble was indeed dire and of the worst, and she was not the woman to make little of such distress as this. She gave a sigh of relief to find that her personal fears had been without foundation, but even as it passed her lips, she drew her excited visitor to the sofa and made her sit down beside her, telling her, by the motherly way in which she cuddled her trembling hand within her own, that in coming to her, she had not chosen a wrong place of refuge.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130738">"What is it, my dear?" she asked. "Tell me all about it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130739">But, for a moment, Mrs. Farquhar could not tell her what the trouble was; an indignant wave of colour swept across her face and faded out, leaving it more white and haggard than before. Then she burst out. "Oh! Mrs. Trafford, they are saying in the town that it was <hi rend="italic">I</hi> who went off that night with Captain Graham—<hi rend="italic">I</hi>—<hi rend="italic">I!</hi> And I don't know what to do—I don't know how to prove my innocence. I haven't a soul I can turn to, and I feel as if I must be going mad."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130740" n="109 A BURDEN OF SORROW."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130741">Mrs. Trafford looked so thoroughly astounded, that, for a moment, the other thought she was turning against her.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130742">"Don't say that you believe it she cried. "It will be my only hope gone."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130743">"Believe it!" repeated Mrs. Trafford, in utter scorn. "My dear, it's absurd. I don't believe any woman on earth would go off with such a little toad. I don't think any-body in their senses will ever believe that such a thought entered your mind for an instant."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130744">"But, they do—they have!" cried Mrs. Farquhar wildly. "And some people have cut me already—already."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130745">"But you must disprove it," said Mrs. Trafford firmly, for she wanted to get rid of the chaff of distress and indignation, so as better to see and judge of the grains of truth which lay beneath.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130746">"I cannot," said the other sadly. "I cannot!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130747">"Oh, nonsense, nonsense, my dear; <hi rend="italic">you must!</hi>" cried Mrs. Trafford sharply. "It will be the easiest thing in the world. We all know the date on which the scandal-mongers declared the elopement took place—I can fig it positively both by my diary and by my visiting book, which will prove conclusively that I had heard the rumour that afternoon, and that you were present at an afternoon tea at my house that very day. My dear, a dozen people would be able to swear to it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130748">"Yes, I know; I have thought of all that," with a hopeless shake of the head.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130749" n="110 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130750">"And you must bring someone to shoat where you were the previous evening—<hi rend="italic">the</hi> evening, in short," Mrs. Trafford went on briskly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130751">Mrs. Farquhar shook her head more despairingly even than before.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130752">"That is just what I cannot get over. I can't bring anyone to speak for me then."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130753">"But why? You will tell me?" coaxingly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130754">"Oh, Mrs. Trafford, there is no secret about it; I had meant to keep it so, but all the world may know now"—and then she told her all the circumstances of that painful night's work, not omitting a single word from beginning to end.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130755">Little Mrs. Trafford opened her eyes wide indeed at the story, and at the end of it she spoke her mind and gave her counsel.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130756">"Of course, my dear, it is very goad and loyal of you to wish to shield this unhappy and miserable woman—whom God above help if her heart is in anyway touched by that man. Graham; but, at the same time, you have your life's happiness and that of your husband to think of and guard, and, as Mrs. Hildersley has not taken much care of her good name, I do not see that you need make such great sacrifices in order to do it for her. Probably the story will die a natural death, as scandal so often does; if it does not, you must simply insist upon Mrs. Hildersley speaking up in your vindication."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130758">The unhappy victim of gossip drew a long breath as Mrs. Trafford came to the end of her say—a long <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130757" n="111 A BURDEN OF SORROW."/>breath, which was neither more nor less than a gasp for air.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130759">"Mrs. Trafford," she said, in a piteous tone, "I hardly expect you to credit it—<hi rend="italic">but it is Mrs. Hildersley herself</hi> who brings this awful accusation against me!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130760">"<hi rend="italic">Impossible!</hi>" Mrs. Trafford burst out.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130761">"No, it is not impossible, it is true. I heard it from Mrs. Forster, to whom she had told it, and I went across to her at once. I 'Emily,' I said, 'when you needed it I stood by you and did you a great service, and now the time has come when you must stand by me,' and—and—she——" but at this point the poor soul's pent-up indignation and distress could be kept prisoner no longer and burst out in a storm of wild grief, such as Mrs. Trafford had never seen in all her life before. She let her cry on in peace for a little time, and then made an effort to get her to finish her story.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130762">"Now—now, dear," she urged, "pray try to tell me everything there is to know. It is no use my entering into the case with but half a brief, you know."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130763">"She asked me how I <hi rend="italic">dared</hi> go to her on such an errand—how I <hi rend="italic">dared</hi> try to fasten my guilt on her. <hi rend="italic">My guilt</hi>!" with a wild, hysterical laugh. "<hi rend="italic">I</hi>,—who wouldn't touch him with a pair of tongs!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130764">"Then she ignores her share in the affair altogether?"</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130765" n="112 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130766">"No, indeed—nothing of the kind. She simply reverses our positions, and says that <hi rend="italic">she</hi> went to save <hi rend="italic">me</hi>. I can't <hi rend="italic">prove</hi> it was otherwise. I did go—and, as she reminded me, 'You went <hi rend="italic">by yourself</hi> to Captain Graham's office, and were seen by several people leaving it. His orderly was at hand and probably heard you imploring him for some favour; at all events, his wife told me you had been there and that he was very cold to you. And so, you wicked woman,' she said—yes, she called me a wicked woman—'after all I have done for you, this is the reward you give me. I don't know,' she ended, '<hi rend="italic">how you have the audacity to face me</hi>.' So you see, Mrs. Trafford, what a complete trap I am in. I can only tell the truth, and I must admit that the true story sounds by far the most improbable one of the two."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130767">"It is shameful!" Mrs. Trafford cried in disgust and anger.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130768">"But you believe me?" asked Mrs. Farquhar, timidly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130769">"Oh, my dear! Believe you?—as implicitly as I believe in that Providence above us, which will unmask this wicked plot against you and make the triumph of the innocent complete and unassailable "—and with this she opened her arms, and her unhappy guest crept into them and laid her head upon her shoulders, feeling that she had got into Sanctuary.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130771">For a long time they sat thus, silent; and at last, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130770" n="113 A BURDEN OF SORROW."/>Mrs. Trafford spoke, quoting a few lines of a poem, in a tone which betokened deep thought:
<q><lg type="stanza"><l>"For Jenny, my cousin, had come to the place, and I knew right well</l><l>That Jenny had tript in her time: I knew, but I would not tell.</l><l>And she to be coming and slandering me, the base little liar!</l><l>But the tongue is a fire as you know, my dear, the tongue is a fire.</l></lg><lg type="stanza"><l>"And the parson made it his text that week, and he said likewise,</l><l>That a lie which is half a truth is ever the blackest of lies.</l><l>That a lie which is all a lie may be met and fought with outright,</l><l>But a lie which is part a truth is a harder matter to fight."</l></lg></q></p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130772">"A lie which is all a lie," Mrs. Trafford repeated. "Ah! that is just the difficult part of our task, my dear. Still, never mind, the right must conquer in the end."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130773">Mrs. Farquhar gave a long sigh.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130774">"If only Charlie was at home I could afford to laugh at the story and the people who believe in it and keep it floating, alike; but then, Charlie is not at home, and some kind friend will certainly be kind enough to tell him what people are saying about me. I don't know what to do, Mrs. Trafford, nor which way to turn, and I believe I shall go out of my mind."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130775">"Your husband <hi rend="italic">couldn't</hi> believe such a tale!" cried Mrs. Trafford indignantly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130777">He might; one never knows how a lie may take effect—and the whole sound of the thing is so dead <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130776" n="114 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>against me, so dead against me. I am quite prepared for it—I am quite prepared for the worst. I shall not be the least surprised if matters come to the very worst."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130778">In truth, she was so thoroughly upset and unnerved at the superb audacity of the woman whom she had befriended and saved from perdition, that the fighting instinct, which belongs to all noble natures, had left her, and she was scarcely less helpless than a baby to resist the waves of evil, which had crept up to her innocent feet, and threatened to overwhelm her altogether.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130779">But Mrs. Trafford was a plucky little soul, and, like a bull-dog, would fight if need was as long as breath lasted; she would have none of this giving in and letting the wicked ride on triumphant.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130780">"Oh! my dear child, that is all rubbish and nonsense. It won't do to talk <hi rend="italic">or think</hi> in that silly way; it is foolish—foolish. The case simply stands thus—you <hi rend="italic">must</hi> clear yourself—there is no half-way house—you must do it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130781">"But how can I do it?" cried the other fretfully, "except by my word, and what is that worth?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130782">"You can, and you must do it. Tell me, to whom have you ever mentioned this midnight excursion?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130783">"I told Charlie, of course."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130784">"That is good. Then have you mentioned it to nobody else?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130786">"Only to my sister, as a secret. I told her in this very house—that afternoon, you know. But, <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130785" n="115 A BURDEN OF SORROW."/>stay—somebody else did know, for Captain Orford overheard part of my conversation with my sister, and I begged him not to say a word about it, as I wanted to hush the whole thing up as much as possible. Ah!" she ended bitterly, "did I not play into her hands nicely? Did I not shield her well from what she has thrown on to me?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130787">"For a time, yes. But you say Marcus knows. Well, we must take him into our counsel. We could not do better, for his judgment is remarkably good, and, somehow, he always suggests a wise course to be followed. In any case, I am sure that you had better come and stay here till the storm has blown over and subsided one way or the other. You can shut your house up and give your servants holiday."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130788">Mrs. Farquhar's eyes opened to their very fullest extent.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130789">"Do you mean it?" she cried. "Will you do that? Oh! bless you! God bless you! And God <hi rend="italic">will</hi> bless you," she ended solemnly, "He <hi rend="italic">will</hi> bless you."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130791">They say that prosperity hardens us and makes us arrogant and worldly, and that adversity and sorrow soften and refine our earthly natures. I don't know—I don't altogether agree with the theory. I have never known men and women whom great afflictions made kinder and more sympathetic. It is a beautiful idea, of course, but it has not been my lot to see it in practice; and I do know that a year before Mrs. Trafford would almost as soon have <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130790" n="116 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>thought of jumping off the tower of "the Parish," as of offering to take into her house a woman who was slandered by the evil tongue of scandal, and at whom was already pointed the finger of scorn.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130792">True, she might, in her heart and soul, have believed her to be as innocent as the driven snow is white, and yet she would, not unnaturally, have hesitated to endanger her position in society, by taking up arms in her behalf against a sea of troubles of such inky blackness and overwhelming strength.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130793">But now, it was all different! Secure by her niece's engagement to the future Lord Ceespring, she felt herself as far above society—as society goes in Blankhampton—as the heaven is above the earth, and so the natural tenderness of a really kind heart came to the surface and took its own way untrammelled by the base considerations of self-interest and self-advancement.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130794">Yet they say that prosperity hardens the human heart!</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130795">Ah!—"They say—what say they?—let 'em say"—<hi rend="italic">I</hi> don't believe it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130796">I grant you that <hi rend="italic">the memory</hi> of by-gone suffering, out of which we have passed into happier or more prosperous times, may, and often does, make us soft and sympathetic to the same suffering in others but <hi rend="italic">while</hi> we are in tribulation, are we softened and made tender thereby? I don't think so.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130798">How, when one is in worldly adversity, one looks <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130797" n="117 A BURDEN OF SORROW."/>out for slights and insults, aye, and finds them too, easily enough, though the giver of the slight or insult may never have meant it to be such for a moment. But <hi rend="italic">we</hi> see it and the meaning too, quickly. We don't wait to meet such troubles half way; oh, no! we run across the road to shake hands with them, and we welcome them and nurse them, we coddle them and make much of them, as we never troubled to do when a blessing came along in our direction.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130799">They call that sort of thing—Pride!</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130800">However, be that as it may, Mrs. Trafford chose to make the case of Mrs. Charles Farquhar hers, and having taken it up, she set to work with a will to clear up the mystery.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130801">"Come and take off your coat and hat, my dear," she said, with a pleasant little air of authority which was as balm to Mrs. Farquhar's stricken soul. "You shall have some tea and be made much of, and we will take Marcus into our counsel and see what he can suggest to help us. And after that, we will take a cab and fetch what things you will require to wear, and arrange what to do with your servants, and so on. Now, come with me."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130802">Mrs. Trafford was a little woman who had always had her admirers, but in all her life she had never been worshipped as Charles Farquhar's wife worshipped her at that moment.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130803">"Mrs. Trafford," she said, half-hesitatingly, "do you think you would mind calling me Georgie?"</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130804" n="118 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130805">"No, my poor Georgie, I am quite sure I should not," she answered kindly, and there were tears in her eyes as she said it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130806">Then she took her up to her own room and bathed her tear-stained face with rose water, waiting on her and tending her as if she had been a child.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130807">"There! you look quite like yourself again," she exclaimed, giving a last touch to her visitor's soft golden curls. "So come along, and we will enjoy our fresh tea and hot scones. I am sure all this excitement must have made you very faint and hungry. I wonder if you have had anything to eat to-day."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130808">"Not very much," answered poor Georgie with a forced smile.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130809">"Some people," said Mrs. Trafford, "would give you wine and make your head ache beyond endurance. <hi rend="italic">I</hi> shall dose you in my own way, and make you quite yourself again," and then she opened the door into the drawing-room and introduced her guest by merely saying that she had persuaded Mrs. Farquhar to take her hat and coat off, and would Julia give them some tea?</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130810">The tea was fresh and of the best, the buttered scones were hot and delicious, and before many minutes Mrs. Farquhar, poor soul, began to feel strengthened and comforted, and as if this brisk and capable little woman in whom she had put all her trust, would succeed after all in pulling her out of the trap into which her innocent feet had led her.</p>
        <pb n="119 A BURDEN OF SORROW." pages="119" facs="jwgarri119"/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130812">And presently Sir Anthony, who saw that something very serious was in the wind, said good-afternoon and departed, feeling that he was not wanted there just then. Mrs. Trafford slipped back into her old self as she laid her hand in his.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130813">"Good-bye, Sir Anthony. I want you to come and dine with us, quite in a friendly way, the day after to-morrow. Can you?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130814">"Oh! I shall be charmed—charmed," said Sir Anthony, whose looks did not belie his words in the least.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130815">"Half-past-seven; then we shall expect you. Good-bye," said the little widow blithely.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130816">She whispered to Laura to fetch Madge and Marcus if possible, going back herself to her guest at once. Presently, the three came in together, laughing and joking; and perhaps Orford looked a little surprised when he saw Mrs. Farquhar so thoroughly at home, but Mrs. Trafford, holding her hand fast all the time, told them the story as I have told it you already.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130817">"And now, my dear boy," she ended, "we await your advice."</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130818" n="[120]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_021" n="11" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER XI.<lb/>THE TALK OF TILE TOWN.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130819">"Slugs crawl and crawl over our cabbages, like the world's slander over a good name. You may kill them, it is true, but there is the slime."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—DOUGLAS JERROLD.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130820">ORFORD's advice was promptly given, and it was distinguished by plenty of sound common sense, although he deprecated the idea of his being of any real use in a case of such difficulty, and in the face of such exquisite audacity as Mrs. Hildersley had shown in deliberately shifting the weight of scandal off her own shoulder on to those of her friend.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130821">"I'm not a clever chap," he said regretfully, "and it seems to me in a delicate affair like this, you want a cool, far-seeing, calculating brain like Urquhart's to unravel such a business."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130822">"But, my dear Marcus, we have not got Colonel Urquhart at our service just now, and we have you," put in his aunt-by-marriage elect. "Tell us what you think?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130823">"Urquhart's your man, Mrs. Traff', I assure you," Orford persisted.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130824">"He might not care to be drawn into it," Mrs. Farquhar suggested timidly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130826">Urquhart is as good as gold, if you want help of any kind," Orford declared; "and he's such a 'cute, far-seeing beggar, that I should like to have his <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130825" n="121 THE TALK OF THE TOWN."/>advice on the matter. Do you mind my telling him about it, when I go back to barracks? You don't mind its being known?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130827">"I can't help it—it is known," Mrs. Farquhar cried.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130828">"And the sooner everybody knows that she has taken refuge with me from all the evil-speaking, lying, and slandering that goes on in this hot-bed of scandal and gossip, the better," supplemented Mrs. Trafford severely. "Still, let us hear what you think, Marcus."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130829">"Well, Mrs. Traff," said Orford, "I think that——" and here he bit the uncomplimentary term "she-devil" off the end of his tongue, "that Mrs. Hildersley ought to be ducked. But as that's impracticable, I think she ought to be hounded out of society altogether—and it won't be any fault of mine if she isn't. But that's an affair of the future—for the present, it seems to me the first thing to do is to prevent her getting at Farquhar."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130830">"Getting at Charlie!" exclaimed Charlie's wife in dismay. "How can she do that?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130831">"I don't mean at him personally, but she is safe to take steps to make sure that this precious story of hers shall reach his ears."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130832">Mrs. Farquhar's pale face flushed scarlet.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130833">"Oh, do you think she will dare go so far as that?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130834">Orford could not help smiling.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130836">"Desperation will dare anything," he said. <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130835" n="122 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>"And the first thing to do is to prevent her brewing mischief with him—if it's not too late already."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130837">"I will go out to Charlie. I'll start to-morrow," the unhappy woman cried. "I'll go to him at once."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130838">"You must do nothing of the kind," returned Orford sharply. "What you have to do is to get to the very bottom of this business and force the truth out of that woman. By running away—whether you go to your husband or not—you will give colour to the story, and then <hi rend="italic">every</hi> one is bound to believe it. No, believe me, Mrs. Farquhar, your <hi rend="italic">only</hi> course is to stop here and fight the thing out, inch by inch if need be. And, to begin with, I should telegraph to Farquhar at once, now."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130839">"Yes? And you would say—?" eagerly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130840">"I should say that you are staying with Mrs. Trafford, and that he is to open no English letters until he receives one from you. You must write to-night."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130841">Mrs. Farquhar looked down at her shaking fingers in a doubt that was unmistakable.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130842">"She cannot, poor darling," cried Mrs. Trafford, with sudden and fresh pity. "She is too thoroughly upset by this vile slander to write a line to anybody."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130843">"Then will you write for her?" Orford asked. "Or would you like me to do it?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130845">"I wish you would," cried Mrs. Trafford eagerly. "I will write a short letter of course, but I do not <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130844" n="123 THE TALK OF THE TOWN."/>really think I could sit down and put all the story on paper. And what about the telegram?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130846">"That ought to go at once. I'll go out and send it now if you like, and then will write the letter between that and dinner-time."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130847">"You are very good," faltered Mrs. Trafford's guest. "I don't know why you should take so much trouble for me, Captain Orford."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130848">"Because I have a very great respect for you, Mrs. Farquhar. And because I should be sorry for your husband to be in trouble whilst he is over in that loathsome country, which has already cost the English people more happiness than they can afford to lose. And—and I confess I should like to see that brazen woman bested—I always detested her," he added with some hesitation, as if he was half-ashamed of cherishing such feelings towards a woman.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130849">"I quite agree with you," said Mrs. Trafford without any hesitation whatever—she had no nice feelings of chivalry to contend against, and would dearly like to have seen Mrs. Hildersley crushed and abject, down in the very dust of the earth.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130850">Eventually, this was the form of warning which went speeding by wire and cable into the land of the Pharoahs that night.</p>
        <q>
          <p xml:id="jwgarri_130851">"Marcus Orford, the Black Horse, Blankhampton, to Captain Charles Farquhar, the Blankshire Regiment, Alipah, Egypt.</p>
          <p xml:id="jwgarri_130853">"Your wife is staying with Mrs. Trafford, and will <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130852" n="124 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>remain there until she hears from you. Don't be uneasy about her, whatever you may have heard. Open no English letters until you get one from me posted this evening, which will explain this telegram fully. If you can get leave, return home as soon as possible. She is in good health."</p>
        </q>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130854">"Charlie will be frightened out of his senses," exclaimed Mrs. Farquhar, trembling like an aspen, poor unnerved thing.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130855">"Oh no, he'll guess pretty nearly what it means," replied Orford, soothingly. "And it's not long to wait for the explanation, while, if that treacherous cat has got at him, it will set his mind at rest, and start him working for leave."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130856">"I wonder if he will be able to get it," said Mrs. Trafford.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130858">"If he's got any sense he'll just go sick," Orford answered, "and after all the doctors are very good, they'll always stretch a point in a case of real need. I knew a fellow once," he went on, as he folded the paper on which the message for Farquhar was written, "whose wife got awfully ill from the climate in India. She'd had a lot of trouble out there, lost child after child, and at last her heart gave out, and the doctors declared there was nothing for it but coming home. Well, she refused to come home without her husband—said she'd rather die. Anyway, she wouldn't come without him, although her passage was taken and he did his best to persuade her. No, she said she'd <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130857" n="125 THE TALK OF THE TOWN."/>rather die; and as there seemed every chance of her dying if she didn't come home, the doctors said to him, 'Well, you'd better go sick too; you've been looking seedy for a good bit, so we'll sit on you and certify you sick,'—and so they did, and they came home together as happy as could be. She was a pretty soul," Orford ended; "I saw them the last time I was in Town."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130859">Before an hour passed Orford had sent the telegram and had almost completed the letter which would tell Charles Farquhar, in plain unvarnished terms, how his wife had become the victim through her own generous-hearted goodness of the venom of an unscrupulous and wicked woman.</p>
        <q>
          <text xml:id="jwgarri_1206">
            <body xml:id="jwgarri_1205"><p xml:id="jwgarri_130860">"She is naturally thoroughly upset by all this miserable business," he ended, "and as nervous as a cat; but personally you needn't worry about her, for Mrs. Trafford is the kindest of women and believes in her goodness and innocence implicitly. But pray do you, my dear Farquhar, work all you know for leave, that you may come home and help us to unmask this d—d traitress, for whom, in my humble opinion, hanging is too good and cleanly an end. Meantime, you may rely upon me to take your place and knock any fellow down. who presumes to say a word against your wife in my presence. I wish Graham would.</p> <closer><salute>Ever, my dear Farquhar, Your sincere friend,</salute><signed>"MARCUS ORFORD."</signed></closer></body>
          </text>
        </q>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130861" n="126 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130862">It was a characteristic letter, and represented Marcus Orford to the very life.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130863">And when it was gone, they all seemed to be at a standstill until there should come an answer to it. Colonel Urquhart was consulted through Orford and came down to St. Eve's and talked the matter over; but as Mrs. Hildersley obstinately stuck to her story, and as Graham gave corroborative evidence, nobody could move in the absence of Charles Farquhar or without instructions from him.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130864">Mrs. Hildersley and Graham had ceased to be friends entirely, in fact his fury at her listening to Mrs. Farquhar's persuasions had been so great, that he had cut her dead from that moment. So in keeping them apart, poor little Georgie, as they had all come to call her in St. Eve's, had raised up two deadly enemies against herself, enemies whose hatred would be deadly to their lives' end.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130865">For Mrs. Hildersley, in consenting to remember her children and forbear to take that step which would have been irrevocable, ending only in destruction, had had no intention of giving up <hi rend="italic">her friend</hi>, and the bitterness of seeing the man who had been openly at her feet for months past, pass her by without so much as a look, had made her furious against the woman who had brought it about.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130866">And on his part, Graham, who prided himself on being altogether irresistible, could not forgive the woman who, brave and plucky soul that she was, had wrested his prey from his grasp even at the eleventh hour.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130867" n="127 THE TALK OF THE TOWN."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130868">Not that he even made an effort to forgive the blow to his pride and vanity. Not he! On the contrary, he vowed a vow that he would leave no stone unturned to be what he called "even with her." No stone unturned! He had not far to look for a stone to turn, for there was that great ugly fact of her visit to his office, damaging enough to overwhelm any woman. And he turned that stone, aye, turned it and turned it again with the hand of a master, a master of wickedness—he moved it an inch here or an inch there so that it should lie just in the way, a big ugly stumbling block that nobody could get over or over-look—poor little Georgie least of all.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130869">Mrs. Trafford tried her best. She went straight at it with the energy of one who has the courage of her opinions; she explained it—she made it as clear as day-light, but in spite of her determined efforts, it remained to the world at large a stumbling-block that there was no getting over, or under, or round.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130871">Meantime, the story had spread from one end of Blankhampton to the other, and was literally raging in all classes of society. It was <hi rend="italic">the</hi> topic of the day. People even forgot that To-To Antrobus's wedding was drawing very near now, and the details thereof were simply a drug in the market. To-To might have changed her mind at that time and instead of fulfilling her engagement with the festive Herrick she might have married the Ding of Siam, with all the pomp and ceremony of the Cæsars and the Czars <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130870" n="128 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>combined, and, in the face of the mystery as to whether it was Mrs. Hildersley or Mrs. Farquhar who started to run away with Captain Graham on an eventful night a few weeks previously, nobody would have thought it a matter of much importance.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130872">As a matter of absolute fact, a good deal of the gilt was wearing off the ginger-bread of To-To's engagement, and, now that the wedding was drawing close at hand, it turned out to be none such a grand alliance after all. Rumours crept about that the festive Herrick was "a jealous, ill-tempered brute," and dark hints began to pass to and fro, that he had more than once done his very best to shuffle out of the affair altogether. Anyway, it is quite certain that a plated tea and coffee service was all that his immediate relations, combined, bestowed upon the bride as a wedding-gift, which, to the Antrobus family and their friends and acquaintances, served almost to clear the gingerbread of gilding entirely.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130873">As for Mrs. Hugh, she was eloquent about that plated service, and descanted upon the subject to folly in quite her own peculiar style.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130874">"I <hi rend="italic">never</hi> thought," she wound up, "that a child of <hi rend="italic">mine</hi> would marry a plated tea and coffee service! But these <hi rend="italic">new</hi> people are all show."</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130875" n="[129]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_022" n="12" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER XII.<lb/>WAITING.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130876">"O Woman! in ordinary cases so more a mortal, how, in the great and rare events of life, dolt thou swell into the angel!"</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—LORD LYTTON.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130877">MRS. HUGH ANTROBUS'S face was a study when she heard, as she did from Mr. Winks, that Mrs. Farquhar had taken refuge in the house of Mrs. Trafford.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130878">"My dear Lord Charterhouse," she gasped, "you really must be mistaken!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130879">But Mr. Winks shook his head.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130880">"No, Mrs. Antrobus," he maintained. "It's perfectly true—as true as gospel."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130881">"But I am sure Mrs. Traf-FORD would <hi rend="italic">never</hi> lend herself to such—such a—a—<hi rend="italic">person</hi>," she persisted.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130882">"She has done so, anyway. Stakes her friendship with everybody on the final issue," he replied. "Upon my word, I never heard such a hubbub as there is all over the garrison, and I do believe, if Graham doesn't clear out of it pretty soon, he'll be getting lynched or ducked, or something equally unpleasant."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130884">"And the majority <hi rend="italic">believe</hi> in Mrs. Farquhar?" cried. Mrs. Hugh, as if such a Delilah as poor little <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130883" n="130 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>Georgie had never polluted the sacred air of Blankhampton since she had first shed the somewhat greasy radiance of her extensive countenance upon the old city.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130885">"Believe in her?" repeated Mr. Winks with a chuckle. "Yes, that they do; and small wonder, for she's a nice little woman, and a good little woman too. I don't believe she'd touch Graham with a pair of tongs. Anyway, as soon as ever she heard what people were saying about her, she went off to Mrs. Trafford, and threw herself upon her protection."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130886">"What? <hi rend="italic">asked</hi> her to take her in?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130887">Oh, that I can't say for certain. But Mrs. Trafford <hi rend="italic">did</hi> take her in, and means to stick to her until Farquhar comes home. They've telegraphed for him."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130888">"<hi rend="italic">They?</hi> Who?" Mrs. Hugh asked, beginning to feel that she had backed the wrong horse in going for the other side.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130889">"Oh!—er—Orford did that, I believe."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130891">"What? Is <hi rend="italic">he</hi> mixed up in it?" How she wished she had never mentioned the miserable story to anyone. Unfortunately, in spite of her absorbing interest in the almost endless stream of self-glorifying prattle about the approaching marriage festivities, Mrs. Hugh had found time to mention the Graham-Hildersley-Farquhar scandal to almost every single person with whom she had lately come in, contact, and, with equally bad fortune, she had mentioned it in the tone of one who wished to be <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130890" n="131 WAITING."/>the champion of Mrs. Hildersley. "Is <hi rend="italic">he</hi> mixed up in it?" she asked hopelessly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130892">"Oh, rather! But only as pretty nearly half the fellows in the garrison are mixed up in it," Mr. Winks replied. "Orford and the Colonel are very keen about it too—in fact, Orford has announced everywhere that he means to knock any fellow down who presumes to say a single word against Mrs. Farquhar in his hearing. Consequently, for days past, the fellows in our regiment have been trying all they know how to get Graham to lunch or dinner, in the hope that Orford may have a chance of carrying his threat into effect."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130893">"Do you think he would? Captain Orford, I mean," Mrs. Hugh asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130894">"What? Knock him down? Why, yes, like a bird, to be sure, and enjoy it beyond everything," Mr. Winks cried, with a gay laugh. "But he won't, because he won't have the chance—Graham will take care of that, the little toad."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130895">Eventually, Mr. Winks, after giving Mrs. Hugh all the details of the affair that he knew, went away, leaving that good lady in an exceedingly perturbed state of mind. It was quite early in the afternoon, and Mr. Winks had found her alone, her brood being all away in different parts of the town.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130896">She went out into the hall as soon as he had gone, meeting Jane on her way from opening the door to let him out.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130897">"Jane, I—I am not at home," she said hurriedly. "I am going out presently."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130898" n="132 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130899">"Very well, 'm," said Jane.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130900">Thus set free from the chance of being disturbed, Mrs. Hugh went up into her bedroom to think what should be her next move? She had not the smallest idea of sticking to Mrs. Hildersley and proclaiming herself her champion, as Mrs. Trafford had done for Mrs. Farquhar; nor had she the smallest idea of losing Mrs. Trafford's friendship by letting the affair drop and minding her own business. Not she! On the contrary, she had every intention of shaking herself free of Mrs. Hildersley, and going in red-hot as the upholder and protector of outraged innocence, to whom she could offer a capacious and motherly wing, so as to ease the little woman in St. Eve's of her self-imposed labour of love.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130901">But she did not quite know how to set about it; as a matter of fact, to speak with uncompromising plainness, she hadn't quite enough "cheek" to go boldly forward and announce that she was Mrs. Farquhar's friend in the matter.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130902">However, she felt—and she was about right there—that it was no use sitting and staring at the terraces and the river; so she roused herself and tired her head, and made ready for the fray, putting on her best bonnet and her newest pair of gloves.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130903">And thus arrayed in all her glory, she waddled down to St. Eve's, and in an incredibly short time—considering that she travelled about seventeen stones—was standing at Mrs. Trafford's door awaiting admittance.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130904" n="133 WAITING."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130905">Yes, Mrs. Trafford was at home, Cox informed her. So she was taken upstairs and ushered into the drawing-room, where she found Mrs. Trafford—still busy with the crimson silken socks—alone.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130906">She rose, with an inward groan, as her visitor entered, and Mrs. Hugh explained herself.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130907">"How do you do, Mrs. Traf-FORD?" she enquired, with her most interested air. I hope you won't think me a nuisance to come so soon again?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130908">"Not at all—I am charmed, I am sure," returned Mrs. Trafford, with an affable, but at the same time distinctly condescending, manner.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130909">"When I finished lunch, I had as much intention of calling on <hi rend="italic">you</hi> to-day, as I had upon the MAN in the MOON," Mrs. Hugh went on with her gayest and most neighbourly little laugh.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130910">Mrs. Trafford bent her head and smiled a little, as a polite hostess would. Mrs. Hugh explained matters further.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130911">"But the fa—ct was, my girls had all gone out and I was quite alone, when Lord CHARTER-HOUSE came to see me, and—er—from him I heard—well—er—what, of course, must be the truth about this terrible scandal that is simply demoralising the town."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130912">Mrs. Trafford let the crimson sock and the bright steel knitting needles fall upon her knee.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130913">"You mean about Mrs. Farquhar?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130914">"Yes—er—is it true that she is with you?"</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130915" n="134 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130916">"Oh! yes, and will stop here until her husband comes home."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130917">"And will that be soon?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130918">"Very soon; he starts from Alexandria to-morrow."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130919">"Oh! really. Well, I needn't ask you if you believe in her, for of course, you must do so."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130920">Mrs. Hugh was beginning to get a little nervous now that she was getting near the chief point in her mission.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130921">"I do, implicitly," said Mrs. Trafford, apparently noticing nothing unusually flurried in her visitor's manner, and speaking very gravely. "She is as innocent as a baby—as a baby. I don't think a good, true woman was ever so cruelly wronged before."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130922">"Mrs. Hildersley came to me"—Mrs. Hugh began.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130923">"To you? When?" cried Mrs Trafford sharply.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130924">"It was some little time ago—and—really she made out such a sad story of Mrs. Farquhar's ingratitude, that I—I believed her. I assure you I never had a suspicion of the truth until Lord Charterhouse told me all about it this afternoon; and I felt I must come—I didn't wait for any of them to come home—I just put on my things and came at once. I felt I must. I couldn't rest until I had really learned the truth, and had made my peace with her, poor thing, for having doubted her."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130926">"It is very good of you, very sweet and motherly," exclaimed Mrs Trafford, and forthwith she dropped <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130925" n="135 WAITING."/>her little air of affable condescension and told Mrs. Hugh all about it. "Poor child, "she ended, "she is almost frantic at times to think that such a slander should have been fastened on her, and she has no idea of facing it out and living it down as a false woman would have. On the contrary, her only desire, until Captain Farquhar gets home, is to get out of sight, to creep out of the way. She was here when you knocked at the door; but she ran away as if you had been a policeman come to carry her off to prison."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130927">So the two fraternized and made friends over the affair, and, presently, Mrs. Trafford persuaded poor little Georgie to come down and see Mrs. Hugh and receive from her the assurance that she had one more friend in Blankhampton than she knew of.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130928">She was very simple in her manner to her, new champion and more cold than Mrs Hugh could have wished; but the good lady took no heed of that, for it was better for her to be on cool good terms, than on warm bad ones. But later, when Mrs. Hugh had departed, with a remark that her young people would all be impatiently awaiting her, she said to Mrs. Trafford that she had no idea Mrs. Antrobus and she were such intimate friends.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130930">"My dear," returned Mrs. Trafford, in a tone which implied that in ever having such an idea at any time she was acting most unreasonably, "Mrs. Antrobus is the <hi rend="italic">very last</hi> person in the world I should make a friend of; but it is well that everybody should know that you are here and exactly <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130929" n="136 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>how you are here, and she will spread the news thereof better than anybody else in the whole Town, excepting Colonel Coles, who is already on our side. Now, do you see?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130931">"Yes, perfectly," with a faint smile, then nestling her hand into that of her protector, "I'm so glad she's not a <hi rend="italic">friend</hi> of yours. I think she's such a horrid woman," she burst out. "There's something so—so artificial, so false about her, and she does glorify herself so awfully—and—and—I don't like her. I don't believe she's my friend at all. I've an instinctive feeling against her; perhaps it's wrong, but I can't bear her."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130932">"Neither can I," rejoined Mrs. Trafford promptly, she's so greasy and plausible. But she will help us in her way, I've no doubt."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130933">Oh! society, society, society! <hi rend="italic">What</hi> a game it is! Mrs. Hugh had gone home to the bosom of her family beaming and triumphant, because she had taken the bull by the horns and had come out of an exceedingly awkward and unpleasant situation with flying colours. She did not care the twentieth part of one poor scruple whether Mrs. Hildersley or Mrs. Farquhar, or both, had wanted to run away with Captain Graham—either or both might just sink or swim, which they could, for aught she cared. But she did care to be on terms of confidence and intimacy with "dear Mrs. Traf-FORD," and to encompass that most desirable end she would have gone in single-handed and fought the cause of either against the world.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130934" n="137 WAITING."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130935">And having succeeded so well, she went home beaming and triumphant. Well she might. But, oh! if she had but known that Mrs. Trafford was only making use of her to gain her own ends! If she had but known that Mrs. Trafford had no more intention of any ensuing intimacy with her, than she had of taking up Mrs. Hildersley's cause! If she had only known it—but, then, she didn't, and perhaps it was better that it was so.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130937">We should all be pretty well let down if we knew our neighbours' honest opinion of us—our relations generally take care that we do not remain in ignorance of theirs and it is most often a brutally honest one, a good deal more honest than we find palatable. But just try to imagine what our feelings would be like, if we suddenly discovered that Mrs. A. had asked us to her party, not because she wanted us, but because she couldn't make up her number without us; or that Mrs. B. had been civil because Mrs. C. had been civil, and she wasn't going to be "cut out" by her! We should feel very uncomfortable and unpleasant, and after all, it is much better that we should go on in our blissful ignorance, and go to our parties honestly believing we have been asked simply because Mrs. A., and Mrs. B., and Mrs. C. consider us pleasant, agreeable people, and for no other reason. So it was, doubtless, much better that Mrs. Traf-FOLD and Mrs. Hugh should each believe they had—to speak vulgarly—done the other in the social eye. Oh, yes, it was much <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130936" n="138 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>better, very much better. For Mrs. Hugh went to and fro in the land, and enlarged blandly on the shameful way in which Mrs. Farquhar, sweet little woman that she was, had been slandered, and even more emphatically on the scandalous way in which Mrs. Hildersley had tried to get her, Mrs. Hugh, that is, on her side; and by thus doing, she exactly fulfilled her mission. While as for Mrs. Trafford, in order to keep Mrs. Hugh faithful to the cause she went and called on her, paying quite a visitation and inspecting all To-To's presents, the tea-service included, which was put well away at the back of the table containing the presents, so that it was not easy to get a very close look at it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130938">And then she was introduced to the bridegroom-elect, the festive Herrick, who, unfortunately, did not quite understand—as he might have done from Mrs. Hugh's florid introduction—that she was quite so important a person as she was in Mrs. Hugh's eyes, and distinctly snubbed her, which, as Mrs. Trafford was exerting herself to be unusually civil, was rather a pity.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130939">"A most dreadful young man," remarked Mrs. Trafford that evening at dinner, to Orford's intense amusement. "He stood with his elbow on the mantel-shelf all the time, and pulled his moustache; and everything I said to him, he said: 'Er—yers—yers.' Really, I wonder Mrs. Antrobus can be so elated about the match."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130940">Marcus Orford fairly roared.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130941" n="139 WAITING."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130942">What did you say to that, Mrs. Traff?" he asked.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130943">"I turned my chair well round, so that I was not oblige to include him in my conversation; and then Lord Charterhouse was mentioned, and Mrs. Antrobus said in <hi rend="italic">her</hi> way: 'Oh! we are all <hi rend="italic">very</hi> fond of Lord Charterhouse,' upon which that dreadful young man said, in the most patronising tone imaginable: 'Er—yers—Cherterhouse is a very decent fell-ah!' and then he tugged at his moustache, and said: 'Er—yers,' again. I <hi rend="italic">looked</hi> at him," Mrs. Trafford wound up.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130944">Orford positively shook with laughter.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130945">"What a joke, and Mr. Winks will enjoy hearing it—he <hi rend="italic">loves</hi> him."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130946">So, on the whole, Mrs. Trafford's long visit to the River House was not so successful as Mrs. Hugh would have wished. Moreover, she was not much better impressed by the little bride, To-To.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130948">"Such a mass of affectation," Mrs. Trafford informed her delighted audience; "she mouthed and minced, as if she had a scalding potato in her mouth,"—it was, by-the-bye, surprising that the little lady should invariably be so frightfully down on "side" of that kind—"and she twisted her scraggy little body this way and that, until she looked like a little worm wriggling about as much as anything else. Mrs. Antrobus was really eloquent about the two. 'Herrick is so ex—tray—agantly fond of her,' she said—when he at last followed her into the hall, and I was pleased when he did; I was so afraid he <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130947" n="140 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>would take root beside the mantel-shelf—I he calls her his bit of "Dresden china fair," and really it seems as if he can-NOT lavish enough admiration upon her. He is going to bring <hi rend="italic">real</hi> orange-blossoms for the wedding, <hi rend="italic">real</hi> flowers; he declares she will look more exquisitely lovely under such a wreath than any bride that ever went to the altar. And I think she will look well,' Mrs. Antrobus added, with an air of humility and modesty which was quite touching—quite touching."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130949">"What did you say to that, Mrs. Traff?" enquired Orford.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130950">"I said I had no doubt that Miss To-To would look extremely well," returned Mrs. Trafford drily. "Mrs. Antrobus went on to tell me that Mr. Brentham is not only excessively proud of his little betrothed's lovely face, but also of her figure—<hi rend="italic">her figure</hi>," repeated Mrs. Trafford, in fine contempt. "It seems little To-To was very anxious that he should buy her a sealskin coat as one of his wedding gifts to her; but Herrick wouldn't hear of it, said he wasn't going to have her beautiful little graceful figure bundled up in a great fur coat only fit for an old woman. I said, 'Oh, well, he must give her dark sables—<hi rend="italic">all</hi> kinds and all ages of figure look well in dark sables.'"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130951">"'But Herrick does not like furs of <hi rend="italic">any</hi> description,' rejoined Mrs. Antrobus, as if that was the most distinguished taste in the wide world.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130953">"I suppose the truth is," Mrs. Trafford wound up, "he finds them too expensive to like—but then <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130952" n="141 WAITING."/>they might just as well say so honestly, without pretending that he has the income of a prince; it's so silly,—just as some people pretend that first-class carriages are stuffy, and that that's the reason they don't use them."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130954">"Poor Mrs. Antrobus—and poor little bride," cried Orford.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130955">"Poor little bride," echoed Madge, thinking of the difference between To-To's groom and her's.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130956">"By-the-bye, Mrs. Traff," Orford exclaimed. "I had a letter from my Mother to-day."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130957">"Yes, and how is your Father?" Mrs. Trafford enquired with interest, for the long-promised visit of Lord and Lady Ceespring to Blankhampton, that they might make the acquaintance of Madge and her family before asking her to visit her future home, had been postponed again and again owing to an obstinate attack of gout, which had fluctuated from bad to worse and from worse to a state bordering on convalescence, time after time, only to break out again with renewed violence.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130958">"The gout seems to have gone at last, and they propose coming abort the middle of next week, if that will suit you."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130959">"Oh, perfectly—perfectly," cried Mrs. Trafford, looking at Madge, who flushed and paled a little at the mere thought of such a dread ordeal.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130960">"In that case my orders are to secure rooms at the 'Golden Swan.' My Mother says my old Dad is pining to see Madge—talks about nothing else."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130962">"We must send out invitations at once for the <pb n="142 GARRISON GOSSIP." pages="142" facs="jwgarri142"/>people we want to ask to meet them," said Mrs. Trafford, thinking at once of ways and means of entertaining these distinguished guests, for her guests they would be practically, although they were not actually going to stay under her roof.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130963">"You must ask the little bride and the festive Merrick," laughed Orford. "By Jove, what an effect Mrs. Antrobus would have on my Lord."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130964">"Marcus," said Mrs. Trafford, in the tone of one who suddenly remembers some particular bit of news. "Mrs. Antrobus hadn't the least idea, until I told her, that Lord Charterhouse is going to be married."</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130965" n="[143]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_023" n="13" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER XIII.<lb/>A THUNDERBOLT.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_130966">"At every step in life we meet with young men from whom we anticipate wonderful things, but of whom, after careful inquiry, we never hear another word."</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—NATHANIEL HAWTHORNE.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130967">"SHE had no idea," said Mrs. Trafford, "that Lord Charterhouse was going to be married!"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130968">For a full minute Marcus Orford stared at his aunt-by-marriage-elect, as if she had suddenly informed him that she had, with her own eyes, seen the gracious Liege Lady of these dominions standing on her head in the middle of the Winter Garden, or something of an equally preposterous nature.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130969">"Mrs. Traff," said he solemnly, "you never told Mrs. Antrobus about Mr. Winks' engagement to Lady Nell Temple?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130970">"I did, indeed," returned Mrs. Trafford, looking up innocently. "Why should I not? It is common property; in fact, I thought she knew all about it."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130971">Marcus Orford's stare of astonishment relaxed into the broadest of smiles.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130973">"My dear Mrs. Traff," he cried, with a gay laugh, Mrs. Antrobus didn't know a word until you told her, not a word. Why, Mr. Winks,—although he went and got engaged, as a sort of protection against the charms of the fair Polly and the wiles of her <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130972" n="144 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>astute mamma,—has never had pluck enough to go and tell them what he has been and gone and done; at least, he had pluck enough to go, but, poor little chap, he hadn't pluck enough enough to tell them when he got there; and as for all us, why"—laughing yet more—" it has been the object and business of our lives to keep it from her."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130974">"Pray, was that why you never told us a word about it?" demanded Madge.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130975">Orford nodded.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130976">"Yes. By-the-bye, how did you come to hear?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130977">"My dear boy," cried Mrs. Trafford, "with Colonel Coles in the Town, need you ask?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130978">"No, I suppose not. But I put him up to it as soon as I remembered his proclivity for doing 'Town-crier.' I suppose he had already told you, though the old sinner swore he didn't happen to have breathed it to a soul."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130979">"I wonder what Mrs. Antrobus will do now?" put in Madge. "Lord Charterhouse has really been so dreadfully intimate with the River House."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130980">"Cut him, I should think," suggested Laura.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130982">"Not she," cried Mrs. Trafford. "If Lord Charter-house has not said a word about it, she will lay the flattering unction to her soul that he has been drawn into his engagement with Lady Nell, and that his inclinations lit, with the fair Polly. That being so, she will argue in her most creamy tones that marriage is a <hi rend="italic">very serious</hi>matter, a knot tied for <hi rend="italic">life</hi>; that marriages are made in Leaven, and should never be entered into without real trust and <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130981" n="145 A THUNDERBOLT."/>love on either side. And so, she will help and encourage poor little Lord Charterhouse to escape from the meshes of the net which his fine, fashionable cousin has thrown around him for the sake only for his title and not at, all for himself, and to follow whither the dictates of his good and affectionate heart lead him,—that is, to make her the mother-in-law of Lord Charterhouse. I think that will be about Mrs. Antrobus's next move."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130983">"I wonder if she will manage it?" said Mrs. Farquhar, in a musing tone.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130984">"Likely enough," replied Mrs. Trafford with a lofty air which argued no great things for her opinion of Lord Charterhouse.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130985">"And if she does," struck in Orford, "I, for one, shall not grudge her the victory. I felt when Mr. Winks first let out that lie had been there and hadn't told them, that if the old lady got the better of him after all, why, she would thoroughly deserve the honour of being his mother-in-law; that he would equally deserve being taken in, and Lady Nell be equally lucky in getting rid of a sweetheart who hadn't moral courage enough to stick to her; and so I did everything I could to give Mrs. Antrobus a fair field and no favour."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130986">"I'm sorry I told her," said Mrs. Trafford, "which just shows you, my dear Marcus, how foolish it is to work entirely in the dark. If you had taken us into your confidence, I should not have upset your plans, as I did this afternoon."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130988">"Oh! it doesn't really matter," he answered, with <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130987" n="146 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>a gay and easy laugh. "By-the-bye, did I tell you I saw your friend, Mr. Vyvyan, in the High Street this afternoon?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130989">"Yes, you did."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130990">"He's been away, you know—came back this morning—been to Town to see his lawyer. I thought he looked awfully seedy."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130991">"Really? Ill?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130992">"Yes, seemed to have a heavy cold upon him; voice hoarse, eyes heavy; complained of sore throat, said he had never felt worse in his life, that he could remember. 'Pon my word, I quite pitied the poor d—er—that is, the poor chap."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130993">"Really, I am sorry to hear it. It's to be hoped he won't have an illness—it must be so wretched to be ill at an hotel," said Mrs. Trafford.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130994">Oh! wretched," cried Georgie.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130995">"Can't imagine anything worse," from Julia.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130996">"Except being ill in barracks," put in Laura, who hadn't seen Staunton for days and imagined he must be ill, though she did not like to put the question to Orford outright.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130998">"Oh, there you're quite out of it," Orford declared; "a fellow who goes sick in barracks gets as decent a time as most men, for all the other fellows come and sit with him, and the doctor looks in three or four times a day, and altogether he does very fairly. I remember, though, being sick once when it was an awful nuisance. I had entered a horse to run in a steeple chase open to the army, and of course, wanted to ride him. Well, I had to train no end <pb xml:id="jwgarri_130997" n="147 A THUNDERBOLT."/>to get my weight down and somehow or other—perhaps the Turkish baths had been too much for me—I got a fearful cold on the top of the training. Three days before the race I had to send for the doctor, who said I was going to have rheumatice fever or inflammation of the lungs, or something, and ordered me to stop in bed. 'I suppose I shall be all right by Thursday, Devenish?' said I between my groans.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_130999">"'Oh, no, you won't,' said he, 'you've carried your training too far this time, and in bed you'll have to stop for the next fortnight—the next three months if you run any risk.'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301000">"'But I must go to the races,' I said blankly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301001">"'You'll do nothing of the kind,' he said positively, 'you'll stay where you are and be rolled in linseed poultices.'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301002">"'But hang it all, Devenish,'—I began, by way of remonstrance; but he was a peppery old person was Devenish, and cut me as short as you please.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301003">"'Just listen to me,' he said, 'you're going to no races this side of April—it was the 1st of March, that day—so don't try to argue the matter out with me, youngster, for I won't have it. By George,' he wound up, getting into a regular fume at my presuming to contradict his fiat even in desire, I if you say another word I'll send for a stretcher and have you carried over to the hospital, and stick a double guard over you, and I wonder how you'd like that?' he ended, positively chuckling over the idea of having me in his own pet particular prison.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301004" n="148 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301005">"Well, I shouldn't have liked it at all, so I said, 'Very well, Devenish, I didn't know I was so bad as that,' and quietly, accepted the situation.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301006">"'Didn't know you were so bad!' he gobbled out, why, bless me, lad, don't you <hi rend="italic">feel</hi> bad?'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301007">"Of course I had to admit that I <hi rend="italic">did</hi> feel bad, and so I did, no mistake about it; but all the same I didn't, any the more on that account, want to give up seeing my horse run for the biggest thing of that year; though how to bring the old duffer to hear reason, I did'nt know.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301008">"Well, a couple of days went by, and instead of getting better, I got worse. Heavens! how I suffered those two days."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301009">He stopped in his story for a moment, for at this point he caught the tender gaze of his sweet-heart's beautiful sympathetic eyes, and knew that her gentle heart was aching now for the pain he had borne five years ago; so of course he was obliged to pause and send an answering glance at her, to show he recognised and appreciated to the full her tenderness and care for him.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301010">"So you had to give up your race?" said Laura, who was growing more interested than she usually T ad been in desultory conversations since she and Sir Anthony had slipped apart.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301011">"Oh! no, I didn't. I fully meant to go, but didn't see how to manage it. However, the afternoon before, the race came off, Staunton, who had the next room to mine, came in on his way to some tea-fight or other."</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301012" n="149 A THUNDERBOLT."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301013">"'Do anything for you, old chap?' said he, and, as you may imagine, I just jumped at the chance his help could give me."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301014">"Yes?" Laura was beginning to get intensely interested in the story now, and leaned forward the better to catch his words.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301015">"'Do anything, old chap?' said I, G why I should think you rather can. Look here, it's out of the question my riding Lovelace tomorrow, for old Devenish won't let me out of this; but, all the same, I don't see why I shouldn't go on the quiet, just to see the race, you know.'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301016">"'No, to be sure not—if it won't do you any harm, that is.'</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301017">"'Not a bit in the world,' said I, and I give you my word I was so horribly ill at that moment, I could scarcely get my breath for pain. But, though they say there's no fool like an <hi rend="italic">old</hi> fool, I think there's no fool on earth like a young one; and like the young idiot I was, I'd have gone to that race, if by hook or by crook I could get there, if my life itself paid the forfeit So I was only too glad to make use of Staunton, who's just the best-natured fellow in all the world, and will do anything for anybody. So I asked him if he would go to a parson I knew in the town—an uncommonly good chap—and tell him I wanted to go to the races next day, but couldn't because I couldn't get leave, and ask him if he'd lend me a clerical rig-out.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301019">"Of course Staunton promised and brought <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301018" n="150 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>the whole concern back in a Gladstone bag for me. And the next day I waited till the fellows had all gone, Staunton among them. Just at the last minute, whilst the break was waiting in front of the mess, old Devenish bustled in to see me.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301020">"'Now, Orford,' said he, 'just for a last look at you before we're off. H'm—poultices on? Er—all right. If the pain continues,' he said to my servant, 'you'd better add a good spoonful of mustard to the linseed-meal, and be sure Mr. Orford doesn't get the least chill or be left a moment uncovered when you change the poultices. And keep up your spirit, Orford,' said he to me, 'and don't think anything more about the races; we'll tell you all about it when we come back,' and then off the old sinner bustled again, thinking he had condemned me to solitary confinement until he came back again.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301022">"However, we just waited until the break was clear of the gates, and then I jumped out of bed—pulled off my poultices—dressed myself in my parson's rig-out, with a great fair beard and a fair, longish, curly wig—both of which I happened to have by me—and put a <hi rend="italic">pince-nez</hi> on my nose. I give you my word of honour, not one of you would have known me. I looked in the glass and didn't know myself. My man had got a cab waiting for me, so off I went, got to the race-course just in time, saw the race and another—and then another after that. And then I bundled back and into bed <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301021" n="151 A THUNDERBOLT."/>just in time to let my fellow smother me in fresh poultices and fold the parson's rig-out up and get it stowed away in the bag again. And from that day to this," Orford ended, "not a soul but Staunton, and my man and the parson, were ever a bit the wiser; and old Devenish came back and told me all about the races, while I could have laughed in his face as he told me."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301023">"Did you win?" asked Laura.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301024">Orford shook his head.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301025">"Not I! No; the horse was good enough, but the man who rode him was an out-and-out duffer."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301026">"And did you take any harm?" asked Madge, as anxiously as if it had been yesterday.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301027">"Oh, didn't I!" Orford returned with a laugh, "I tell you there's no fool like a young fool. Ill! I was laid up for weeks, until they had to send for my mother and my lord. Ill! Oh! I was ill too, and my mother came and cried over me, and my lord hum'd and haw'd, and cleared his throat and said all sorts of naughty things I shouldn't like to repeat here, just by way of proving to the people round about me that he wasn't upset like my mother, or in a mortal funk that I was going to clear out and let the old name sink into oblivion. And Staunton used to come in and sit by me whenever he could, and look at me with such self-reproach in his eyes that I couldn't help laughing, though I was much too far gone to speak. Oh! yes, I paid dearly for my whistle that time, Heaven knows," he ended.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301028" n="[152]"/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301029">"Please, dear Marcus," said Madge, afterwards, when they had risen from the table and he had wandered after her into the boudoir, "Don't buy any more whistles at that price, will you?" and for answer Orford caught her in his arms and kissed her.</p>
      </div>
      <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301030" n="[153]"/>
      <div xml:id="jwgarri_024" n="14" type="chapter">
        <head>CHAPTER XIV.<lb/>ORANGE BLOSSOMS.</head>
        <epigraph>
          <cit>
            <q>
              <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301031">"Snobs in high places assume great airs, and are pretentious in all they do; and the higher their elevation the more conspicuous is the incongruity of their position.</p>
            </q>
            <bibl>—SMILES.</bibl>
          </cit>
        </epigraph>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301032">HOW shall I attempt to describe Mrs. Hugh's feelings when Mrs. Trafford blandly informed her, not as a piece of news, not as anything astonishing, but simply in a tone which conveyed it as a fact known to all the world, that Lord Charterhouse was going to marry his cousin Lady Nell Temple?</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301033">Well, I admit it is not an easy task, and to anyone knowing Mrs. Hugh less thoroughly than I do, it would be an impossible one to achieve. But happily for the reader who is interested in Mrs. Hugh Antrobus and the fortunes of her family, I know the good lady well—know every line of face and form, and every gesture, every accent of her oily voice, every turn of her far-seeing and astute, but nevertheless, her at times mistaken soul.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301034">Let me then put her feelings in the simplest possible language.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301035">She was thunderstruck—<hi rend="italic">thunderstruck!</hi></p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301037">For a moment she grew faint and sick, her head reeled, her brain whirled, her soul grew weak and <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301036" n="154 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>heavy within her. Was this thing true? Was this the end for which she had worked? Was this the reward for which she had planned and plotted? Were all her hopes thus to be dashed to the ground? Was her pride—and oh! how she had prided herself on her belief that her beautiful favourite daughter would one day be Lady Charterhouse—thus to be brought down to the very dust? In truth, she was so astonished, so overwhelmed, that she quite forget to pretend that it was quite old news for her and that she had known all about it for a long, long time.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301038">"Really?" she stammered. "Are you quite sure?"</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301039">"Oh, quite sure," replied Mrs. Trafford, with her little important air of being behind the scenes.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301040">"It is a recent engagement?" persisted Mrs. Hugh.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301041">"Oh, yes. Quite recent."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301042">"Oh, really. I had no idea of it. How <hi rend="italic">odd</hi> that Lord Charterhouse did not tell us about it," with a little laugh, which, considering the state of her mind, really did her great credit.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301043">"Very odd," said Mrs. Trafford drily.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301044">"It does not look as if he was very proud of his engagement," Mrs. Hugh remarked in a slighting tone.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301045">"Not at all events proud to proclaim it," returned Mrs. Trafford. and then she rose and said she really must be going, she had made quite a visitation, and Mrs. Antrobus would think her quite a nuisance.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301046" n="155 ORANGE BLOSSOMS."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301047">So the two ladies took a really affectionate leave of one another, and parted on the most friendly terms imaginable, for Mrs. Trafford was indeed very sorry to feel she had dealt the other such a blow, as she could not help seeing her information was.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301048">And then Mrs. Hugh sat down to think—to think! What should she do? How should she break the news to her family? How should she tell Polly?</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301049">She knew, alas, too well, from long experience, what a difference the news would make to Polly, and in Polly's every-day life. For the prospect of her becoming, ere long, Lady Charterhouse, was all that kept the little bride-elect—whose airs and graces were already quite insufferable—in a mood to show Polly anything like sisterly kindness at all. Mrs. Hugh knew but too well that did she but once hear a whisper, a hint, of Lord Charterhouse's engagement, all peace, even during the few days which must elapse before that of the wedding, would be utterly at an end.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301050">She had been alone when Mrs. Trafford told her of it—for the "love-bird" had sidled out of the room, and Polly was not there either. Nobody came near for a long time and she still sat there alone, quite alone, thinking, plotting, planning what would be the best for her to do.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301052">And as she sat thus, the shades of evening crept closer and closer around her, the fire, from a fierce roaring mass of blazing coals, became a silent red heart, then collapsed with a feeble attempt at a crash and fill to the bottom of the grate a <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301051" n="156 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>smouldering heap of live cinders, lightened here and there by a struggling jet of flame.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301053">So long she sat—and then she rose up with a new idea and a new resolve in her heart.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301054"><hi rend="italic">She would not tell anybody a word about it</hi>. Which was exactly what Mrs. Trafford, an hour or two later, told Marcus Orford she would do.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301055">Why should she tell them? Lord Charterhouse, had carefully kept the fact a secret so far as they were concerned and, for anything she knew to the contrary, from everybody else. He was evidently not <hi rend="italic">proud</hi> of it, and she wondered if—if—if he were not particularly fond of his cousin? Perhaps it had been a family affair, arranged for him years ago by his relations! Perhaps—and indeed there was nothing at all unlikely about it—perhaps he did not care for his cousin at all, and meant to throw the engagement over if he succeeded in winning Polly.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301056">"I will not say a word about it," said she to herself, "not even to Hugh—least of all to Polly. Even if nothing else comes of it, it serves to keep To-To quiet; and really the child does give herself terrible airs, and is so very much inclined to crow over Polly, though she ought to remember that if Polly had taken advantage of <hi rend="italic">her</hi> first offer, she would have been poor Eliot Cardella's widow now. Ah! well, well, it was a great blessing nothing further ever came of that," and Mrs. Hugh gave a pious sigh of thankfulness for past mercies, which was really quite patronizing to the Providence which had ordered them.</p>
        <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301057" n="157 ORANGE BLOSSOMS."/>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301058">So Mrs. Hugh rose up and girded herself with her own blandness, so to speak, and went out to do battle against poor absent, unsuspecting Lady Nell, who did not know she had an enemy in all the wide world, least of all one she had never even heard of, who loved "dear old Charterhouse" with a life-long, wholesome, hearty love, wrote to him twice or even three times in a week, and thought it an awful shame the poor dear boy couldn't get more leave, little thinking that there was a fair Polly down at Blankhampton whose eyes had altogether prevented him from asking for it.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301059">Happily no other ill wind blew the news in the direction of the River House, and Mrs. Hugh kept bravely on her way, making pleasant little entertainments for Lord Charterhouse, for which the approaching wedding served as an excellent excuse.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301060">And Polly dreamed the days away, trailing her soft draperies to and fro over the polished floors—they had lovely floors all over the River House—and fancied she was "my lady," and safe in an atmosphere of rank and fashion for ever. Poor Polly! Poor Polly! So fair, so beautiful, with her yellow hair and her peach-bloom lovely skin, so gentle and good-tempered, even if a trifle aimless and spiritless.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301061">And Fate was stealing fast upon her, a fate that there was no resisting, because it was hers—so fast—so fast. Poor Polly! Poor Polly!</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301063">Little Mr. Winks, on his side, still found himself drawn towards the River House and went there <pb xml:id="jwgarri_1301062" n="158 GARRISON GOSSIP."/>more frequently than ever, and Marcus Orford, who, as were several other of his brother officers, was closely watching his movements, carried to Mrs. Trafford the news that certainly Mrs. Antrobus had done as she had predicted and had kept her information concerning Lord Charterhouse to herself.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301064">"I can't tell what the little chap is driving at," Orford ended.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301065">He repeated the same that evening to Staunton as they sat together over their last pipe before turning in, and he said it with such a puzzled air of utter perplexity that Staunton burst out laughing.</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301066">"It's easy enough to understand," he returned. "It's a jolly enough house, I've no doubt, and they make an awful lot of him, and after all, the girls are as pretty, if not prettier, than any other girls in the whole town. 'Pon my word, I can't see your difficulty in understanding the whole affair. The only difficulty I have in understanding him is to know why on earth he went and engaged himself to Lady Nell."</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301067">"Felt himself getting spoons on Polly and wanted to put himself under lock and key," suggested Orford,</p>
        <p xml:id="jwgarri_1301068">"More than likely. And he has alway