<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE TEI.2 SYSTEM "teixlite.dtd"><TEI.2>	<teiHeader>		<fileDesc>			<titleStmt>				<title>A MAYFAIR TRAGEDY</title>			</titleStmt>			<publicationStmt>				<p/>			</publicationStmt>			<sourceDesc>				<p/>			</sourceDesc>		</fileDesc>	</teiHeader>	<text>		<front>			<titlePage>				<docTitle>					<titlePart>A MAYFAIR TRAGEDY</titlePart>				</docTitle>				<byline/>				<byline/>				<docImprint>					<name/>					<name/>					<name/>					<date/>				</docImprint>			</titlePage>		</front>		<body>			<pb n="1"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER I<lb/>ONLY A SINGING-MASTER</head>				<epigraph>					<lg>						<l>"Si tu savais comme je t'aime,</l>						<l>Bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;tu m'aimerais!"</l>					</lg>				</epigraph>				<p>"SING that verse again, Mademoiselle! Sing it with more feeling&#x2014;more fire!"</p>				<p>She sings it again&#x2014;her voice is untutored, but charming in its flexibility and in its purity of tone. Still there is a curious lack of feeling in it. May be she has not much "soul," though later on&#x2014;like Undine&#x2014;"soul" may be born in her.</p>				<p>When she has finished the verse, she looks down at her master and accompanist, <pb n="2"/>and reads decided disappointment in his eyes.</p>				<p>What superb eyes he has&#x2014;she thinks&#x2014;large&#x2014;dark as midnight&#x2014;so velvetty soft!&#x2014;so full of liquid lustre as they meet her glance, that involuntarily her white lids droop until the loveliest, longest lashes imaginable kiss the faint pink flush which rises on her cheeks.</p>				<p>Marco Ferrari, Italian singing-master at a large and fashionable pensionnat at Brussels, experiences a sharp thrill of gratification as he notes that there is no pride or scorn in his pupil's face, only the sweet alluring softness and shyness that are in his opinion the chief attractions in a young girl. There are scores of lovely girls at Madame de Bernard's pensionnat, but this one to him is the flower of the flock. He has never, <pb n="3"/>to his thinking, looked on a more exquisite specimen of that exquisite age&#x2014;between girlhood and womanhood. Two immense grey eyes with darkness in their gleaming depths&#x2014;a little Greek nose&#x2014;a skin of snow&#x2014;a delicious rose-petal bloom&#x2014;a red mouth like a child's&#x2014;a glisten of small white teeth, and a careless tangle of bronze-flecked hair, make up a matchless whole. Looking at her, he quite understands how men have been fools enough to go blind and mad&#x2014;to lay down life and honour and even soul's salvation for a creature like this, and with the impulsive temperament of the South, Marco Ferrari is deeply enamoured of her. The fire in his breast has smouldered for two long months. It wants but opportunity now to burst into a blaze, but somehow the beauti-<pb n="4"/>ful but passionless face has evoked not only intense admiration, but also a reverence that he has never felt towards a woman before in his life of thirty-four years.</p>				<p>Passionately in love with her, it yet seems to him almost a crime to try and change the lovely innocence of that face into the face of a woman who has eaten of the tree of knowledge of good and evil. He knows so well that nothing&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">nothing</hi> can ever bring back that sweet look of purity and innocence when once the dawn of earthly passion has broken on the heart&#x2014;when once the voice of earthly passion has breathed words that a woman never forgets&#x2014;never while she lives.</p>				<p>If men would but remember how a woman's whole existence for good or evil is often based on the first&#x2014;very first love <pb n="5"/>awakened within her&#x2014;how entirely her first love is responsible for her future&#x2014;they would pause perhaps before&#x2014;to gratify a little vanity, a little passion&#x2014;they brushed away the bloom which no mortal hand can ever restore. Ferrari, like many foreigners, is of a romantic and chivalrous nature&#x2014;love to him is more of a poetic essence than a vulgar realism. He believes absolutely in the existence of a true, pure, disinterested love, for he knows he could love a woman "<hi rend="italic">du c&#x0153;ur</hi>," without a shadow of baser sentiment alloying his feelings. This girl, whom he has simply deified into an angel by right of her exquisite beauty, he is ready to adore&#x2014;to give up everything for&#x2014;to slave for&#x2014;and live for&#x2014;without once questioning whether she is the pure, innocent, truthful being which is the only <pb n="6"/>being he <hi rend="italic">could</hi> love. He adores her madly but reverently. He would not harm a hair of her head&#x2014;he would not tarnish her beauty by one desecrating touch&#x2014;he would not soil her exquisite lips by one passionate kiss&#x2014;unless he <hi rend="italic">knew</hi> that she loved him truly as he loved her&#x2014;and that he was the only man to whom she would belong for the space of her existence.</p>				<p>The girl scarcely merits his opinion of her. Innocent&#x2014;as the world takes the word&#x2014;she surely is, through the circumstances which have attended her since she opened her big grey eyes on this wicked world. She has up to now been exempt from any temptations of evil, but if liberty and temptation were allowed her it is doubtful she would go through the fire unscathed. Of course she knows she is <pb n="7"/>beautiful. It is a fact that has been dinned into her ears, beginning with the monthly nurse whose admiring expressions she did not understand, going on continually by a foolish mother, and ending with an enormous amount of masculine approbation, which in her riper years she <hi rend="italic">does</hi> understand, and she rejoices in the fulness and triumph of her beauty as thoroughly as any embryo coquette.</p>				<p>Has she not been kissed and caressed perpetually&#x2014;just for those big grey eyes and bronze-flecked hair&#x2014;ever since the period of bibs and tuckers, short frocks and pinafores? Has she not always seen ugly children snubbed and passed over, and the plum cake and sugared almonds handed over to her? And this will go on for ever, she thinks, as she looks in the <pb n="8"/>glass and smiles complacently. In the eternal fitness of things it has been ordained so&#x2014;other girls, ugly girls, dowdy girls may wade and work through life&#x2014;but she, like the lilies of the field, will neither toil nor spin. Dukes and princes will crop up in her path with the celerity of gourds in the night. Plum cake and sugared almonds will be hers always. They belong by right divine to pretty people with little Greek noses and rose-petal bloom.</p>				<p>Beside all these ideas of herself she has a deal of fine ladyism about her. She loves dainty garments and dainty food; silk stockings and <hi rend="italic">gris perle</hi> gloves, truffled larks and walnut cream are essential to her notions of pleasantness, and all her pocket-money&#x2014;small as is the hoard, for her people are as poor as the <pb n="9"/>traditional church rat&#x2014;is devoted to gratifying her fancies. She likes fine horses and carriages and the men who can afford to give them, but somehow, though she is nineteen, no one has touched whatever she may possess of heart&#x2014;until now.</p>				<p>And it is only a singing-master&#x2014;a man who has to work for his daily bread, whose position in Society is <hi rend="italic">nil</hi>, whose antecedents are unknown&#x2014;that has captivated her.</p>				<p>There is a momentary silence after she has resung her verse&#x2014;a silence in which two pairs of eyes look into one another. Ferrari and she are the only occupants of the long room&#x2014;so to say&#x2014;though there is an obese little person&#x2014;a sort of sheepdog of the establishment&#x2014;whose business <pb n="10"/>it is to keep guard over the innocent lambs, but who, having no harmonious proclivities, has fallen asleep in her chair near the door.</p>				<p>Ferrari glances at her, smiles and remembers that this is a golden opportunity which it would be madness to lose.</p>				<p>He longs with an intense longing to hear the charming lips say " I love you! " but yet he would not <hi rend="italic">really</hi> care for the sweet avowal, unless it was said<hi rend="italic">de c&#x0153;ur</hi>, and shyly. He longs to clasp the little white hands, but yet he would not care to do so, unless they crept into his grasp timidly, and tremulous at the contact, like young birds. He longs&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">longs</hi> for one touch of the perfect, child-like mouth, but he would not kiss it for the world unless he knew that he had won her, heart and soul, and <pb n="11"/>that no other man's image had fallen on her young life.</p>				<p>But as he looks at her keenly, steadily, a strong conviction comes to him that she is everything his fancy paints her&#x2014;that the great guerdon of an honest, pure love will be his, when the fair white arms go round his neck, and every throb of her being responds to the kiss of a first and everlasting passion.</p>				<p>"Listen, mademoiselle, I am going to sing this verse to you&#x2014;and you?&#x2014;will you try and catch the expression that the song requires?" he asks, with that unutterable softness that is especially Italian.</p>				<p>She bends her head in assent. Somehow she is tongue-tied under the spell of his glance and voice.</p>				<pb n="12"/>				<lg>					<l>"Veux-tu mon nom?&#x2014;il est &#x00E0; toi&#x2014;</l>					<l>Veux-tu mes biens?&#x2014;ils sont &#x00E0;&#x00E0; toi.</l>					<l>Avec bonheur je te les donne</l>					<l>Si ton regard brille et rayonne</l>					<l>Et se repose unpeu sur moi.</l>					<l>Si tu savais comme je t'aime,</l>					<l>Bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;bien s&#x00FB;r, tu m'aimerais!"</l>				</lg>				<p>He sings it divinely, in a perfect tenor, and the girl, listening with bated breath, afraid to lose one note of this most delicious voice, stands as motionless as a statue and as&#x2014;dumb.</p>				<p>He looks up into her beautiful face. Already it seems to have gained in expression. A rapturous feeling fills him as he realises that he has the power to thrill and move her inmost being.</p>				<p>An impulse almost uncontrollable seizes him to clasp her in his arms, that he may feel for one moment&#x2014;one divine moment&#x2014;her heart throbbing against his own, but <pb n="13"/>he crushes it down&#x2014;not for worlds would he offend the delicacy of his dainty love, or startle into life a passion, the slow and sweet dawn of which will bring him such ineffable bliss. He has flirted with many women&#x2014;the sparkling, ox-eyed, olive-skinned women of his country&#x2014;but the feeling he had for them was as water is to wine compared with the intense admiration and adoration he has for this fair English girl with the face of an angel.</p>				<p>Presently he sings again, lingering over each word with a tenderness and earnestness which are perfectly genuine:</p>				<lg>					<l>"Veux-tu mon c&#x0153;ur?&#x2014;il est &#x00B4; toi,</l>					<l>Car il faut bien que tu souviens</l>					<l>Je n'ai plus rien qui m'appartient</l>					<l>Depuis que j'ai connu ta loi!</l>					<l>O prends mon c&#x0153;ur&#x2014;il est &#x00E0; toi.</l>					<l>Si tu savais comme je t'aime,</l>					<l>Bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;bien s&#x00FB;r, tu m'aimerais!"</l>				</lg>				<pb n="14"/>				<p>His right hand wanders slowly upwards and falls gently on the little white fingers that rest on the piano. His palm is so hot, it seems to burn her, but she does not shake off his touch.</p>				<p>"Mademoiselle! you <hi rend="italic">know</hi> how I love you! And you?&#x2014;oh, tell me my love is returned a little&#x2014;even a little!" he whispers in excellent English, flavoured by the musical accent of Italy.</p>				<p>Her eyes meet his once more, and tell him eloquently enough that, young as she is, the capability of love is strong within her&#x2014;but only for an instant she reveals this, the next her white lids droop, but her hand still lies within his.</p>				<p>Standing close beside him, with the glamour of his handsome face over her, she forgets his station in life, and the insular <pb n="15"/>reserve of an Englishwoman; she forgets his profession as singing-master, his subordinate position in Society, and she only remembers that though men have flattered her and stared at her, no one has aroused in her the strange new feelings that this poor singing master has done.</p>				<p>She believes that she would gladly give up family&#x2014;everything&#x2014;all for love, and the world well lost&#x2014;and with this thought in her mind, she looks at him again with a softness which is not habitual to her glance, her heart beats fast, and, reluctant that he should recognise his conquest, she is turning away, when he throws an arm round her and draws her down until her face is almost level with his own.</p>				<q>"'Bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">bien s&#x00FB;r</hi>, tu m'aimerais!'"</q>				<pb n="16"/>				<p>he whispers passionately. "Mademoiselle, let me see you once&#x2014;just once&#x2014;where no eyes are by to mark how utterly&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">utterly</hi> I love you! Will you meet me? As Heaven is above us I will keep guard over every look and word that might make you repent coming. I love you! I love you!&#x2014;but that very love makes you a sacred thing in my eyes. My life&#x2014;my angel! Say&#x2014;will you meet me?"</p>				<p>"Where?" she whispers, carried away by the passion and pleading in his voice, but suddenly her conscience smites her, and she adds: " But, no!&#x2014;it is not possible&#x2014;I cannot go out by myself!"</p>				<p>"Yes, you can if your heart leads you! If it does not plead for me, then we will part to-day, but I <hi rend="italic">know</hi> you will come&#x2014;you will make some excuse and meet me in <pb n="17"/>the Parc this evening. I shall be there at nine&#x2014;oh, <hi rend="italic">mon ange</hi>&#x2014;I only want to hear you say just once that you like me a little! I only want to kiss your hand&#x2014;I only want to know if I can make you love me&#x2014;always&#x2014;always. Promise you will try to come!"</p>				<p>"Hush!" she says, glancing nervously towards the corner of the room where Mademoiselle Havard still sits on guard, but now with her pale eyes wide open.</p>				<p>Ferrari dashes into a lively Italian barcarolle, then stops suddenly, and rising from his seat looks at his watch.</p>				<p>"We must try this little song another day, I am afraid, mademoiselle," he says in a loud voice. "It is too late now. <hi rend="italic">Au revoir!</hi>" he adds presently.</p>				<p>"<hi rend="italic">Au revoir!</hi>" she murmurs, and he <pb n="18"/>knows that she will be at the trysting place at nine o'clock.</p>				<p>Perhaps men are inconsistent, like women, but anyway if his feelings were analysed, there would be a little regret discovered in them that she should come. It would certainly have enhanced his opinion of her extreme purity and innocence if she had refused to meet him. Yet he loves her so, that the thought of being alone with her, even for a few flying seconds, drives everything else out of his head, and sends him away in a whirl of bliss.</p>				<p>Directly the door closes on him, the girl drops on the music-stool and plays a pathetic little air, " La femme du marin," which has drawn tears from many eyes. She plays it dreamily&#x2014;softly <pb n="19"/>and absently&#x2014;with her thoughts leagues away.</p>				<p>She has not been brought up as strictly as most English girls are, but she is quite aware that it is totally wrong and against the <hi rend="italic">convenances</hi> that she should keep the tryst. Her proclivities may be fast, but assuredly she means no evil as she hesitates. A little love of excitement, a good deal of flattered vanity, leavened by admiration of the man's face, are the sole things that bias her, and, convincing herself that there can be no real harm in going out for a few moments, she hesitates no longer. The temptation is too strong for her, the temptation of meeting again two handsome adoring eyes, and listening to an <hi rend="italic">entrainante</hi> voice whispering love-words in her ear. But how is she to evade <pb n="20"/>being seen by somebody as she makes her escapade? The Pensionnat is a good one, the discipline almost severe, the supervision vigilant.</p>				<p>She goes on playing small snatches of melody, unconsciously falling into "Home, Sweet Home." The air suddenly startles her out of her dreamy mood. What would those at home think of her going out at nine o'clock of the evening to meet a foreigner, of whom she literally knows nothing save that he is superbly handsome and has the good taste to admire her? Only a poor singing-master too! She remembers that the bluest of blood runs in her own veins, that her mother is ambitious for her, that she is expected to marry wealth, if not rank; but after all she does not care very much about her people, <pb n="21"/>and puts this thought of them quickly aside.</p>				<p>"I have it! " she cries mentally. "Cis is so like me that Madame and the teachers will never know which of us is absent from prayers. They won't even notice, in that ill-lighted room."</p>				<p>Directly she has arrived at this conclusion she closes the piano with a careless thud, catches up her music, and humming " Si tu savais," passes the sentinel without a word, and runs upstairs.</p>				<p>Here, in the long passage that lies between the dormitories, she falls upon her cousinthe cousin who is so strangely like her, and yet as unlike her as Heaven is from earth.</p>				<p>"Cis," she whispers hurriedly, "tomorrow is Sunday. It is <hi rend="italic">f&#x00EA;te</hi> of the Sacr&#x00E9; <pb n="22"/>C&#x0153;ur at St. Gudule, and I haven't a thing fit to wear. I must have ribbons and gloves, and shall run out by and bye and get them."</p>				<p>The girl addressed as Cis opens her pair of great grey eyes in amazement.</p>				<p>"Going out this evening&#x2014;so late and alone! It will be quite dark. They will never permit you!"</p>				<p>"I don't mean to ask permission. Mind you go to <hi rend="italic">my</hi> seat for prayers. They'll fancy it's me, and you are such a little saint, they are sure to think you are some-where in the room."</p>				<p>She does not pause to look at her astounded auditor, but snatching up her little black cloak and hat that hang in the passage, she runs downstairs and into the long garden&#x2014;unperceived in the twilight.</p>				<pb n="23"/>				<p>Here she hides in a tiny summer-house covered with a Virginian creeper glorious in vivid autumnal tints, until she hears the church clock strike the quarter to nine. By this time the evening shadows trail down blackly over her as she walks quickly to her destination. She has been a year in the charming Belgian capital, and knows her way perfectly. The cool air comes and lifts the little bronze-flecked rings of hair on her forehead, and she thinks it delicious to be out with the purple-spangled canopy overhead, instead of being imprisoned within the glaring white walls of the Pensionnat.</p>				<p>Reaching the Parc, she sinks down on an out-of-the-way bench, in a tremor of excitement and delight. The very novelty of the situation, the sense of liberty, im-<pb n="24"/>part a charm to it. She is quite content to be here, and feels no impatience for the arrival of her lover. Her nature is too mercurial for any strong impression, and her spirit is so fearless and defiant, that anxiety lest her absence should be discovered has no place in her breast, to mar the pleasure she experiences in her escapade.</p>				<p>In a little while, however, there is a presence at her side, and the sound of a voice that has sung itself into what she fancies is her heart, falls on her ear.</p>				<p>Child almost as she is&#x2014;barely nineteen&#x2014;untutored in worldly ways, a novice in feminine guile, she yet turns her head from the moonlight, so that he may not see her face.</p>				<p>"Mademoiselle!" he says in a tone of <pb n="25"/>restrained feeling, and full of the respect he would show to a Grande Dame, instead of an indiscreet little schoolgirl who has stolen out to meet a man whom she knows nothing about.</p>				<p>The respect or rather reverence in his accents makes his voice seem formal, almost cold, and she experiences both vexation and mortification that, after all, he does not admire or appreciate her as much as she believed.</p>				<p>She looks up at him with reproach in her glance. Under the yellow moon's rays she is perfectly lovely, her figure, enveloped in the black cloak, looks less childish than in the close-fitting dress he has seen her in. Her face is as pure and white as carven pearl, and her large eyes have the innocence of a baby.</p>				<pb n="26"/>				<p>Ferrari, gazing at her&#x2014;loses his head.</p>				<p>He has come here resolved not to show her the passion in his heart till he has sifted her nature&#x2014;found her to be wholly without evil or guile, and a girl whom he can woo for the wife of an honest, high-principled man, whose ideas of women's goodness and purity are ultra severe. But Venus-Victrix as usual. Beauty, that snare of the Devil, melts his grand resolves into thin air in a trice. He has a cultivated brain, a strong mind, and a refined nature, but with the proximity of this half child, half woman, he is powerless to keep back the burning words that rush to his lips.</p>				<p>Grasping her two hands&#x2014;tiny hands, white as snow and soft as velvet&#x2014;he bends towards her.</p>				<pb n="27"/>				<p>"Do you care for me, my child?"</p>				<p>He asks it quickly, almost roughly, asks it as if suspense on the point hurt him horribly, and yet he feared to end it.</p>				<p>She does not answer for a minute. She knows now, however, that he <hi rend="italic">does</hi> care for her&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">does</hi> admire her as much as she could wish.</p>				<p>"It was very wrong of me to come," she says presently, in a very low voice, the voice of a child&#x2014;thinking&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">knowing</hi> it has done wrong, and repentant of it. And once more her eyes are lifted up to him deprecatingly, and with a charming shyness in their exquisite depths, " but I&#x2014;could not help coming!"</p>				<p>"I am satisfied," he cries, drawing a long breath. "You need not tell me that you love me, for your sweet eyes have answered <pb n="28"/>for you. Oh, <hi rend="italic">mon ange!</hi> my life! how good it is to be here together, and&#x2014;alone! It seems almost enough happiness for me. Is it so for you, dear child?"</p>				<p>No man has ever spoken to her in such delicious, liquid tones. They arouse feelings she has never felt before. She trembles from head to foot, and a thrill of pleasure goes through her heart, yet amid this new measure of bliss pulsates one sharp throb of pain. It may be a sort of prescience that women often have in the most perfect moment of their life. She dares not try to analyse it, for in a second it is gone&#x2014;but she may perchance remember it in after years.</p>				<p>"But no!" he whispers, throwing his arm round her, "delicious as it is to be here, it would be Heaven to be together <pb n="29"/>					<hi rend="italic">for ever!</hi> Oh, my love! My own! say to me that it shall be so!"</p>				<p>He waits for her answer&#x2014;with bated breath&#x2014;and in this minute the very voices of the night seem hushed as though in expectation of love-words from her perfect lips.</p>				<p>But she says nothing, though her gaze, free and unrestrained from very ignorance of evil, rests on his dark eyes and handsome face, with the open admiration that a savage might show. The colour surges over his cheek as he marks this, and the blood runs riot through his veins. He cannot realise it all&#x2014;he cannot believe that to him has come such unutterable happiness. A gift straight from Heaven to crown his life! Here she is&#x2014;a glorious bit of Nature's handiwork&#x2014;a young, pure <pb n="30"/>maiden, the beau ideal of womanhood he has always worshipped and elected to find, and win. Here she is, like a morsel of delicious tropical fruit, ripe and ready for his hands to pluck if he will&#x2014;a fair, sweet girl, to live for him, and him only, to the end of her days.</p>				<p>Yet he refrains from taking the kisses he longs for from her lovely mouth, close as it is to him, tempting him as it does; he is resolved not to taste those lips until he knows&#x2014;positively&#x2014;absolutely that those lips will be true; those kisses he culls&#x2014;sacred to him.</p>				<p>"Oh, my child," he cries passionately, letting his gaze dwell on her most ex-ceeding fairness until he feels that life will be nothing without her, "it is true that we have known each other but a short <pb n="31"/>time, but love cannot be measured by time! I hardly think that words are needed between us two; we know all surely, even these brief moments have taught us that; we know that we love one another, that we were made for one another by that Heaven who fixed our destiny the day we were born. Why then should we stand apart? Life is so short&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">so short</hi>. Each fleeting second is so precious, each day to be prized before it falls for ever into the gulf of eternity. Ever since I looked on your face, my angel, it has haunted me day and night. It has visited me in my dreams and lingered in my thoughts, till my brain has grown hot and I have felt that I should go mad with love of you&#x2014;with the longing for you. Your sweet eyes have gone with me wher-<pb n="32"/>ever I have gone. My child&#x2014;my dear one, I cannot live without you&#x2014;and you? I know you cannot live without me. Fate has decided so. My life!&#x2014;my love! You must be mine&#x2014;my very own, and I shall wait for that day with beating heart and longing arms, and I know that you <hi rend="italic">will</hi> come to me some day, and stay with me, and love me with a love that will know no death!"</p>				<p>He says it all earnestly, feverishly, with his face close to hers, his eyes looking down straight into hers, his hand on her shoulder.</p>				<p>"<hi rend="italic">Anima mi&#x00E0;</hi>&#x2014;one word&#x2014;one little word, just to say that I have not deceived myself, that I am not a vain fool, and believe you care when perhaps I am nothing more to you&#x2014;nothing more than <pb n="33"/>any other man who has gone mad for you! But no! I cannot believe that. I love you, sweetheart, with all my soul, but I reverence you, and I know that you are too pure, too good to have come here to-night unless you care for me&#x2014;unless your love for me overruled everything else."</p>				<p>"I love you!" she whispers, and she speaks the truth to a certain extent. He is the first man who has spoken to her like this&#x2014;in the softest, most seductive voice. He is the first man who seems to have gathered to himself all of her virgin heart, and awakened the first echoes of passionate feeling within her.</p>				<p>Her grey eyes grow as radiant as the moon overhead, and the smile of a pleased, contented child plays on her lips.</p>				<pb n="34"/>				<p>He clasps her in his arms now and holds her to him, while her beautiful face lies against his breast with an abandonment that is born of innocence.</p>				<p>"Swear to me, child, that you will be true to me! Swear that no other man shall hold you in his arms, or touch your sweet lips, or clasp your little hands. See, how the moon and the stars seem to smile on our love. How Heaven itself rejoices in the true union of two human hearts! In this sacred hour of our betrothal cast aside all reserve and shyness, and tell me the blessed, blessed truth, that you are mine, as I am yours&#x2014;for ever and ever."</p>				<p>"For ever and ever," she says in a very low voice, but he hears her, and, stooping, he kisses her white lids, her rose-flushed cheeks, and her little red mouth, and <pb n="35"/>as he does so a man emerges from the shadows hard by. Sauntering slowly along, involuntarily he pauses a moment, as his glance falls on the splendid, striking beauty of the girl, which the clear moonlight reveals in perfection. He looks at her so keenly and steadfastly that her face is impressed on his mind, then, suddenly realising the situation, he turns his gaze reluctantly and goes on his way with a frown on his brow.</p>				<p>"An assignation, of course," he says half aloud. "I never noticed the man, but of course it's some rascal of a foreigner who has got hold of an English girl, for she is English, I'll swear. No other country but old England ever produced that matchless face."</p>				<p>The girl notices the undisguised admir-<pb n="36"/>ation in his glance, and flushes with pleasure, and even with her impassioned lover at her side she falls to wondering who the tall, fair, patrician-looking stranger can be.</p>				<p>"A compatriot of yours," Ferrari remarks after a casual glance, as if in answer to her thoughts. He is jealous and angry that another man's gaze should have lingered on the beauty which he would hide away from all other eyes but his own.</p>				<p>"What barbarians Englishmen are! I daresay the man stared at you so hard, that he will surely know you again. Cara! I almost wish you were not beautiful; the thought that other men's eyes can feast on that beauty drives me mad!"</p>				<p>"What does it matter so long as I care to look on none but you?" she says with <pb n="37"/>delicious naivet&#x00E9;. "Have I not sworn to keep to you for ever and ever?"</p>				<p>"My angel! My beloved!" he answers passionately, kissing her again and again, and in the Heaven he has found, he believes thoroughly that he will reign supreme, "that no stranger will intermeddle with his joy."</p>			</div>			<pb n="38"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER II<lb/>THE HONOURABLE JOHN</head>				<epigraph>					<lg>						<l>"He is a fool who thinks by force or skill</l>						<l>To turn the current of a woman's will!"</l>					</lg>				</epigraph>				<p>ABOUT a mile and a half from the dull old cathedral town of Exeter, and down a long lane&#x2014;which is a real Devonshire lane&#x2014;flanked on either side by tall, luxuriant hedges, out of which perfumed heads of honeysuckle and long trails of pink and white wild roses hang out beneath the shade of great spreading oaks and elms, with a lovely copper beech here and there, lending an exquisite dash of vivid colour to the general greenness; a white gate now and again breaks the formality of the way, <pb n="39"/>giving glimpses of true Devonshire pasture, lavish almost to rankness and dotted with big, sleepy-eyed, meek-looking cows, whose tinkling bells sound pleasantly on the evening air and are, in fact, the sole enlivenment of the spot, save a band of nightingales that give out a roundelay in the dusk, while from distant farmsteads comes a shrill bark of dogs.</p>				<p>As you go further from the town, the lane narrows and its sylvan beauty is considerably marred by a dozen little cottages, shabby, and tenanted by the poorer class.</p>				<p>Past these and within a large meadow, enclosed by a high wooden fence, stands "Brambledene," a red, straggling building which has the appearance of being two small houses turned into one, with a lot of rakish irregular chimneys, and jutting <pb n="40"/>windows, and rooms bulging out without the smallest regard to architectural symmetry. But the Honourable John Delaval&#x2014;one of that sorely-to-be-pitied army of martyrs, yclept decayed gentry&#x2014;has fortunately grown philosophically indifferent to appearances in general, so long as he can keep the wolf from the door. He is the fourth son of a spendthrift earl, a scion of a long line of <hi rend="italic">rou&#x00E9;s</hi> and spendthrifts, whose title and position are their best possessions, and whose acres in the North are mortgaged to an inch.</p>				<p>By the time the Honourable John reached the age of thirty, he was completely out at elbows. Coats from Poole's were an impossibility, flowers for his buttonhole as far removed from his reach as the moon, cash was nowhere, credit a <pb n="41"/>thing of the past. He was too well known in London to be able to dodge the writs. He had tried all ways and means to arrive at a gentlemanly livelihood, and had signally failed.</p>				<p>Business men looked askance at an aristocratic clerk, and infinitely preferred one to the manner born; titled aspirants to honest work usually meet with discouragement and rebuff, and refinement is the last merit wanted in a paid individual.</p>				<p>Fairly educated&#x2014;better educated, in fact, than English aristocracy as a rule&#x2014;by nature intelligent, and with all the feelings and instincts of a gentleman, he could not dig, and to beg he was ashamed. All his fatherland offered him was genteel starvation, so with his pater's&#x2014;the old earl's&#x2014;blessing, backed up by a <pb n="42"/>cheque of two hundred pounds&#x2014;squeezed with some difficulty out of the family coffers&#x2014;he betook himself across the herring pond, where the patrician name of Delaval was a dead letter, and carried no greater weight in its sound than the common but better-known appellations of Brown, Jones and Robinson, and where he was free to go in for cheese, or dry goods, or anything else that presented itself as a means of daily bread.</p>				<p>But the Honourable John inherited the good looks of his ancestors, and was a fine fellow measuring six feet two inches in his socks, and he not only attracted a considerable amount of notice from the elegant Broadway belles, but got a stroke of fortune as well.</p>				<p>Within a couple of months after his <pb n="43"/>arrival at New York, his face and thoroughbred air fired the fancy of an ambitious young woman, the spoilt child and heiress of a remarkably well-to-do owner of a large oyster saloon in Union Square.</p>				<p>True, the "cash down" was not much to speak of, but the "expectations," when Providence deemed fit to remove old Washington Plumper from his piscatorial sphere, were wonderful, and to a poor man who could not be sure of enough to pay his next week's board and lodging the prospect of a comfortable future was too much. So the Honourable John sent caste to the four winds, and prejudice along with it, swallowed the bitter pill because it was so well wrapped up in prospective bank-notes, and was thankful.</p>				<pb n="44"/>				<p>But as the years rolled by, he began to question whether he had cause to be thankful.</p>				<p>Miss Victoria Plumper&#x2014;she was christened Victoria after Her Majesty of England&#x2014;was far from being a desirable person. In her maiden days she had had no especial recommendation, personally or mentally, but she had seemed to a certain extent harmless and insignificant. As she merged, however, into the Honourable Mrs. Delaval, all the bristly and uncomfortable side of her character came out; she developed the bumps of self-sufficiency, enormous veneration (for herself), and philo-progenitiveness. And as the old owner of the oyster is at the present time&#x2014;just twenty years after his daughter's marriage&#x2014;still hale and hearty, <pb n="45"/>and screwy&#x2014;his son-in-law's lines have not been cast in pleasant places.</p>				<p>The Honourable John is not a bad sort, however, and in spite of the godsend a few thousands would be to him, he bears the fact of Washington Plumper's vitality with exemplary patience. His wife is the one drop of gall and wormwood in his cup.</p>				<p>"There was given me a thorn in the flesh&#x2014;a messenger of Satan to buffet me," is his frequent but unspoken thought, for the North-countryman loves the pipe of peace, and holds his tongue to try and ensure it. His wife is beneath him in birth, inferior to him in mind and brain, unsympathetic in every feeling. She is "common," in fact, and makes his blue blood bubble and seethe, but he makes the best of his bargain and consoles himself for matri-<pb n="46"/>monial infelicity by a loving devotion to his childen. They consist of two girls of the ages of nineteen and sixteen. There were four other little olives, but they are buried in a promiscuous sort of fashion in the different places where the Honourable John and his family boarded and lodged before they finally took root in Devonshire.</p>				<p>The clock is at eight, and pater and mater are sitting in their little dingy parlour. There is not an attempt at comfort, far less at luxury, in the room, owing to the niggardly spirit of the mistress of the establishment. A hard sofa covered with horsehair, a few straight-backed, spindley chairs, a shelf piled with secondhand, well-worn books, greedily devoured by the head of the house, and a square deal table. These articles compose the <pb n="47"/>furniture, and fragments of bread, a pat of butter and a dish of flaccid-looking shrimps, denote that the evening meal is going on.</p>				<p>In the semi-darkness, the couple make a queer contrast, refuting the belief that husband and wife grow like one another after some years of matrimony. He, tall and straight as a poplar, with a fine, blond, Saxon face, clear-cut features, the mien of a grand seigneur, his linen unreproachable, his hands white as snow, his nails a picture. She, short, stout, Dutch-built, swarthy of skin, her eyes as black as sloes, as sharp as a terrier's, her rough crinkly hair pushed untidily away under a tawdry sham lace cap, her black alpaca gown frayed and greasy at the seams&#x2014;certainly not an <hi rend="italic">app&#x00E9;tisante</hi> woman by any <pb n="48"/>means, and a shrew as well, with an unruly member that wags thirteen to the dozen and lashes like a whip.</p>				<p>He, quiet, reflective, soft-voiced&#x2014;a fit specimen of English nobility. She, noisy, full of gesticulation, brusque in movement, and rejoicing in a Yankee twang that irritates the delicate tympanum of his ear, and is more to his distaste than her numerous other failings.</p>				<p>A man and a woman, like many another man and woman whom fortune's freaks have tied together, wide apart in spirit, hating one another's presence, but struggling on to the end with the halter round their necks, either out of deference to what the world considers matrimonial obligations or else from some sheer mercenary interest.</p>				<pb n="49"/>				<p>"I met Melville this morning," the Honourable John announces in his usually low, gentle voice. " He wants me to buy the two cows I liked so much the other day."</p>				<p>"I <hi rend="italic">hope</hi> you were not fool enough to increase your offer of twenty-five pounds for the two," she snaps viciously. "Though I think anyone can do you out of money, <hi rend="italic">except me</hi>."</p>				<p>The last words have an ominous, aggrieved tone, which he quietly ignores. He is so habituated to jeers and reproaches that they have begun to fall on deaf ears at last.</p>				<p>"No, I did not increase my offer, though I felt inclined to do so, poor chap; he is so awfully down on his luck, that I can't help being sorry for him. It is a cruel shame <pb n="50"/>he cannot take his proper stand in the world, just because his scamp of a father chose to run through every sou; I feel for him with all my heart. It's odd how class sympathises with class," he adds half to himself, and the man who belongs to a fine old family, but is only a small tenant farmer owning half-a-dozen cows&#x2014;sighs, sighs so audibly, that the woman sitting opposite to him leaves off crunching her shrimps and eyes him quite vindictively. The fact is that he has trodden on dangerous ground&#x2014;the huge piece that separates her from him&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">caste</hi>.</p>				<p>"'Class sympathises with class'&#x2014;well! that sounds elegant, but it's trash," she sneers. " It vexes me that you have always class on the brain! What is the good of being born a useless fine gentleman when <pb n="51"/>you haven't two pence to rub together? Now I hate such fiddle-faddle! Give <hi rend="italic">me</hi> the real aristocracy of the almighty dollar&#x2014;the big bloods that put down cash handsomely, and hold their heads above credit. Why don't Lord Melville turn his white hands&#x2014;j ust like a girl's, they are&#x2014;to some honest work instead of going about with a long face, and a rusty old velveteen jacket, trying to do people out of their money. I bet those cows you are after are not worth a sovereign apiece. You have never had a cattle ranche, like many of <hi rend="italic">my</hi> family. I don't believe you know the difference between a cow and a buffalo."</p>				<p>The Honourable John gazes at her open-eyed and open-mouthed. She is really getting too much&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">too much</hi>! <hi rend="italic">If</hi> there is a <pb n="52"/>thing he prides himself on, it is being a good judge of pedigree cattle. Wasn't he brought up among one of the finest herds of Jerseys in England?&#x2014;the herd that his father, the Earl of Cottesmere, spent thousands on, and which yet were accounted the biggest bargain by the best judges around.</p>				<p>"Those cows a fraud! Why, I never saw better ones. The Melvilles are a very old family&#x2014;one of the oldest in the United Kingdom, my dear Victoria, and people like these are genuine enough. It's the mushrooms that are doubtful. I would give fifty pounds a piece for the cows to-morrow if I had it. I know Melville wouldn't impose on anyone. <hi rend="italic">His</hi> sort never do."</p>				<p>"His sort is like yours, I suppose," she <pb n="53"/>says grimly. "Now I just hate his sort! A parcel of stuck-up people giving themselves as much airs and graces as if they were rich. That old mother of his treads one under foot as if one was a worm. I met her in the lane the other day, and she looked at me as if I was a tramp, although I had my new dress on, and that hat, you know, with the three fine ostrich plumes."</p>				<p>He bites his lip to hide a smile as he pictures her with her three ostrich plumes, then he looks away in distaste.</p>				<p>"Lady Melville is very proud and dignified, and no wonder. She is the daughter of one of our biggest dukes, and the widow of an earl. She has the bluest of blue blood running through her veins; everyone cannot boast of that, you know! <pb n="54"/>She is always charming to me, even when I meet her in my threadbare old coat minus buttons, and my old hat, which is not fit for a bull bait."</p>				<p>"She recognises 'class' perhaps, especially the pauper portion of it," she answers sharply. "To me, she is simply hateful, and I should love to crush her&#x2014;airs and all. If I had a fortune, do you know what I would do with it?"</p>				<p>"Haven't an idea&#x2014;buy fine clothes for Claire, or set up an oyster saloon in the Haymarket!"</p>				<p>She glares at him like a wild cat&#x2014;of course he is hitting at her paternal proclivities.</p>				<p>"Oyster saloon, indeed! Well, one could do more silly things than set up an oyster saloon. If it hadn't been for an <pb n="55"/>oyster saloon you would have been starving by this time, or have drowned yourself&#x2014;but gratitude is not in the heart of man!"</p>				<p>He is of a proud and sensitive nature&#x2014;the ill-bred speech hits him hard. It is partially true what she says, however, though he would have respected the delicacy that kept her from the subject.</p>				<p>"I am not guilty of the sin of ingratitude&#x2014;that is peculiar to the mob," he replies in a quiet, dignified tone, "but even if I <hi rend="italic">were</hi> inclined to forget about your money, you would take care to nudge my memory on the subject!&#x2014;but let that pass. When a couple of oxen are yoked together it galls them to pull different ways, my dear Victoria. Now may I know what you would do if you had a fortune?"</p>				<p>"What I should do? I guess I'd buy the <pb n="56"/>roof over that old Lady Melville's head," she flashes. "I should like to live at High Towers better than any place I have seen."</p>				<p>He does not answer her, but sits gazing dreamily out of the window, balancing a bit of buttered crust on his fork.</p>				<p>"Have some shrimps&#x2014;they're wonderfully good and meaty, and get on with your supper, for it's growing late."</p>				<p>"Thanks&#x2014;I dislike shell-fish," he answers absently, "they don't agree with me."</p>				<p>"Now that's another fling at Washington Plumper's oysters," she exclaims in a loud, rasping voice that brings him back at once from dreamland.</p>				<p>"I was not thinking of&#x2014;of&#x2014;oysters," he murmurs mildly, "I was thinking of High <pb n="57"/>Towers. It <hi rend="italic">is</hi> a grand old place, but I don't fancy it would suit you. There is nothing modern or bric-&#x00E0;-brac about it, you know! Now <hi rend="italic">I</hi> would as soon live on at Brambledene if I had enough money to give Claire and Bell a fair start in life. Brambledene doesn't offer much social aggrandisement for them, poor little souls, I am afraid. I could die as happy as a prince if I knew the girls were properly provided for&#x2014;and little Cis as well!"</p>				<p>"Cis, indeed! that's another of your follies. You were not content with the mouths Providence gave you to feed, but you must go and add another one. Just like men! you are either miserly or wickedly improvident; there's no happy medium in your sex. What earthly right had you to saddle yourself with the keep <pb n="58"/>of that child when you couldn't do justice to your own offspring, I should like to know?" she asks in an aggrieved tone and with an aggressive look.</p>				<p>"Could I help it? Could I refuse my brother's dying request? The child's aristocratic relations on her mother's side&#x2014;Lord and Lady Lyonsdale&#x2014;would have nothing to say to her, because her father, poor old Ned, was a gentlemanly pauper like myself. However, Cis, poor mite, is as quiet as a mouse and harmless enough."</p>				<p>"But an expense&#x2014;always an expense! She has to be clothed and fed, and then she costs double with her finishing school."</p>				<p>"Simply because you would not let Claire go to Brussels by herself, and you knew that Cis, young as she is, is steady enough for a duenna, and you were quite <pb n="59"/>right. Claire is by far too handsome a girl to gad about alone. If I had my wish I should keep her always under our eyes. I shall never have a moment's peace when she comes out at the Opera. She hasn't backbone enough to stand flattery&#x2014;admiration will turn her head, and she'll never keep straight."</p>				<p>He adores his children and covertly dashes the back of his hand against his moist eyes as visions of Town men, <hi rend="italic">alias</hi> ravening wolves, rise before him, prepared to devour his pretty lamb.</p>				<p>"Claire will make a grand success on the stage and set fine Society ablaze. Gus Harris never did a better thing for himself than when he promised to bring my girl out at Covent Garden," she answers in a hard, decided voice, her <pb n="60"/>dusky cheeks all aglow with maternal complacency. Her eldest daughter is the one creature on which she showers any amiable feeling she happens to possess, and in return Claire rules her with a rod of iron. "I never saw anyone so beautiful as Claire in my life."</p>				<p>"Except Cis," the Honourable John puts in quietly. "Cis and Claire are as like as two peas, except that Cis puts one in mind of moonlight&#x2014;soft, tender&#x2014;and Claire of sunshine."</p>				<p>"Give me the blaze of sunshine! Cis cannot hold a candle to my girl. Claire is a Queen of Beauty. She is downright elegant! What would she be if she were set off by rich silks and satins and plenty of diamonds and emeralds, when she is just lovely in her old cottons that cost four-<pb n="61"/>pence-halfpenny a yard, or that horrid old green merino that has been turned twice? My poor, dear, ill-treated girl, she ought to be the Empress of Eussia instead of a pauper going to sing for a livelihood. My blood boils to think of the few advantages she has."</p>				<p>"'Beauty unadorned'&#x2014;you know the rest, my dear Victoria. Claire's face is her fortune, and no one looking at her will notice the fourpenny-halfpenny cottons or the objectionable green merino. Her hair is a glory in itself. Titian would gladly have given some years of his life to paint it!"</p>				<p>"Who cares about that stupid old Titian, whoever he may be&#x2014;some old fogey pal of yours, I suppose," she snaps scornfully. "<hi rend="italic">I</hi> want a prince of the royal <pb n="62"/>blood or a big lord to admire Claire and her hair."</p>				<p>"You wouldn't mind the Earl of Melville, though he tries to do us about cows."</p>				<p>"Even the Earl of Melville, provided he could keep Claire like a grand lady. He has a fine-sounding name anyhow, and I should like my girl to have a right to go to Buckingham Palace and kiss the Queen's hand, and to go to Marlborough House and the British Museum and the Alhambra and all the other places where the English bloods go, and to buy her frocks in Regent Street instead of having to haggle about a few shillings with that cheating Miss Simpson in Exeter."</p>				<p>"And you would like to be mother-in-law to a real live swell, and to crush the <pb n="63"/>old nobility under your feet! Well!&#x2014;well! who knows what may be in the womb of Time?"</p>				<p>Her eyes twinkle at the thought, then her face darkens.</p>				<p>"I don't believe the Boss is thinking of dying yet," the affectionate daughter mutters impatiently.</p>				<p>"Don't say ' Boss,' my dear Victoria; leave that to the waiters in Union Square."</p>				<p>"Well, I'll say father next time if you prefer it, but Washington Plumper wouldn't understand it. We all called him ' Boss,' and he liked it; you see, there is quite a ring of dignity about the word."</p>				<p>"Is there, indeed? Of course it is quite an Americanism and sounds queer to English ears. Then say 'Boss' if it <pb n="64"/>pleases you by all manner of means, there are not many people round here to listen to you."</p>				<p>"That's flat enough. We can count our acquaintance on our fingers. They don't care about paupers in this country, I suppose, but if we came in for a lot of money all the neighbourhood would be Tom and Jerry."</p>				<p>"Tom and Jerry! Why, surely that's the name of one of your drinks. You meant Jack and Tom, I fancy."</p>				<p>"Perhaps I did. How you snap one up if one makes a little mistake. The old nobility don't seem to have had the extra twopence paid for manners, anyway!" she flashes indignantly.</p>				<p>"If we <hi rend="italic">had</hi> money we might bid for High Towers when it comes under the <pb n="65"/>hammer next month," he says with a smile, wishing to appease her.</p>				<p>"Is High Towers going to be sold?" she questions eagerly, with a malicious look in her face.</p>				<p>"Without reserve, and more's the pity; poor Melville is off abroad somewhere to try and forget in change that he is homeless and comparatively penniless&#x2014;Where's the child?"</p>				<p>"The child " is his youngest olive branch, her name is really the quaint and pretty one of "Bluebell," but, after the manner of most pretty names it is shortened into a commonplace appellation. She is the strangest little creature imaginable; romantic, dreamy to excess, a lover of reading, and with an intense passion for music. She is fragile and as white as snow, with exquisite <pb n="66"/>little features, and a pair of large serious eyes as guileless as a baby's. She is idolized by her father and looked upon by her mother as a very inferior article to her elder sister.</p>				<p>"Where is the child? Why, in the usual place, I suppose, lying under the apple trees with some rubbishy book of fairy tales. A. more lazy, useless child I never saw. She must really be sent to a good school soon, where they'll knock all romantic nonsense out of her, and besides she <hi rend="italic">must be finished</hi>, you know. She can't dance a step or play a bar of 'Yankee Doodle ' or&#x2014;"</p>				<p>"She can sing like a bird, far better than Claire does," the Honourable John cries stoutly, roused out of his habitual indolence, as he takes up the cudgels for his <pb n="67"/>especial companion, pet and plaything. "I never put my foot down, but there is a limit to forbearance, you know, and sorry as I should be to oppose your wishes, Bell will <hi rend="italic">never</hi> go to a finishing school. They are sinks of iniquity to my thinking. She may not be able to do the skirt dance, she may not be able to thump away on the piano at "Ta-ra-ra-boom-de-ay,"but she can do a lot of Greek and Latin, she can keep accounts and she has a wonderful capacity for composition. She is <hi rend="italic">my</hi> pupil, and I flatter myself my youngest daughter will be one of our most celebrated novelists some day. She has a fertile imagination, an intense temperament and a poetical nature. Bell is <hi rend="italic">spirituelle</hi>, and has the refinement the Delavals are known for."</p>				<p>"And a mighty deal of good refinement <pb n="68"/>has done the Delavals; much benefit has it been to you. Bell ought to learn cooking and housekeeping and darning instead of staring up at the stars, writing sonnets to the moon and dreaming away the time. It's downright wicked, I call it."</p>				<p>"Bell never did or thought a wicked thing in her life; she does not know what wickedness is. I <hi rend="italic">won't</hi> have her run down, poor little mite. There's misery enough, God knows, in this world, without letting misguided notions make a child's existence a burden. Bell would soon be out of this world if she was severely treated, and her spirit broken. She is a delicate little thing, and if we want to keep her we cannot be too careful and tender."</p>				<p>"Going out of this wicked world isn't <pb n="69"/>such a dreadful thing as people fancy," the Honourable Mrs. Delaval announces, drearily, lifting her black eyes piously Heavenward. "I am sure I often wish to die, and no wonder."</p>				<p>"And yet you would be very sorry to leave this world with all its wickedness; you love the wicked world, my dear Victoria, and you would be loth to leave the fleshpots yet awhile."</p>				<p>"Fleshpots indeed!" she answers filliping a shrimp with a contemptuous finger. "Much I get of them! It's all a grind, a pinching and a starving."</p>				<p>"No wonder the larder isn't too well replenished when <hi rend="italic">Claire</hi> is indulged in every whim and extravagance, and she <hi rend="italic">is</hi> extravagant! not that <hi rend="italic">I</hi> grudge her anything if we can possibly manage it; but <pb n="70"/>it's late and I must get a breath of fresh air."</p>				<p>He runs down the meadow towards a clump of apple trees.</p>				<p>Here, in the gloaming, Bell lies on the grass regardless of anything so commonplace as rheumatism. Her fair head rests on her arm, her face is upturned to the sky, out of which all signs of day are fast dying, and she is so wrapt in her fantastical thoughts that her father is close beside her before she knows of his proximity. It is wonderful the loving look that flashes into her eyes as she sees him. Jumping up, she entwines her arm in his.</p>				<p>"Don't scold, darling. I forgot everything&#x2014;supper and you&#x2014;and everything. It has been so beautiful lying here, you know. I watched the stars peeping out <pb n="71"/>one by one through that big bank of cloud and I wondered if it was true what I have been reading to-day about a plurality of worlds. How nice it would be if it was really&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">really</hi> true."</p>				<p>"Why, little one?"</p>				<p>"Because you and I could go and live in a star and be so jolly and peaceful&#x2014;away from all the bother down here&#x2014;away from&#x2014;&#x2014;" She pauses.</p>				<p>"Your mother," he is just on the point of saying, but stops short. "Why, Bell, I believe it has been raining,"he cries anxiously, as the touch of his shoulder against a big, fruit-laden bough brings down quite an avalanche of water over them both, " the grass must be quite damp, and you'll be ill."</p>				<p>"No, no, dear, I am all right. Just look <pb n="72"/>at those rain-drops on the leaves shining like big diamonds in the starlight; they look like the jewelled trees in Aladdin's garden. I wish I was a fairy! Half the mortals I know are so dull and uninteresting. They think of nothing but eating and drinking."</p>				<p>"Which reminds me that you must come in to supper at once. There are some lovely shrimps," he says laughing.</p>				<p>"I <hi rend="italic">hate</hi> shrimps," she cries energetically.</p>				<p>"So do I. I hate all sorts of shell fish."</p>				<p>"Not oysters, papa! Mamma says oysters are the greatest blessing we have. I can't fancy oysters being a blessing."</p>				<p>"They may be," he says with a twinkle in his eye, then he pauses discreetly, for he remembers that the piscatorial benefits from Grandpapa Plumper have been kept a sealed book from his grandchildren.</p>			</div>			<pb n="73"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER III<lb/>THIRTY THOUSAND A YEAR</head>				<epigraph>					<lg>						<l>Here, where the world is quiet,</l>						<l>Here, where all trouble seems</l>						<l>Dead, winds and spent waves riot,</l>						<l>In doubtful dreams of dreams."</l>					</lg>				</epigraph>				<p>THE little shower that had wetted the apple tree boughs and powdered the foliage with diamonds, according to Bluebell's poetical fancy, turned during the night, into quite a soaker, and Brambledene&#x2014;none too beautiful even in sunshine&#x2014;looks damp and dreary enough when its inmates settle down to the parsimonious repast yclept breakfast.</p>				<p>The Honourable John, in an old, wornout tweed suit, but looking as clean and <pb n="74"/>dainty as if he had just emerged from a bandbox, cracks his solitary egg listlessly, and absently chops into minute bits his thick slice of brown, leathery toast.</p>				<p>After having, in times gone by, his appetite coaxed by luscious morsels of sorts, a nice devilled kidney, a delicate little <hi rend="italic">sole &#x00E0; la financi&#x00E8;re</hi>, scrumptious steak, or a well-cooked cutlet, it certainly does seem hard in the autumn of his days to content himself daily with fare the reverse of <hi rend="italic">app&#x00E9;tisant</hi>, but according to his wont, he does not grumble. For a man of the nineteenth century, he is wonderfully patient and resigned, but all the same, he thankfully pushes his plate away as the "rat-tat" of the postman comes like a pleasant innovation.</p>				<p>"From Claire, to say when she is going <pb n="75"/>to make up her mind to come back," the Honourable Mrs. Delaval cries acidly.</p>				<p>"Another dun from the butcher," the Honourable John murmurs meekly. "He told me the other day meat had risen considerably, and he wanted his money."</p>				<p>"Run, Bell, for the letters," her mother orders sharply.</p>				<p>Bell, who, like her father, has no proclivities for indifferent food, abandons her porridge and thick bread and butter willingly, and is back again in the twinkling of an eye.</p>				<p>"No letter from Claire, nor is it a bill. It is a letter for you, mamma, a great, long funny-looking letter," and she holds up an important bluish document which the Honourable Mrs. snatches at roughly.</p>				<p>Tearing open the envelope, she glances <pb n="76"/>hurriedly at the contents. As she reads, her swarthy face grows redder and redder and she breathes hard and loud. Then she turns pale, but only for a second. As she begins to realise what the letter is about, her eyes begin to burn fitfully and a vivid patch of crimson rises on her cheeks.</p>				<p>"John," she almost shrieks, in the delirium of her delight, "read, read!" but overcome by some emotion of pleasure or grief, she leans back in her chair, panting and apparently unable to articulate another word.</p>				<p>"What is it all about?" he asks, quietly and indifferently, taking the momentous effusion from her shaking hand.</p>				<p>"What's the letter about?&#x2014;see what it's about! Oh, John! John! I <hi rend="italic">ought</hi> to <pb n="77"/>be sorry, but I&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">can't</hi> be! It is out ofmy power to be <hi rend="italic">really</hi> sorry&#x2014;but the Boss is&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">dead</hi>and&#x2014;and&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>"And we have come in for thirty thousand a year," the Honourable John says very quietly.</p>				<p>He never thinks of himself as he studies the document. He is as unselfish a man as ever breathed. For twenty years he has been waiting for a windfall&#x2014;for some money to come, and for all this wretched grinding and privation to be over, and now that he knows they <hi rend="italic">are</hi> over, all he says from the bottom of his heart is:</p>				<p>"Let us thank God, my dear Victoria, that the children's future is assured. Claire need not go on the operatic stage."</p>				<p>His wife stares at him with vacant eyes; she scarcely hears what he is saying.</p>				<pb n="78"/>				<p>"Remember it is <hi rend="italic">my</hi> money, John, settled on me absolutely for my life! and after my death it all goes to Claire! Fancy my girl being such a big heiress! I tell you, John, that my very first purchase shall be High Towers. I said I would buy the roof over that hateful old woman's head if I ever had money enough to do so, and now that I have it, I'll teach the proud old Countess of Melville to be civil to me; I'll teach her to knock under to the only real aristocracy in the world, the aristocracy of ready money, the aristocracy that can walk through the streets with its head up in the air&#x2014;the aristocracy that pays down its money and has its choice!"</p>				<p>The Honourable John looks across the table fixedly at the amiable partner of his bosom. How desperately vulgar and <pb n="79"/>waspish she is, how terribly wanting in all feminine beauty and grace.</p>				<p>"Can this accession to wealth even reconcile him to being this woman's husband?" he asks himself, with an inward shudder, then he quickly turns away towards his youngest born&#x2014;his little Blue-bell&#x2014;who is certainly a far pleasanter object to look upon, with her charming mignonne figure, her big blue eyes and her long hair floating over her shoulders, down below her waist, like golden mist.</p>				<p>She sits bolt upright on a three-legged stool, staring alternately at her progenitors.</p>				<p>"High Towers!"</p>				<p>She cannot take it in a bit. "<hi rend="italic">Going to buy High Towers</hi>," her mother said.</p>				<p>The place that has always seemed to Bell&#x2014;accustomed as she is to shabbiness and <pb n="80"/>circumscribed space&#x2014;like a sort of royal residence, fit for the Queen herself, and oh! what an exquisite paradise it looks whenever she peeps through some little gap in the hedge and gets a tiny glimpse of the magnificent old house, crowned with three towers that seem to reach up to the skies. How she has always longed to steal into the enchanted domain, and pluck the bright sweet flowers that she doats on. How she has longed to dream away the hours beneath the shade of the tall ancestral trees, whose great boughs, leafless and snow-wrapped in winter time, seemed like white arms waving to her to come.</p>				<p>But of course it cannot be true! It is only a tale, like Cinderella. Her mother is joking, though she jokes but seldom, <pb n="81"/>and as she awakens to this fact, her startled eyes resume their blue serenity, and catching her father's amused glance, she laughs&#x2014;a ringing laugh like silver chimes.</p>				<p>"Come along, Bell, we'll go and have a run with the dogs&#x2014;the rain has cleared up and the sun is shining&#x2014;the beggars have been scratching and whining at the door for the last ten minutes; they don't under-stand that we are richer to-day than we were yesterday, and make no allowance for our wishing to sit quiet and realise such wonderful news."</p>				<p>"Before you go, John, I wish to impress on your mind that I don't wish Claire to hear of the change in our fortunes&#x2014;mind, Bell, not a word of it if you write. I must insist on my wishes in this matter being <pb n="82"/>complied with," the Honourable Mrs. Delaval says pompously.</p>				<p>"All right," her husband replies, and he and Bell are off at once from the room, which always seems to stifle the man when his wife is in it.</p>				<p>Left alone, she seizes the precious document, which is lying on the table, and presses a dozen frantic kisses on it.</p>				<p>"The poor old Boss was an awful old miser&#x2014;bless him&#x2014;may his soul repose! Thirty thousand pounds&#x2014;pounds, not dollars&#x2014;a year, and thirty thousand pounds down! What a big sum it seems, but it's not a bit too big for a place like High Towers. I can hardly believe in such luck. If I found out now that it wasn't all real, I believe the shock would kill me downright, but it is real&#x2014;real&#x2014;real!"</p>				<pb n="83"/>				<p>Her face grows calmer, her swarthy cheek pales and her black eyes lose their fire, and gaze for a few moments greedily on the paper, then she carefully stows it away in her ample bosom.</p>				<p>"There!" she cries spasmodically. "There, it's all safe! Won't Claire be pleased to hear such news? She might as well have come home long ago, but she is a downright queer girl, there isn't much heart about her, I reckon. She prefers Brussels to home, of course; anyhow, she shan't have the news till she returns. I'd like to get settled down at High Towers, all carpeted and elegant, before she comes back. My beautiful girl! To think what an heiress she is, and what a fine marriage she can make&#x2014;nothing short of a royal prince is to my liking, but in this horrid <pb n="84"/>Conservative country royalty is as far removed from ladies and gentlemen as if they were sweeps. Anyway, we shall have all the big bloods running after her&#x2014;the greater the swell the greater the pauper in England&#x2014;nothing but exchange and barter&#x2014;so much money for such a title. Claire will be able to buy a real live dook with <hi rend="italic">her</hi> money, thank goodness! Fancy me&#x2014;her mother&#x2014;having to call her 1 your grace,' but that's the custom in this' country, I have heard. My! won't she put on side considerable! She's fond of being grand now, what on earth we shall have to put up with when she knows about the fortune, I shouldn't like to guess! No more pinching and squeezing for us! rumpsteak for breakfast, every day if I want it&#x2014;six courses for dinner&#x2014;it's <hi rend="italic">heavenly</hi> to <pb n="85"/>think of! Bless you, poor old Boss! You have done your duty properly towards your child, and you have got your reward by this time. To think that an ugly, little, shapeless creature like an oyster should have brought us such good luck. Bless it&#x2014;bless <hi rend="italic">them</hi>&#x2014;bless all the oysters that have been eaten in Washington Plumper's saloon! I shall never forget to mention them in my prayers, along with the Boss, for they have all been my best friends in this world. John won't abuse shell fish any more&#x2014;he couldn't be capable of such base ingratitude."</p>				<p>She rises from her chair, and unlocking a drawer in the old worm-eaten sideboard, takes out a little flask of whiskey&#x2014;she likes it neat, so does not trouble for a tumbler.</p>				<pb n="86"/>				<p>"There," she says, "that's my first real long pull for many a day, and it's all in honour of the Boss; I drink long life&#x2014;" she pauses, and turns a little white. "What <hi rend="italic">was</hi> I going to say? Why, the Boss is&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">dead</hi>&#x2014;dead as a hammer! Poor, dear old Boss, but I have the real consolation of knowing that he must have died peacefully, and with an approving conscience at having done his duty in a first-rate fashion to-wards me and mine!"</p>				<p>Meanwhile, Topsy and Turvey, the little fox-terriers, having had a long run under the now sweltering sun, are lying in the soft grass of the orchard, showing their little red tongues, and their chaperons&#x2014;the Honourable John and Bluebell&#x2014;perch like a couple of Love-birds, on a large <pb n="87"/>lopped bough under the grateful shadow of an apple tree.</p>				<p>The two have been silent for some moments, principally because they are out of breath like their canine companions, but presently he speaks, while he strokes her bright hair fondly.</p>				<p>"Shall you like having a great big house, Bell?"</p>				<p>"I don't mind what size the house is, if you are in it, dear," she answers lovingly, slipping her mite of a hand into his strong, firm clasp, "but mamma was only joking when she talked about High Towers, wasn't she?"</p>				<p>"No, she was very much in earnest, I think. Shan't you be glad to be rich, Puss? Just fancy how many smart things you will want, smart frocks, smart hats, <pb n="88"/>as many as the Queen of Sheba had, I dare say."</p>				<p>"I don't care a bit about smart hats and frocks. I like my old cotton dresses because I can tumble them without being scolded. Perhaps the Queen of Sheba did not care about lying on the grass?"</p>				<p>"I never heard if she had any proclivities that way. She was a sensible woman, I dare say, not a small silly like you. However, what would you like best?"</p>				<p>"What I should like best?" reiterates Bluebell reflectively with a queer, dreamy look coming into her eyes. "It's so difficult to know. Papa, I think I should like some nice large trees, larger than these, to shade me, when I lie on the grass. I <hi rend="italic">love</hi> lying on the grass, dear. I can think <pb n="89"/>ever so much better out in the open air. It's such a lot of room, you know, with only the lovely sky above one&#x2014;and, dear, I should like some new books, my ' Andersen's Fairy Tales ' is so torn, but it isn't my fault. I <hi rend="italic">am</hi> very untidy, as mamma says. But I really do take care of my books. Topsy and Turvey fought for Andersen the other day, and nearly chawed him up between them. I don't think there is anything else I want very much."</p>				<p>"Your requirements are very modest, my Bluebell," he says laughing. "I dare say we can compass the big apple tree and the fairy tales, if we are economical in other things. Wouldn't you like to have lessons in riding, and painting, and music?"</p>				<p>"Music!" she answers eagerly, a strange <pb n="90"/>bright light flashing in her eyes, and her face flushing warmly. "Oh! how I should love to sing beautifully."</p>				<p>"As well as Claire?"</p>				<p>She does not answer for a moment, then she says:</p>				<p>"Don't you think, dear, that some music makes one's heart beat&#x2014;one's eyes feel blind, one's hands grow cold, and one's soul soar right away from earth to Heaven? When Claire used to sing, I never felt all this, papa. I wonder why?"</p>				<p>He does not reply, but he knows why&#x2014;he knows that Claire's music is heartless, soulless, and that it never appeals to him like some little snatch of a simple melody that breaks now and then from Bluebell's pretty lips.</p>				<p>"Oh, how I should love to sing beauti-<pb n="91"/>fully," the girl cries, clasping her little hands enthusiastically. "I should sing all day long, I think. Some songs haunt me in sleep, and make me feel as if I were dead and being floated on angels' wings to the sky. Do you ever feel this, papa?"</p>				<p>"No, my pet, I am afraid I am too old and prosaic for that sort of thing. Music is all very well in its way, but <hi rend="italic">ne quid nimis</hi>, which means that one can have too much of a good thing. I expect we shall be pretty well regaled in shakes and trills when Claire comes home, though by the way, she may not care to practise much now that there is no necessity for her to come out at the Opera. Young ladies of money and position don't practise much at anything now-a-days, except airs and graces," he says drily, then he goes off in a <pb n="92"/>brown study about the future and Bell follows suit, except that with her as with most people of tender years, the present has most attraction.</p>				<p>"I really think I should be a little sorry to leave Brambledene," she murmurs wistfully.</p>				<p>"Sorry to leave Brambledene? Why, what on earth could you find to regret in this place, child?"</p>				<p>"I don't know, perhaps I have grown accustomed to its ugliness, and then the nightingales in the lane are lovely. I don't believe any other nightingales sing like them. I shall never forget that great treat you gave me last year when we were in London. Do you remember, papa? It was when you and I, quite by our two selves, went to the Italian Opera."</p>				<pb n="93"/>				<p>He remembers, and shrugs his shoulders at the occasion being called a "treat." It was a treat indeed, being boxed up in a row of the cheapest seats with the great unwashed around, and with the grilling heat of a real June night, making the outing downright purgatory.</p>				<p>"I shall never forget that night, <hi rend="italic">never&#x2014;never!</hi>" Bell goes on in a slow, low voice, and with a curious rapt expression in her great blue eyes. "When the man who acted Lohengrin sang, I really thought I was in Heaven. It was so beautiful. It was like the song of the dying swan, which I have read is the most beautiful music in the world. I have never heard anything like it in my life, except the nightingales. That is why I should like to go on living here, just to listen to them in the lanes."</p>				<pb n="94"/>				<p>The Honourable John pulls at his grisly moustache and looks a trifle grave.</p>				<p>Bluebell, the darling of his heart, is such a queer, imaginative child&#x2014;such a difficult child to bring up in the way she should go. He shivers as he thinks that some unscrupulous ruffian with a tenor voice, would probably captivate her at once&#x2014;evidently he did an unwise thing when he took her to Covent Garden and let the sweet subtle sounds of Jean de Reszke's voice steal into her heart.</p>				<p>"You silly child," he says, "you must really put all such things out of your little head and become a young lady of Society. What sensible man would care to marry a romantic little goose who loves nightingales and fairy tales above everything else?"</p>				<pb n="95"/>				<p>"I don't want to marry&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">ever</hi>" Bell asserts positively, "I wouldn't leave you for the world, dear, unless&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>"Unless?"</p>				<p>"Unless Lohengrin asked me," she whispers shyly, "and then I <hi rend="italic">know</hi>&#x2014;I<hi rend="italic">couldn't resist!</hi>"</p>			</div>			<pb n="96"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER IV<lb/>HIGH TOWERS</head>				<epigraph>					<p>"The stately homes of England,</p>					<p>How beautiful they stand."</p>				</epigraph>				<p>THE home of the Melvilles for many a generation is a grand old house, that presents a stone face, which is ornamented with elaborately carved balconies and spiral columns, a little after the Italian style. The frontage, in lieu of the ordinary principal entrance, has three enormous portals surmounted by high towers that seem to reach the skies, according to Bluebell's imaginative mind.</p>				<p>On the centre of each of these towers, is a marvellous representation of the <pb n="97"/>Melville crest&#x2014;a large crowned heart supported by a gauntleted hand.</p>				<p>The interior of the huge building contains large rooms, lengthy corridors, wide galleries and tesselated flooring. Right before the high mullioned windows, in the midst of a vast sloping lawn green as emeralds and soft as velvet, rises a tall fountain of purest white marble. It is as old as Mount Horeb, and is chipped and broken, but it is a marvel of sculpture, with a design of three seminude nymphs, holding vases in the shape of Roman urns aloft.</p>				<p>On the surface of the marble basin repose large water lilies, lovely when first budding out their pure virginal charms amidst fresh and undulating leaves. Thrice lovely when, with alabaster-hued <pb n="98"/>petals fully expanded, they float regally. Pale with passion they seem, as, their delicate faces are turned upwards to meet the fervid gaze of the sun-god; the languid flowers bend beneath the heat of the summer hours, while the deep dense green of the foliage relieves the intensity of the glowing colouring. High Towers, though intensely English in most things, yet conveys the impression of a foreign clime, of a land where the leaf never falls. The surroundings are simply paradisical,. and the air is full of soft and subtle perfumes. All round the house, as if in artistic contrast to the cool green of swelling sward, backed by the darker hue of groups of gigantic trees, sheltering the blaze and glory of a multitude of bloom, a broad stone <pb n="99"/>terrace skirts the lawn, and before it lies a lovely lake fringed with drooping trees, that seem to kiss the purple water. Hot-houses and vineries form avenues of glass that the moonbeams touch into gold and the sun kindles into fires at noonday. Stretches of woodland lie in the distance full of shadowy dells and verdant nooks. Orchards hold out their luscious fruit. Here and there towers a monster oak or elm, and&#x2014;save the monotonous whisper of leaves, the lilt of the summer wind, and the ripple of water&#x2014;all around is silence, that profound silence in which one seems to hear the great heart of Nature beat. Through the air steals the fragrance of starry jessamine, entwining its long feathery arms lovingly round each sister plant, and mingling its delicious perfume <pb n="100"/>with that of roses&#x2014;the peerless queen of flowers, renowned for their beauty since three thousand years ago, when, so tradition saith, the first of the species shot up from the earth which was stained by the crimson tide of Adonis's blood.</p>				<p>But a deserted and very neglected place is High Towers, after all, though as prodigal in sweet odours as if money and care had always been lavished on it. Strewn across the broad, ill-tended paths, lie long branches of briony and honeysuckle, tangled and bruised pitilessly under foot. On either side, wherever the eye turns, all manner of flowerets growing in wild profusion blush through all the gradations of white to red, blue-eyed blossoms peep out upon the scene, and cinquefoil creeping stealthily along the grass dots it with <pb n="101"/>tiny golden speckles that gleam and glow in the sunshine. The only living animated objects visible are what some poet calls the bright offsprings of the air, gorgeously spangled butterflies; now above and now below fluttering recklessly among the honeyed flowers&#x2014;soaring high up in wayward flight, or alighting on some scented chalice to repose and sip. But the butterflies and the blossoms, the sunbeams and the ambient air, are all in sad contrast to the internal appearance of poor High Towers.</p>				<p>Within, everything bears a look that gives depression&#x2014;a look of faded splendour, that brings painfully to the mind the decay of a noble house once rich in the wealth and indomitable pride of the old English aristocracy.</p>				<pb n="102"/>				<p>The wide tapestried curtains, woven cunningly with devices that might have graced the celebrated Gobelins, hang tattered and soiled by the hand of ruthless Time. The exquisite arras&#x2014;put in for good Queen Bess's benefit when she slept two nights at High Towers&#x2014;follow suit, and here and there a superb old Worcester jar or quaint old English marqueterie enriched with silver and platinum, mark by their lone splendour the almost poverty stricken appearance of the general surroundings. Tall-backed prie Dieu chairs, elaborately embroidered by the nuns of the Bleeding Heart, in manifold hues that have unanimously blended into neutral tints, stand formal and uninviting round the dark oak wainscot, and the tesselated floor is neglected and stained. But all the <pb n="103"/>dullness, the discomfort, the pinch of poverty, have been borne wonderfully by the proud old Countess of Melville. She is a rigid devotee, considering a word or a laugh lightly given a dire disrespect to Heaven, and believing that intense mortification of the flesh is the only thing that conduces to a healthy soul. The Melvilles have always been strict Roman Catholics, but the present Countess is the strictest of them all. She loves her only son, but that love has been so pruned and regulated by her religion that most of its fervour has fled, and only a tame sentiment left. All her confidence, all her conversation, is given to a priest, all her devotion and her thought are lavished on the ivory crucifix that hangs on her breast and is frequently pressed to her lips.</p>				<pb n="104"/>				<p>The dismal atmosphere of High Towers is by no means brightened by her sombre presence. Yet her son has deemed it almost a sacrilege to intrude on the solemn tenor of her life by the guests whose mundane notions and frivolity would horrify the holder of a creed more approaching to fanaticism than reason.</p>				<p>There is, however, inconsistent as it may seem, one earthly passion in Lady Melville's breast, an absorbing love for her home, and leaving it seems to her to be death in life.</p>				<p>Yet she knows that High Towers is doomed to the hammer&#x2014;that nothing can keep it in her grasp.</p>				<p>Alan, Lord Melville, is twenty-six years of age. He has a handsome patrician face, and a tall, <hi rend="italic">svelte</hi> figure, remarkable <pb n="105"/>for its symmetry. In spite of his undeniable poverty he is unimpeachable in dress, but, whatever his dress might be, he is a man to be remarked wherever he goes.</p>				<p>In the latter years he has been very down on his luck. There is not a single break, as far as short-sighted mortals can discover, in the dark clouds looming over his fortunes. In fact, he knows well enough that there is but one event in the future that could bring him back the position his forefathers have held, and that is a wealthy marriage.</p>				<p>But no signs of such an El Dorado have shown themselves, and if they had, it is doubtful that he would avail himself of them, for, in spite of his having lived a good deal in the world, Lord Melville <pb n="106"/>has the folly to be romantic to a certain extent.</p>				<p>He has found plenty of women to admire him, and has never lacked success if he sought it, but he has never troubled himself about any woman much&#x2014;according to the French rhyme:</p>				<lg>					<l>"On dit que dans ses amours,</l>					<l>II fut caress&#x00E9; des belles</l>					<l>Qui le suiv&#x00E8;rent toujours</l>					<l>Tant qu'il marcha devant elles!"</l>				</lg>				<p>The man in fact is no voluptuary&#x2014;his love affairs have been more in accordance with the ways of the upper ten than from any overdue impetuosity of temperament. He is a true Briton, possessing all the good and bad qualities that appertain to his nation.</p>				<p>					<hi rend="italic">Blas&#x00E9;</hi> as he avows himself to be, there is <pb n="107"/>genuine depth and freshness in his nature, and the noise, the gaiety, the perpetual "life" in town are dear to his heart. He loves London, loves it after the fashion of most of the golden youth&#x2014;loves it from high to low&#x2014;from its magnificence down to its lowest&#x2014;just because it <hi rend="italic">is</hi> London. He is not especially extravagant or frivolous, but class and habit have made him believe that the <hi rend="italic">summum bonum</hi> of existence is Fortunatus' purse, unfailing as the widow's cruise of oil. He likes to dress well, to dine well, and to finish up his day at White's or Brooks's with an excellent cigar.</p>				<p>So, on the whole, Lord Melville's vices and virtues are pretty evenly balanced. He is as handsome as a man needs to be, he is a typical Englishman of the very best social class, one on whom the culture of <pb n="108"/>generations is as apparent as the fine blood of a thoroughbred horse. Tall, neither fair nor dark, with a pair of deep blue eyes under long black lashes, close curling hair of a medium brown, and an air of unmistakable distinction. There is generally something about him&#x2014;an honest languor in the deep blue eyes&#x2014;an honest weariness on the face, that lead those who look below the surface to imagine that he is not a really happy man, or at any rate not a well satisfied one. Though he is by no means "<hi rend="italic">sans peur et sans reproche</hi>," he is not either a "Don Juan."</p>				<p>The fashionable follies of the day used to come as naturally to him as his daily bread&#x2014;but within the last year he has renounced all extravagant pastimes and expensive toys, for he has to face the fact that the <pb n="109"/>home of his forefathers must pass out of his life.</p>				<p>Pass away into the hands of strangers for ever.</p>				<p>What a thrill of unhappiness the thought brings to the man's heart, but he wears a brave front, and no one looking at him could guess what he feels when he takes his last look at the old familiar scenes among which he was born, and which have been a part of his very life.</p>			</div>			<pb n="110"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER V<lb/>"WILL YOU SWEAR IT?"</head>				<epigraph>					<lg>						<l>"Yea, I know this well: Were you once sealed mine,</l>						<l>Mine in the blood's beat&#x2014;mine in the breath,</l>						<l>Mixed into me as honey in wine,</l>						<l>Nor time that sayeth and gainsayeth,</l>						<l>Nor all strong things had severed us then."</l>					</lg>				</epigraph>				<p>THE tryst in the Pare at Brussels was only the forerunner of many more. Claire Delaval had crept out in the dusk, and her absence of an hour has never been observed, and now she has grown more hardy and the hour is lengthened into two&#x2014;hours that pass like seconds to the Italian singing-master and his pupil.</p>				<p>Which of us, however, do not know by the time we have reached one score, that <hi rend="italic">omnia vincit amor</hi>? There are, in truth, <pb n="111"/>moments in life, moments when that divinest of delusions and folly that men call "love" holds autocratic sway, moments when heat or cold, sunshine or snow&#x2014;in fact all external things&#x2014;present exactly the same aspect to the full heart revelling in its delicious sense of reciprocity. The modern Adam and Eve of the Brussels Pare, in their retreat beneath the spreading trees, are indifferent to everything but their two selves. The man's dark eyes seek his love's grey orbs with a passionate intensity that commingles with a sort of wistfulness, and the few wavering lines round his mouth which are his only defect, show up in absolute feebleness.</p>				<p>It is palpable enough that to him the universe holds but one woman. He is not more foolish or credulous than most of <pb n="112"/>his sex, yet he believes that an angel in woman's guise sits by his side. Mad havoc the charming face has made in his heart, the beauty of it thrills his veins, the proximity of it makes his blood run riot. Strange to say, with these earthly influences over him, passion-tossed, weak as a reed in the blast, the love that leaps and flows and burns in his pulses and soul, is a tender love and a true one&#x2014;not a model love by any means in the eyes of the stiff and starched but true and tender in comparison to the love men give women nowadays.</p>				<p>Broad statuesque lids, white as milk and heavily fringed with long, curling lashes, veil the windows of the girl's soul&#x2014;her great grey, luminous, almond-shaped eyes. Young as she is, Heaven only knows what <pb n="113"/>those sweeping lashes hide! There may be love infinite, love single-minded, heartfelt, pure and self-abnegatory&#x2014;or there may be mockery incarnate, the diabolism of an embryo Jael or Delilah within their depths for aught he knows.</p>				<p>Still he is as wholly and absolutely hers, body and soul, now and till Doomsday, as if his faith were pinned to the purest and most immaculate of maidens and equalled in magnitude his blind and unreasoning worship.</p>				<p>It is only a case of Venus Victrix; another proof that a woman's single hair is a man's strongest chain. The marvellous loveliness of her face has a glamour for him, just as it might have for a man a thousand times firmer and more resolute than himself, a man perchance less passion-<pb n="114"/>ful, less prone to be enslaved by lust of the eye. Marco Ferrari does not pause to question whether this half-child, half-woman, he adores is pure and good and true, as a woman should be. While he gazes entranced on her beauty, it is not likely he can conceive her to be evil, black as Gehenna within. He would laugh to scorn the very idea that so fair a casket could hold aught but a priceless pearl.</p>				<p>An intense, all-absorbing desire possesses him this evening, that no human gaze save his own should rest on the ripe perfection of face and form that has fired his heart and brain. So strongly does he feel this that he believes he could kill her sooner than let another man pluck the beauty he covets. The word "covet" is used advisedly, for, lovers as they are and have <pb n="115"/>been for the period of months, he covets the full and clear revealment of the heart in her fair bosom&#x2014;he covets greedily the kisses that she has hitherto <hi rend="italic">yielded</hi> him, but never proffered.</p>				<p>Most women are sphinxes and paradoxes. This girl, to those who know her, has always created a wonder if she ever was a child, or whether she came into the world with her feelings fully matured, and with wiles and blandishments at the end of her taper fingers.</p>				<p>The starlight shows her face to him, a face that has no flaw, her waving bronze-flecked hair glitters like burnished ore; her lids are lowered, and somehow she looks cold and reticent, and apparently as soulless as Galatea.</p>				<p>Maddened by her beauty, stung by her <pb n="116"/>coldness, Ferrari seizes her hands, while his own quiver at the touch&#x2014;for he loves her so!</p>				<p>His heart and his manhood lie at her feet, and he would rather she trod them ruthlessly in the dust, than that they should crown any other woman's life with joy and glory.</p>				<p>"Look at me, my darling. Let me see your eyes," he cries impetuously. He yearns to read her real feelings towards him, and, unconsciously perhaps, he has more faith in her glance, than in the pretty lips&#x2014;so tempting&#x2014;yet so like a child's.</p>				<p>His impetuosity sounds rather masterful, and she likes it. It suits her own imperious nature, and touches her more than gentleness or sentiment.</p>				<pb n="117"/>				<p>She slowly lifts her eyes to his, and what she reads in his fervent gaze, brings a hot, flickering colour to her cheeks, melts away her look of coldness and, sending a swift glow to her features, renders her doubly beautiful.</p>				<p>In this moment, perchance, <hi rend="italic">soul meets soul</hi>, though one soul&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">his</hi>&#x2014;is as far above the other, as the stars are above the earth. In sudden moments like these, in the twinkling of an eye, the veil of deceit and worldliness is uplifted, and soul meets soul just to show mankind that Love is Life, and that without love human beings might as well be cabbages or oysters.</p>				<p>Like a second Pygmalion, Ferrari looks at the beauty he has invoked. With a quick, impulsive gesture, he catches her to his <pb n="118"/>breast, and holds her there. It is her kingdom, in which she reigns sovereign&#x2014;fickle, capricious, perhaps unworthy, but absolute and alone.</p>				<p>So they rest for a little while. The Pare is deserted and the silence lies unbroken save by the quick throbbing of his heart. It is a glorious night, the wind is slothful and warm, the twinkling lights outside the Pare fall mellow and chastened by the clustering foliage, and nature's pulse seems stilled into ineffable peace.</p>				<p>Alone! he and she! with the clear sky above them, and only the soft, shy eyes of the stars watching.</p>				<p>It is just the hour for love and happiness, an hour to steep with pleasure one's life, an hour when, lip to lip and hand in hand, the joys of Eden concentrate in a few <pb n="119"/>fleeting moments. But yet the man's heart throbs with pain.</p>				<p>"When we part, shall you grieve, dear child?" he asks brokenly, and he strains her closer in his arms, for the thought of parting cuts him like a knife.</p>				<p>A bright head with waving bronze-flecked tresses drops on his heart with an utter abandonment that startles him. Galatea no longer, it is a tender, loving woman, who gives him back love for love. Her coldness has been a sham throughout. Claire Delaval is a born coquette, and trifling and dallying with men's affections will be meat and drink to her by-and-bye. She already knows how to play with human feelings, and, as Watts says of the bears and lions, "it is her nature to."</p>				<p>She really believes this moment that she <pb n="120"/>adores this handsome, fervent lover, as much as she <hi rend="italic">can</hi> adore, but in reality her feelings are a mixture of gratified vanity, a craving for conquest, with a savour of incipient materialism.</p>				<p>"I shall die!" she flushes passionately. "Yes!" she reiterates. "I shall die whenwe part&#x2014;but&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>She pauses a second&#x2014;a vivid recollection that she is uncommonly badly off in the world's goods, that she is doomed to be a plaything of Fortune, comes to her mind&#x2014;she remembers the dreary sordid life at Brambledene, the absence of all things pleasant, the presence of all things hateful, the awful prospect of wasting her sweetness on the desert air, if she cannot secure a livelihood on the operatic stage.</p>				<p>Prudence whispers to her that it might <pb n="121"/>be as well to assure her future in some way if she can. What if this lover of hers is only a singing-master? What if he is not over wealthy? He has muscle, he has stalwart limbs to work for her, while she sits in the <hi rend="italic">dolce far niente</hi> of indolence and comfort that she loves. She has nothing to lose, but much to gain. Her home is undesirable. Poverty has made her father unsociable, her mother she is ashamed of, her cousin and sister have no place in her affections. Surely as Marco Ferrari's wife, she will be a million times happier, and better off! While she reasons thus, Ferrari is far away in a land of dreams, in which such gross common-place things as practical calculations and interested scheming have no part.</p>				<p>He is simply drunk with the ecstasy of <pb n="122"/>the first caress she has given, and through the delirium of a love-sick brain, a great wonder fills him, that such perfect lips have been offered, such beauty yielded to his clasp with the abandon of a child.</p>				<p>Surely he has reached Heaven!</p>				<p>Blind with the subtle glamour of passion he only sees the glowing flowers of Eden, while the trail of the serpent is hidden from his gaze.</p>				<p>"Why must we part, uncertain when or where we shall meet again?" she whispers.</p>				<p>He starts, he hearkens&#x2014;his head whirls, and a mist rises before his eyes, as he tries to realise this lovely creature as his very own.</p>				<p>She seems as far above him as the sun <pb n="123"/>is above the earth. Still, he has wooed her, with other thoughts and intentions. He has had no desire for a clandestine marriage. He has only wanted to convince himself that she was pure, sweet, innocent and worthy as a woman can be, before he made her&#x2014;openly, proudly, before all the world&#x2014;his wife.</p>				<p>Surprised at his silence, half-indignant that her suggestion has not been seized upon with avidity, she feels a keener desire to have her own way.</p>				<p>"I thought you loved me so!'' she murmurs. "I thought that the prospect of our never parting again, was as dear to you as it is to me!"</p>				<p>"Love you!" he exclaims hastily. "Love is a tame word for the <hi rend="italic">storm</hi> that rages in my soul! I would lay down my <pb n="124"/>life right willingly, if for a little while even I could call you my very own. If I could feel that I am to you, what you are to me&#x2014;that every pulse in your frame answers to mine&#x2014;my darling, my queen. It would be torture to leave you unfettered, but it would be ten time torture to part, knowing that other men's eyes feasted on the beauty of my wife. That horrible thought would drive me mad, for we <hi rend="italic">must</hi> part for awhile, my love. I could not in honour take you forcibly, clandestinely from your home. It would be an insult to you, whom I love and reverence with all my heart. I want you to be my wife, but the marriage must be open and above-board. Your people must give you to me willingly, and all the world must know that neither you nor I are ashamed of our choice."</p>				<pb n="125"/>				<p>There is a short silence, then her arm drops from him, and she says in a quiet, constrained voice:</p>				<p>"It is time for us to say good night and good-bye; my people will never let me marry you; there was but one way to avoid our parting for ever, and&#x2014;and you have refused it&#x2014;good bye."</p>				<p>She moves off, but with one quick bound he reaches her and catches her in his arms.</p>				<p>"Let me go!" she says impetuously. "Do you think I am only a plaything for your idle hours?"</p>				<p>"Oh, love! My love, don't drive me wild by such words," he pleads brokenly. "Don't you know that I am striving to act like a good and honest man? Don't you know that I am as wax in your hands, that your word is my law? <hi rend="italic">Don't you</hi>					<pb n="126"/>					<hi rend="italic">know it?</hi> Do as you will with me&#x2014;bind your life to mine&#x2014;but for God's sake do not blame me later&#x2014;do not be false to me&#x2014;do not ever forsake me!"</p>				<p>She sees truth written on every feature of his face&#x2014;the handsome face that has captivated her fancy.</p>				<p>"I'll never blame you&#x2014;I'll never be false to you&#x2014;I'll never forsake you!" she whispers.</p>				<p>"Will you swear&#x2014;swear with your heart against mine&#x2014;with your eyes looking into mine?"</p>				<p>"I swear!"</p>				<p>He stoops and seals the oath with a passionate kiss.</p>			</div>			<pb n="127"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER VI<lb/>MAN AND WIFE</head>				<epigraph>					<lg>						<l>Veux-tu mon c&#x0153;ur&#x2014;il est &#x00E0; toi,</l>						<l>Car il faut bien que tue souviens</l>						<l>Je n'ai plus rien qui m'appartient</l>						<l>Depuis que j'ai connu ta loi!</l>						<l>"O prends mon c&#x0153;ur&#x2014;il est &#x00E0; toi!</l>						<l>Si tu savais comme je t'aime</l>						<l>Bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;tu m'aimerais!"</l>					</lg>				</epigraph>				<p>CLAIRE DELAVAL sings her song now with all the fire and passion that the most exigeant lover could desire, and the handsome face of her singing-master grows radiant as he listens. All the listlessness, the want of "soul," in the first lessons have been dispersed to the four winds by the allpowerful touch of love, and as her clear <pb n="128"/>notes rise and fall and thrill through his heart, Ferrari <hi rend="italic">feels</hi>that she is his, that he has won her for all time.</p>				<p>"Play something,"she whispers, for the sheep-dog, Mademoiselle Havard, is unfortunately wide awake to-day and doing her eternal knitting.</p>				<p>His hands wander over the keys in a lovely improvised air. He does not know himself what sounds emanate under his skill, for his eyes are lifted to the girl's face with the adoration and reverence a <hi rend="italic">devotee</hi> gives to his saint, and as the exquisite form leans close to him his pulses throb at the proximity.</p>				<p>"In two days more I go to England, Marco," she says hurriedly. "There is no hope of delay."</p>				<p>The man's face, so full of happiness a <pb n="129"/>moment back, grows white as death, and infinite pain creeps into his eyes, his lips quiver and no sound comes from them, and all the while he plays on mechanically, but the air has changed into a plaint&#x2014;a plaint that comes from the heart&#x2014;and as it strikes his own ear, he thinks to himself it is a requiem for dead hours, the blissful hours that will never come again.</p>				<p>"Tomorrow at one o'clock&#x2014;for God's sake come!"he says with pallid lips, in a low, hoarse voice.</p>				<p>She bends her head in assent, stoops down on pretence of picking up her handkerchief, which she has purposely dropped, and in another instant Ferrari feels the warm pressure of her perfect mouth on his cold hand.</p>				<p>This kiss sends the blood flying back to <pb n="130"/>his cheek. He looks up at her fixedly. His life&#x2014;his love! And in another moment his mind is made up. What is honour, what are actions of which his conscience disapproves? What is <hi rend="italic">anything</hi>in comparison with the agony of letting her go away unfettered! If she knows she is married to him it will keep her true. It will be her strongest armour against temptations. As he realises this fact he flings away the memory of all the feelings he has hitherto held regarding women and marriage, flings the memory of them aside as recklessly as he would fling away his life, if by doing so he could secure to himself for even a little while her fair face and form, and above all, her <hi rend="italic">heart</hi>&#x2014;a little while, in which the joy and content of years would be concentrated. As he decides <pb n="131"/>bait. I intend to put out that bait, and I guess he'll nibble at once. Not that I care about him myselfthere's something common about the plain fronts of his shirts that hurts my eyes. Nobility, I have always heard, have their shirt fronts embroidered and done up splendid, and he hasn't a shirt stud, but a little gold thing which is only gilt, I dare say, and I don't like his manner or his conversation. I like a man who shows that he enjoys visiting in a grand house like this, and having expensive food five times a day, not a man who takes his meals and never says a 'thank you' for their being good. However, I am not going to marry him, so it does not signify what I think."</p>				<p>The door opens noiselessly and Melville walks in. True, his shirt front is of the <pb n="132"/>plainest kind, and only one little unpretending stud adorns it, but he looks the pink of fashion and the mould of form nevertheless&#x2014;as <hi rend="italic">chic</hi> a young nobleman as ever trod Piccadilly and Pall Mall.</p>				<p>Dinner is announced at this moment and he marshals in his hostess with all the courtesy imaginable, while the Honourable John appears, just in time to escort his daughter.</p>				<p>The meal passes off better than Claire expects, and when it is over the <hi rend="italic">parti carr&#x00E9;</hi> go back to the drawing-room.</p>				<p>Mrs. Delaval has dined liberally, and has consumed a little more than her share of the champagne, and she feels like a giant refreshed and very fit for the tug of war, when Melville returns from his postprandial smoke.</p>				<pb n="133"/>				<p>She is in a hurry to open the campaign, for sleep is coming near her lids, and once or twice already the two ostrich tips on her head-gear have nearly nodded down to her ample bosom.</p>				<p>"May I have the honour of a few words with you, my lord?" she begins solemnly. "It is a duty I owe to myself, and to my eldest daughter."</p>				<p>Melville looks up astonished. He has a guilty conscience too, and feels a little uncomfortable at the ominous word "duty."</p>				<p>"Certainly, Mrs. Delaval!' he tries to say jauntily, taking a chair near her, and with his white patrician hands folded on his knee and his head thrown a little back, he half closes his eyes and prepares to listen.</p>				<p>"Well! it's getting late, my lord, and I'm getting sleepy, so I won't beat round <pb n="134"/>the bush, but come to the point at once. You admire my girl, now don't you?"</p>				<p>"Extremely, my dear madam&#x2014;who wouldn't?"</p>				<p>"Well, that's a point gained; now do you think my girl is good enough for a fine lady of Society? I mean is she clever enough, can she speak French and German, and sing and play&#x2014;whatever is required for a lady in the upper circles?"</p>				<p>"I consider Miss Delaval has every requisite for any position, be it ever so high," he says politely.</p>				<p>"Then why in goodness' name don't you make her your countess? You have only to say the word, and I'll give her ten thousand a year to begin housekeeping with. After my death, she will come in for thirty thousand a year. There! What do <pb n="135"/>you think of that, my lord? Not to be sneezed at, is it?"</p>				<p>"Certainly not, Mrs. Delaval, but you know, however near to one's heart a matter may be, it requires a little reflection. You do me a great favour, and I thank you for it. Of course I know that you must be anxious to see your daughter's future assured, but would it not be more prudent for you to be longer acquainted with me before you decide that it is in my power to make your daughter happy?"</p>				<p>He looks up when he says this and catches Claire's eyes&#x2014;how wistfully they regard him! How pretty she looks, when she is pale and agitated, as she evidently is during this conversation! But his love for Cecil makes him impervious to every other woman's beauty now. He is Cecil's, and <pb n="136"/>never again will be tempted by the loveliest eyes and lips in the world.</p>				<p>"It's very nice of you, my lord, to speak so humble. Humility is a cardinal sin, so I think I have heard my husband say, but don't be afraid of Claire not being happy with you. She's one of those girls who have been well brought up and can suit herself to any company, and she's very accomplished too. She can sing Italian songs as well as Adelina&#x2014;&#x2014;I forget her surname, like something eatable, I know."</p>				<p>"Patti," Melville murmurs, putting up his handkerchief to hide an irrepressible smile.</p>				<p>"Yes, Patty&#x2014;I knew it was something that went with oysters or shrimps. Well, Claire, though I say it, is just the girl to make you an excellent wife. You know now <pb n="137"/>the money you would get with her, and as both the old lady and you are rather short just now, I advise you to think over the matter, and let me know what you decide. Good-night, my lord. I hope I haven't said anything that was not my duty towards my daughter&#x2014;if I have, you must put it down to my being a home bird and unused to grand society."</p>				<p>"Good-night, Mrs. Delaval," and then he turns towards Claire a bored face.</p>				<p>"By Jove!" he says.</p>				<p>Two little words, but they contain a very great deal.</p>				<p>Claire covers her face with her hands and gives a real sob. The sob is from rage, but he puts it down to sheer humiliation at the maternal parent's outspoken remarks and he pities her; but that is all. <pb n="138"/>There is no intention or desire on his part for a warm scene number two. Nay, he walks over to a far window, and pushing aside the lace curtains, looks out at the starry night.</p>				<p>He is thoroughly perplexed as to his future action. If he repudiates a marriage with Claire, all chance of seeing Cecil will be denied him, and he <hi rend="italic">cannot</hi> risk that. Absorbed in his thoughts, he does not even hear Claire's soft footfall on the thick carpet, and the first intimation of her proximity is an ice-cold hand on his, and a low voice close to his ear.</p>				<p>"You won't let my mother's shortcomings prejudice you against me, Lord Melville!" it pleads." Heaven knows how shocked I am at her words. Oh, think what I must feel to be held up as <pb n="139"/>an article of exchange and barter. Think of the shame of being flung at your head when&#x2014;when you do not even care for me, perhaps!"</p>				<p>He turns round from his star-gazing, and by the gesture disengages his hand from hers; her touch seems to burn a hole in his flesh. His hand belongs to Cecil, and the man has really a refined and loyal nature that shrinks from any action or word now that his betrothed would be pained by.</p>				<p>"Let us sit down and talk this matter over quietly," he says, and Claire obeys.</p>				<p>"One word I beg! It is no reason because my mother has chosen from a misguided notion of duty, to offer me to you, that you should think I am an aider and abettor in her course of action. <pb n="140"/>Surely, <hi rend="italic">surely</hi> you acquit me of such a thing! I <hi rend="italic">have</hi> hoped, fondly hoped ever since <hi rend="italic">that evening</hi>, that our relations would have been more friendly than they are, but that hope has been only in my heart, I have never breathed it to living soul! Exonerate me, I implore you, from blame, and <hi rend="italic">feel</hi> for me that my mother is one of whom I cannot be&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">proud!</hi>"</p>				<p>She says it all meekly, humbly, and he <hi rend="italic">does</hi> feel for her. It must be terrible for a lady-like girl to have a mother like Mrs. Delaval.</p>				<p>"I do exonerate you!" he answers earnestly. "I am quite sure that nothing but delicacy of feeling could emanate from anyone like you. And I admire you, but, as I said before, who wouldn't? Will you <pb n="141"/>forgive me for what passed that evening? Will you try and forget it? I swear to you on my honour that it was not deliberate on my part. Your face&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">you</hi>&#x2014;tempted me to an unworthy advantage, and I was powerless to resist! But you do not know how I have repented of an action which must have condemned me in your eyes&#x2014;you could never guess how <hi rend="italic">dreadfully</hi> sorry I am for words which circumstances at present render it impossible to carry out into facts! Miss Delaval, will you be merciful to that one unfortunate departure from a rule I have made in my life since I became a pauper, if I promise you that I will never offend again? There are things one would dearly like to possess, but poverty prevents me," he adds with a smile.</p>				<pb n="142"/>				<p>"Yes, but you need not be poor," she breaks in hastily and unadvisedly.</p>				<p>He looks at her gravely.</p>				<p>"Ah, yes, I know; but though I am poor&#x2014;poor as the traditional church rat&#x2014;I could not make up my mind to sell myself, not even for thirty thousand a year! But you have not told me yet if you forgive that other night&#x2014;if you will forget it?"</p>				<p>"I forgive, if there is anything to forgive," she replies in a voice full of pathos, "but I cannot promise to&#x2014;forget!" and tears of disappointment rush to her eyes.</p>				<p>"Come!" he says, "don't let anything so paltry as a passing flirtation dim those pretty eyes. It was very nice, but very wrong, but the man you marry will not <pb n="143"/>know of it. After all, <hi rend="italic">you</hi> are not to blame&#x2014;if, in the bewilderment of the moment, I robbed you of a caress which was but a natural tribute to such beauty as yours! Miss Delaval&#x2014;Claire, why should we not be friends&#x2014;if to be lovers is denied us? Do not harden your heart against me, but believe that, under other circumstances, I should have had no dearer wish than to make you my wife!"</p>				<p>She listens to it all, and her spirit does not sink or her eyes weep more, for the innate vanity of her nature tells her that this man does care for her, but is too proud to marry a woman richer than himself. She resolves to marry him some day when, by dint of her fascinations, his scruples will be overcome. Meanwhile, she will wait patiently.</p>				<pb n="144"/>				<p>He speaks again.</p>				<p>"Well! Won't you shake hands and be friends as the children say? <hi rend="italic">Do</hi>," and he holds out his hand with one of the rare smiles that make his mouth as tender as a woman's.</p>				<p>Claire looks up at him. She remembers Ferrari's eyes, the liquid eyes, dark as midnight, soft as velvet, and she shudders away from the memory, as the deep blue eyes of this man smile down on her. Under their thrall she would do anything!</p>				<p>So she puts out five white fingers that tremble a little and Melville clasps them for a moment.</p>				<p>"Is it to be peace?" he asks.</p>				<p>"An armistice rather," she answers.</p>			</div>			<pb n="145"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER IX<lb/>A PAIR OF LOVERS</head>				<lg>					<l>"Yea&#x2014;if I could&#x2014;would I have you see</l>					<l>My very love of you filling me</l>					<l>And know my soul to the quick?"</l>				</lg>				<p>CECIL is quite content to be here, her head on his shoulder, her hands in his clasp, and infinite love in her heart&#x2014;love as fervent and intense as a southern clime, but as pure as England's undriven snow. Here&#x2014;far away from the buzz and din of a town, in the deep peace and stillness of the country, with no sound save that of fluttering leaves and murmuring water, and no witness save the birds and the butterflies.</p>				<pb n="146"/>				<p>Cecil has fallen into a delightful waking dream. In fancy she kneels beside Melville in a grand old church with satin and lace trailing around her and a crown of orange blossoms on her sunny hair, while the song of the wild birds high on the trees sounds like a nuptial hymn. Melville rouses her from love's young dream.</p>				<p>"What are you thinking of, little one?" he asks, a little dreamily himself&#x2014;for as he looks down on the fair young face of his love, an inexpressible happiness steals over him&#x2014;while the green leaves rustle softly on the imperial elms as if they murmur a tender welcome to the sweet wooing of the fickle wind, and just away to the left a few pale holy stars begin to peep at one another in the sky, blinking and winking as if in shyness.</p>				<pb n="147"/>				<p>She tells her dream in a whisper.</p>				<p>"Dreams often come by contraries," he says on the spur of the moment, then he repents of his words when he sees her face whiten and her eyes cloud over.</p>				<p>And a tinge of sadness may be traced on his own brow. But it is not to be wondered at, for he is going to leave her. This is a tryst stolen with difficulty, while Claire believes he has gone into Exeter to see Lord Barrington, an old schoolfellow of his.</p>				<p>Melville feels that he cannot well continue a guest at High Towers after Mrs. Delaval's conversation a week or two ago, but he has not broached the subject of his departure yet, dreading the time when Cecil and he will be parted, <pb n="148"/>and wondering when facilities will be found for meeting again.</p>				<p>The time passes unconsciously to the lovers, for lovers they are in the true sense of the word, and the moon rises behind a large fleecy cloud, and its silver light falls through the interlacing boughs, forming a carpet of diamonds for their feet, and bathing them in liquid lustre.</p>				<p>A subtle scent of pines comes on the wings of the western breeze&#x2014;the birds begin to sleepily twitter&#x2014;the breath of wood violets sweeps by, and all is pleasant and peaceful except Melville's heart.</p>				<p>He loves Cecil devotedly, but their future looks very dark.</p>				<p>Cecil looks up into his face and notices at once the shadow on it.</p>				<p>"What is it, Alan?" she questions <pb n="149"/>quickly, "are you unhappy, or is it our love that troubles you? If so, forget that you have told me you care for me&#x2014;and&#x2014;and I'll never blame you or reproach you!"</p>				<p>"Silly child! Your love is my dearest possession&#x2014;I only wish that I was a rich man, so as to be able to surround my darling with all that wealth can purchase, but I am very poor, Cecil! Do you mind that?"</p>				<p>"I want nothing but you," she whispers. "Was it because we shall be poor that you looked so sad just now?"</p>				<p>"No," he answers, trying to throw a whole throng of unpleasant thoughts from him in a faint sigh. "If a shadow was on my face, it came from that black cloud over there."</p>				<pb n="150"/>				<p>Cecil starts.</p>				<p>"Don't say that!" she falters nervously. "I had an old Italian nurse once, and she told me that when a black cloud suddenly veils the pale face of the moon it is an omen sorrow will come to those who look up at it."</p>				<p>Melville is essentially a practical man, there is nothing very dreamy or poetic in his nature, so he laughs at her fancies and kisses away the quiver on her mouth.</p>				<p>"Tropical imaginations are infinitely more fertile than those of a colder clime, my pet&#x2014;and look, the augury does not hurt us, for there sails Madame Diana without one modest speck to veil her from our profane gaze!"</p>				<p>"Heaven grant you are right," she answers in a low voice.</p>				<pb n="151"/>				<p>"Keep up a brave spirit always, my own! No one will be able to part us. So long as you care for me and keep true to me, all will go well. I may have to go away soon, Cecil."</p>				<p>					<hi rend="italic">"Go away!"</hi>				</p>				<p>Her heart sinks like a stone&#x2014;her breath comes quick and uneven. Her face, even to her lips, grows deathly white&#x2014;and her little hands tremble so, that even his warm grasp cannot still them.</p>				<p>"Only for a little while, dear love! I shall come back soon&#x2014;I must&#x2014;I could not live now without seeing you, and kissing you! You must not fret, darling, but think of me always and look forward to the blessed day when we shall never have to part again!"</p>				<pb n="152"/>				<p>"Bell, it is for myself, my very own self, that he loves me! Had I possessed money I might have a doubt&#x2014;that is, if anyone could be so wicked as to doubt <hi rend="italic">him</hi>. But I am sure&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">sure</hi> that he loves me as much as I love him! Bell, <hi rend="italic">do</hi> tell me if it is all real! Did you think he would ever give me a thought even? That day when we saw him and Claire riding together&#x2014;did you ever, <hi rend="italic">ever</hi> dream that he would love <hi rend="italic">me</hi>?"</p>				<p>"Yes, I <hi rend="italic">felt</hi>it was you," Bell says in her outspoken fashion.</p>				<p>"But I ought not to have met him so, it seems just as if I had put myself in his way."</p>				<p>"As he does not seem to think it was wrong, you need not be unhappy."</p>				<p>"Unhappy, Bell!" and Cecil laughs a <pb n="153"/>bright silvery laugh. "It appears to me that there is no such thing as unhappiness in the world!"</p>				<p>"Cis, have you told Lord Melville what I wanted you to tell?" Bell asks, in a solemn little voice, and her face is very grave.</p>				<p>"About what? Do you mean about Claire not liking me, and wishing to keep me in the background? No, there's time enough for that when we have nothing pleasanter to talk about&#x2014;but when will that be, I wonder?" she says, with a radiant smile. "You look very serious, Bell, darling. What is it?"</p>				<p>"Nothing&#x2014;only I was thinking."</p>				<p>"About what?"</p>				<p>"Does Lord Melville intend to tell Claire that he is engaged to you?"</p>				<pb n="154"/>				<p>"Perhaps. Why should he conceal anything?"</p>				<p>"Cis! She loves him!"</p>				<p>The words fall like a thunderbolt on Cecil's ear, and her pulses seem to stand still.</p>				<p>"Oh, Bell, don't say that, for mercy's sake!"</p>				<p>"It is the chatter of the house, Cis. I have watched them too unseen&#x2014;and&#x2014;"</p>				<p>"Yes!"</p>				<p>Cecil's breath comes in a little gasp, a dreadful, dreadful feeling creeps over her which she does not understand herself. Other and more experienced women might know it is a feeling of incipient jealousy&#x2014;jealousy which is "cruel as the grave."</p>				<p>"Claire is very clever, Cis!"</p>				<pb n="155"/>				<p>"I know&#x2014;but if she is?"</p>				<p>"As I said before, Claire loves Lord Melville. She is very beautiful, and I have read that beauty has great power."</p>				<p>Cecil remembers the hateful black cloud of the evening before that veiled the moon.</p>				<p>Oh, can there be any truth in the Italian superstition? she wonders. She turns so faint that for a moment she cannot speak.</p>				<p>"What could Claire do, Bell?" she asks at last, in a low, husky tone, very different to the bright ringing voice of half-an-hour back.</p>				<p>"How can anyone tell what someone who is not very good can do?" Bell answers with the wisdom that drops from the mouths of babes and sucklings.</p>				<pb n="156"/>				<p>"How you frighten me," Cecil cries, her heart beating fast. "I was so happy, so happy&#x2014;and now! How can I guard against evil? But surely Claire could not be so cruel as to come between me and&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">him!</hi> What can I do?"</p>				<p>"Keep everything secret."</p>				<p>"But how?"</p>				<p>"Easy enough. There is the old way of seeing him, if you must see him."</p>				<p>"Yes, yes, I <hi rend="italic">must</hi> see him! I cannot live without."</p>				<p>"Ask Lord Melville not to breathe a word about you!"</p>				<p>"I can't do that without giving a reason. He would think me deceitful, underhand. But what have I to fear after all? What <hi rend="italic">could</hi> happen so long as he loves me? He is big enough and strong <pb n="157"/>enough to hold his own and fight my battles too!"</p>				<p>Cecil laughs and blushes, and running to her own room, brings back the cherished picture of her early school days.</p>				<p>"Look, Bluebell! Who is Bayard&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">sans Peur et sans reproche</hi>&#x2014;like?"</p>				<p>It is really a striking likeness. There are the same grave eyes, the straight features, the close clustering hair, the tall, stately figure.</p>				<p>"Don't you see the resemblance, Bell?"</p>				<p>"It is like Lord Melville."</p>				<p>"Call him Alan, 'Lord Melville' is so formal, and he will soon be your cousin, you know."</p>				<p>"I <hi rend="italic">couldn't</hi>call him Alan," the girl says shyly, "at least not for a very long while."</p>				<p>But Cecil scarcely hears her. She gazes <pb n="158"/>at "Bayard" adoringly, and is so full of her own happiness.</p>				<p>"His love is a sufficient shield. No one could do me an injury now, and if Claire is beautiful&#x2014;well&#x2014;I must be beautiful too, for you know, Bell, no one hardly can tell us apart."</p>				<p>"<hi rend="italic">I</hi> could. I could tell it by instinct, if I was blindfold," Bell replies, in her queer way.</p>				<p>"How?"</p>				<p>"Because I could <hi rend="italic">feel</hi> the difference of good and evil."</p>				<p>"I believe it is your love for me that makes you anxious, darling Bell."</p>				<p>"It maybe&#x2014;anyway, it's no use making you worried and unhappy. I have made you so already, I am afraid."</p>				<p>"No! I <hi rend="italic">can't</hi> be unhappy, a little while <pb n="159"/>ago I had nothing to lose&#x2014;to day I have nothing to gain, so long as my Bayard cares for me. In Alan's love, Heaven has given me everything."</p>				<p>"And if Claire takes it away from you?</p>				<p>"Hush! For God's sake, don't say such words, it would be <hi rend="italic">death</hi>, I believe!" she whispers, with pallid cheeks and quivering mouth.</p>				<p>"Do you care for him so very much then?" Bell asks, tremulously clasping her mites of hands in her agitation.</p>				<p>"A little while ago, I could not have told you how much I care for him, for I did not know he gave me a thought&#x2014;I felt so dreadfully ashamed of the love I had allowed to spring up, unchecked and even encouraged. But now I need not mind, <pb n="160"/>though I feel the blood rush into my face even when I think of him. I love Alan better than my life, Bluebell, for what would life be without him?"</p>				<p>"Love is a very strange thing," Bell thinks to herself, as a little later she lies hidden away on a rustic bench, behind a big group of laurustinus. "I wonder whether, when Lord Melville talks, Cis feels hot and cold, as if&#x2014;as if she was being carried away on angels' wings to Heaven&#x2014;just as I did when Lohengrin was singing that night. Shall I never hear him again, I wonder?" she says half aloud.</p>				<p>Her voice is curiously wistful, her little face grows sorrowful, but in a moment she rises hastily and flies towards the house.</p>				<p>"I'll ask Cis to let <hi rend="italic">me</hi> speak to Lord Melville. I hope she will, for I am sure&#x2014;<pb n="161"/>					<hi rend="italic">sure</hi> that if Claire finds out anything she will do something dreadful and break Cis's heart&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>Meanwhile, Claire has locked herself up in her room&#x2014;she walks up and down with her hands so tightly clenched that the nails hurt the soft white flesh. She loves Melville so much that to win him she believes she could commit any crime. A certain success, she thinks, has already crowned her efforts to gain his heart and, in spite of the past, the irremediable past, she swears to herself that happiness and content shall be hers.</p>				<p>Who knows, save herself, of the marriage in an out-of-the-way Brussels faubourg&#x2014;a mockery of a marriage, she calls it now. She is safe as far as Ferrari is concerned&#x2014;for months. In those <pb n="162"/>months she will win the man she adores, and once "Lady Melville," who will believe a poor foreigner&#x2014;a miserable singing-master&#x2014;if he swears over and over again&#x2014;that she is his wife?</p>				<p>It is a cruel fate that places in such a woman's hands the bliss or misery of Cecil's life.</p>				<p>But it is not the first time, nor will it be the last, that the daughters of Heth wield a successful warfare with their better and purer sisterhood.</p>			</div>			<pb n="163"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER X<lb/>"SHE WILL TROUBLE YOU NO MORE"</head>				<lg>					<l>"Si tu savais comme je t'aime,</l>					<l>Bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;tu m'aimerais!"</l>				</lg>				<p>"'BIEN <hi rend="italic">s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;tu m'aimerais!'</hi> Always the same old refrain, Marco. You'll go off your head, if you don't look out."</p>				<p>Deep in reverie, Marco starts as Prince Maurice Spagnoletti enters the room, and sits down opposite him. The man has altered terribly since Spagnoletti saw him three months ago. A strange, dreamy, abstracted look has settled on his dark eyes, and a white line of pain goes round his mouth, and has grown habitual to it. Even in the pauses of conversation his <pb n="164"/>spirit seems to wander away far from the present.</p>				<p>He likes to sit and brood, he loves to be by himself. Claire's face is always beside him, her eyes look into his own, her voice sounds on his ear like the echo of some music he had revelled in years and years ago.</p>				<p>Marco has a nature unlike most men's. He is steadfast and loyal unto death, and though he has been driven like chaff before the wind, by the caprice of a heartless woman, though he has suffered torture by her long silence, her curious concealment of her whereabouts, the woman he considers his wife in the eyes of God has never fallen from the niche in his breast where he placed her to love and worship for ever and ever. He has never spoken of her, <pb n="165"/>save to his best friend and old schoolfellow, Spagnoletti; even to him he has been somewhat reticent, and Spagnoletti, believing that speaking of the subject nearest Marco's heart will be a relief to him, reverts at once to it.</p>				<p>"Marco, you have never really told me about your masquerading at Brussels. All I understand is that you carried out your romantic programme of looking for a <hi rend="italic">rara avis</hi>&#x2014;otherwise, a woman, young, beautiful, and above all, disinterested! Well? You succeeded?"</p>				<p>"Yes! I found her&#x2014;a girl with an angel's face, with a child's guileless spirit, with a woman's loving heart. Maurice, I swear to you she is so good, so pure, so different to any other woman I have known, that the very caresses I laid on her lips <pb n="166"/>brought with them a feeling of self-reproach. It seemed like desecration to me! We loved one another&#x2014;we met often alone. She was guarded only by her innocence and the reverence I had for her&#x2014;the reverence I would give to a saint. Yet&#x2014;she left me as pure as she was the first moment I looked on her. True, I married her, believing it would bind her more closely to me, that the knowledge she was my wife would keep her true; but it was really a marriage in name only and an informal marriage&#x2014;for our faiths are different, and no Protestant church ratified our vows. Well&#x2014;&#x2014;!"</p>				<p>He pauses.</p>				<p>"She left you, telling you where to find her in England?"</p>				<p>The red blood surges over the other man's face.</p>				<pb n="167"/>				<p>"No! You see she is under age. Her people are poor, and anxious she should make a good marriage."</p>				<p>"Good marriage! and are not you good enough? English parents must have odd notions on the subject if your position and name are not high enough for a middle-class girl, or even a 'daughter of a hundred earls'!"</p>				<p>"Yes&#x2014;but Claire does not know more about me than that I was singing-master at the school, and that I worked for my bread! I wanted her to love me for <hi rend="italic">myself</hi>, and so she did!"</p>				<p>"She would have loved you ten times as much if she had known all about you! Women are wonderfully interested creatures&#x2014;you don't know them as I do!"</p>				<pb n="168"/>				<p>"<hi rend="italic">She</hi> is not interested&#x2014;or why did she bind herself by marrying me&#x2014;knowing me to be a nobody?"</p>				<p>"Well&#x2014;go on&#x2014;your wife left you&#x2014;haven't you seen her since?"</p>				<p>"Yes, we met by accident in London&#x2014;she was more lovely and loving than ever, she promised to tell her father and mother of our love, and to ask their consent to our marriage; poor child&#x2014;of course she dared not tell them that half a marriage already existed. She is very young and timid. And she made me promise that I would wait patiently till she wrote to me to come. I have waited patiently&#x2014;but&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>He pauses again and Spagnoletti sees his cheek grow white and a tortured look steal into his eyes.</p>				<pb n="169"/>				<p>"And have you heard from Madame lately?"</p>				<p>Marco does not answer for a moment&#x2014;then he says in a hoarse voice:</p>				<p>"Yes, a few days ago."</p>				<p>"And what does she say!"</p>				<p>"Oh, Maurice, you torture me. Man! do you know what it is to long for a thing&#x2014;to yearn for a presence night and day&#x2014;to live only for another sight of the face that has bewitched you? And to know that an accursed promise keeps you to a living death! I heard from my wife a few days ago&#x2014;she tells me her people will not hear of our love for each other, that I must wait&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">wait</hi> till she is of age&#x2014;for thirteen months, and then our marriage shall be completed without their consent. Heaven bless her for <pb n="170"/>saying that. It is all the consolation I have."</p>				<p>"Thirteen months&#x2014;it's a long probation to give a man! Take my advice, Marco. As you have given your word to wait and not to go to her till the given date, you must keep it. But do not lead this life&#x2014;you are ruining your health, and eating your heart out&#x2014;for what?&#x2014;for a woman who has not the real stuff in her&#x2014;a woman who hesitates between the husband she loves, and the fear of braving her family's wrath!&#x2014;or if you cannot live without her save in this wretched condition of heart and brain, sit down and write to her father and mother&#x2014;tell them who you are, and&#x2014;I am a poor man, Marco, but I'll bet you half my income that they will not only consent to their daughter being your wife, but will <pb n="171"/>kill the fatted calf in celebration of the wedding!"</p>				<p>"I cannot do that even if I would&#x2014;I do not know where to find her."</p>				<p>"But she wrote to you&#x2014;was there no address?"</p>				<p>"Only a post-office in some English town, and she was leaving in a few days."</p>				<p>Spagnoletti shrugs his shoulders, and walking up to the window begins whistling softly.</p>				<p>"Don't, Maurice, I <hi rend="italic">can't</hi> forget while I hear that song."</p>				<p>"What song? Good Heavens, is the accursed song running in my head too? Beg pardon, <hi rend="italic">mon ami</hi>, I did not know what I was whistling, but why have those words such an attraction for you? When I <pb n="172"/>came here before, <hi rend="italic">'Bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;bien s&#x00FB;r&#x2014;tu m'aimerais,'</hi> saluted my ears."</p>				<p>"It is the first song I taught <hi rend="italic">her</hi>. She sang it at first coldly, as if the words had no meaning for her. It was I who taught her what love was&#x2014;she had, like Undine, no soul&#x2014;no man's power had touched a chord of her being till she saw me and then!&#x2014;my God, Maurice! Is not life&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">Heaven</hi>&#x2014;when a man and a woman love one another&#x2014;utterly? When, absorbed in one another&#x2014;they forget that aught else exists save themselves in the whole world?"</p>				<p>"Marco! does there happen to be any one in Florence who has caught your fancy at all? Anyone, loving, lovely, who could make you forget the past and brighten up the present?"</p>				<p>Marco laughs. Such a laugh it is&#x2014;with <pb n="173"/>utter desolation and weariness running through it&#x2014;even to listen to it makes the other man's heart grow sick.</p>				<p>It is a laugh that is born of disbelief in one's kind, that comes from thorough hopelessness.</p>				<p>"You don't really know me, Maurice. No woman living&#x2014;were she lovely as Venus, pure as an angel&#x2014;could make me forget the time which was the nearest approach to Heaven that a man can reach&#x2014;no woman&#x2014;not one&#x2014;could fill Claire's place&#x2014;ay&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">shall</hi> fill the place&#x2014;which is hers while I live! But why ask such a question?&#x2014;you must know I am in no humour for banter now."</p>				<p>"I asked because I hoped there was such a woman, and if there was, I should say to you with all my heart&#x2014;go in and <pb n="174"/>win! Thrust all care and trouble from you&#x2014;throw memory to the four winds&#x2014;for the cloud that has shadowed your life has a rift in it. Life will wear rosy colours once more, for you are a&#x2014;free man!"</p>				<p>"A free man?" echoes Marco dreamily.</p>				<p>"Yes&#x2014;a free man&#x2014;for <hi rend="italic">she</hi> will trouble you no more!"</p>				<p>"Trouble me no more! What do you mean, Maurice?"</p>				<p>"That Madame knows her marriage with a singing-master was informal, and she will never claim you as her husband! I am a man of the world, and I have had a good deal of experience about the sex. No&#x2014;don't look as if you were going to murder me, Marco&#x2014;one must open the wound to heal it&#x2014;and I tell you again that no woman would write as your wife has <pb n="175"/>written, if she loved you one whit! Take my word for it, she is not what your romantic fancy has painted, or, for her own suffering's sake, she could not live without letting you know all that is in her heart&#x2014;without hearing all that is in yours!"</p>				<p>"If you were anyone else, Maurice, I should fling you out of my door for daring to impugn my dear one's truth and loyalty. To you I say, let this matter be a sealed book between us. I know you mean it for my good, that you feel my trouble almost as if it were your own, but, Maurice, you do not know her. Only one word more&#x2014;never, I beseech you, desecrate my love for my wife, by speaking to me of another woman!"</p>				<p>When Spagnoletti is gone, Marco sinks <pb n="176"/>back in his chair and covers his face with his hands. A long, long time he remains thus&#x2014;the conversation with his friend has raked up each incident of his love episode. In spite of himself Spagnoletti's words have raised a doubt of Claire's affection, and cruel thoughts make him dizzy and faint. Suddenly he jumps up and, going to the buffet, pours out half a tumbler of brandy which he drinks to the dregs. A little later he runs down the stairs whistling: "Il balen del suo sorroso."and goes on his way to dine with il Duca Rutiano and Spagnoletti at the Caff&#x00E9; di Roma</p>			</div>			<pb n="177"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTER XI<lb/>BLUEBELL'S MISSION</head>				<lg>					<l>"List all who love and choose him</l>					<l>See love, and so refuse him,</l>					<l>For all who find him lose him,</l>					<l>But all have found him fair."</l>				</lg>				<p>BLUEBELL is the quaintest and most original of mortals&#x2014;a child almost in years and looks, but with the dreamy temperament of one double her age. But in spite of her dreaminess, her love of fairy lore and flowers and nightingales, she has a deal of "character." She is faithful to tenacity in her attachments, as true as steel in her nature and loyal to the backbone.</p>				<p>She adores Cecil, she would starve for <pb n="178"/>her without one murmuring word. Cecil is the one perfect human creature she knows except her father. Cecil is a lily of purity, a star of beauty, and to serve her Bell would walk barefooted to the end of the world.</p>				<p>Now in the full swing and security of a first passion, Cecil firmly looks on Melville as a very tower of strength, but with a strange prescience of evil, which often goes hand in hand with original temperaments. Bell resolves to settle matters for herself. Her unparalleled devotion to her cousin and her utter distrust of Claire aggravates her presentiments into positive fear, and goads her to immediate action. So tossing on her hat carelessly, without so much as a look at herself in the glass, she steps down to the grounds in the dusk, so as to <pb n="179"/>waylay Melville when he takes his ordinary stroll with his cigar an hour before dinner.</p>				<p>She has not long to wait. He emerges from the laurustinus path and starts as the little slender figure bars his progress. Bell looks like a spirit in the gloaming, her face is very pale and her great eyes shine like a couple of stars.</p>				<p>"I have come," she says catching her breath, "because I want to ask a favour of you, Lord Melville."</p>				<p>"Do you? Ask away then; there is nothing on earth I would not grant you, Miss Bluebell, but first let us sit down here," and he points to a rustic bench under a weeping ash, the long trails of which almost hide it from view.</p>				<p>"Cecil has told me of&#x2014;&#x2014;" she pauses <pb n="180"/>shyly&#x2014;love to her is such a sacred thing, that she feels like a little traitor to Cecil when she alludes to her engagement.</p>				<p>"Cecil has told you I love her very dearly; there is no secret in that, so you need not hesitate."</p>				<p>"That is just what I have come to ask; will you let it be a secret from everybody, especially from my sister?"</p>				<p>Melville stares a little in perplexity, and to say the truth he is not over-pleased. Bell has taken his fancy especially by her apparent honesty of purpose and free, outspoken ways, which are yet innocent as a child's, and now the little thing's words savour of mystery.</p>				<p>For a moment his old cynicism returns to him and he believes that all women are alike&#x2014;a mass of deception.</p>				<pb n="181"/>				<p>"Have you come as a messenger from Cecil? Does she desire all this extraordinary secrecy?" he asks in a cold voice.</p>				<p>Bell catches the inflection in his tone and loyally hastens to reinstate Cis in his good opinion, at all hazard to herself.</p>				<p>"No! oh no. I asked her permission, or rather I begged her to write to you and make the request before you saw Claire at dinner to-night&#x2014;but Cis wouldn't."</p>				<p>"Why not?"</p>				<p>"Because she hates deceit and concealment. She is an angel and she cannot believe in wickedness."</p>				<p>"Then why should you ask it? I am sure <hi rend="italic">you</hi> don't know anything about the wicked ways of the world. Tell me your <pb n="182"/>reason for wishing me to hide that which I really glory in."</p>				<p>"I <hi rend="italic">can't</hi> explain, and you would not understand if I did. I know that your happiness as well as Cecil's depends on it."</p>				<p>"What a queer young person you are, Miss Bluebell! and a sphinx as well, for I can't even guess anything from your face. But do you know that never in my life have I found any good come out of a secret, and you see <hi rend="italic">I</hi> have lived years and years."</p>				<p>She glances at him and shakes her head. He does not look very old in spite of his years and years. His close, crisp hair has no single line of silver, and his brow is as smooth as an infant's.</p>				<p>She is evidently not much impressed by <pb n="183"/>the superiority of age or the superiority of his wisdom at this moment.</p>				<p>"True, upon my honour," he goes on, "there is nothing like open-handed dealing and straightforward ways; a secretive nature is horrid in my opinion, and a secret is a very bad thing."</p>				<p>"What has this attachment sprung from but a lot of secret meetings?" she asks with a mischievous laugh.</p>				<p>Melville laughs too. He rather likes being posed by this bit of a girl, with her little white face and solemn blue eyes that seem to go straight as an arrow into the very soul of the person she addresses.</p>				<p>There is something comical yet weird about her. And yet she is marvellously pretty, with her delicate features and her fragile look.</p>				<pb n="184"/>				<p>"There was a reason for the meetings being secret," he says.</p>				<p>"I know. It was because you could not talk to Cecil before Claire, without vexing my sister."</p>				<p>"Exactly, and under the circumstances it was reason sufficient, for I did not wish Cecil to have hard things said to her, but now that I have made up my mind to marry Cecil whenever she will marry me, I care nothing about giving offence."</p>				<p>"Anyway, Claire has no right to your confidence," she flashes out with an impetuosity which seems strange in her.</p>				<p>"But she is Cecil's cousin&#x2014;and besides, my dear old friend Delaval ought to be told at once."</p>				<p>"Oh, Lord Melville, I beg of you to let <pb n="185"/>the thing remain a secret for the present at any rate. Papa never interferes much in family matters. He is out so much, you know, and besides, he is quite under Claire's rule like the rest of us. Do believe me, that it is far better for you and Cis to keep your own counsel."</p>				<p>"But everything must be made known soon&#x2014;I can't be kept out of my happiness long. I would do anything to oblige you, but I must tell you that there are reasons&#x2014;powerful reasons," and Melville looks red and uncomfortable, "why Miss Delaval should know of my engagement to Cecil!"</p>				<p>Bell throws a queer glance at him.</p>				<p>"I understand!" she says.</p>				<p>"You?"</p>				<p>"Yes."</p>				<pb n="186"/>				<p>"Of course you do. I begin to think you are a cross between a witch and a snowdrop. And what are my reasons?"</p>				<p>"May I say?"</p>				<p>"By all means."</p>				<p>"You won't be angry?"</p>				<p>"I couldn't be angry with you."</p>				<p>"Well, then, Claire thinks you have no right to care for Cis. She is so beautiful, and is going to be so rich some day, that she believes all men must fall in love with her&#x2014;and I suppose many do!"</p>				<p>He colours again, and for the life of him feels like a culprit under the girl's clear, truthful eyes, and he thanks Providence that she does not know the full measure of his folly, the madness that had crossed his life.</p>				<pb n="187"/>				<p>"I may tell you one thing, Lord Melville, that Cis has never been treated kindly by Claire."</p>				<p>"In what way?"</p>				<p>"Every way. Claire dislikes her, and is jealous of her. When she hears that Cis has won your liking, her rage will be too awful."</p>				<p>"The girl who is to be my wife must be afraid of no one!" he says, with all the proud blood of the Melvilles flashing in his eyes. "<hi rend="italic">I</hi> will take care that no one <hi rend="italic">dares</hi> to vex her."</p>				<p>"Men don't war with women, you know! Claire will make you feel her anger, too."</p>				<p>"I think you are a little hard on your sister. She is certainly as beautiful a girl as ever walked the earth, and perhaps this <pb n="188"/>makes her imperious, but she never speaks unkindly of Cecil&#x2014;she never mentions her, in fact."</p>				<p>"Of course, she would like never to see Cecil or hear of her again."</p>				<p>"Hush! You are quite a baby yet, or you would have learnt the wisdom of never letting your feelings run into unfounded prejudices. Eemember she is your sister."</p>				<p>Bluebell rises quietly from the bench and pulls her hat over her eyes, and he can see that she is half crying from disappointment.</p>				<p>"I thought it best to come," she murmurs sorrowfully. "I hoped you would listen to my words, but I haven't done a bit of good."</p>				<p>"Don't look so dreadfully <hi rend="italic">triste</hi>. You <pb n="189"/>have, at any rate, done no harm. How earnest you are about your request."</p>				<p>"And yet you won't grant it!" she says, looking up at him with big, wistful eyes.</p>				<p>"I <hi rend="italic">would</hi> grant it, but I do not think I should be justified in passing here as a free man, when I belong absolutely heart and hand to Cecil. It appears to me somewhat in the light of dishonour and treachery to Miss Delaval."</p>				<p>"Still and still, I beg of you not to mention this matter. I know you will be glad by-and-bye for Cecil's sake."</p>				<p>"I'll think over it, and speak to Cecil to-morrow. Will you tell her to be sure and meet me near the waterfall&#x2014;I shall eat my heart out with disappointment if she does not come."</p>				<pb n="190"/>				<p>Bell glides away in the dusk, and he stands and watches her.</p>				<p>"Queer little girl, but as good and staunch as steel," he thinks, and he walks slowly towards the house. "It strikes me that the lovely Claire is not quite so saccharine as I fancied. I wonder why all this secrecy is required. Surely Cecil has nothing to be afraid of&#x2014;nothing that Miss Delaval could say against her could influence me! My little darling! If an angel came down from Heaven and told me you were not all my fancy paints you, I wouldn't believe it&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>"Do you know it is very late, Lord Melville?" a voice says from the stone steps. He cannot distinguish the form, but he knows the voice well enough. "What have you been doing&#x2014;taking a <pb n="191"/>stroll with anyone?" and there is a suggestion of suspicion in the tone.</p>				<p>"With my cigar," he answers carelessly. "I told Bell deceit was a bad thing!" he thinks.</p>			</div>			<pb n="192"/>			<div>				<head>CHAPTEE XII<lb/>BAYARD'S CONFESSION</head>				<epigraph>					<lg>						<l>"Mine arms are close about thine head,</l>						<l>My lips are fervent on thy face,</l>						<l>And where my kiss hath fed,</l>						<l>Thy flower-like blood leaps red</l>						<l>To the kissed place!"</l>					</lg>				</epigraph>				<p>CLAIRE is essentially vain, but not vain enough to persuade herself that Lord Melville is really in love with her. Her face, her voice, the hour&#x2014;all these had goaded him into a moment of folly, but she, who had been taught by Marco Ferrari what desperate love is, feels that if she ever becomes Countess of Melville, it will be by her own skill and <hi rend="italic">savoir faire</hi>. Notwithstanding her love affair, she is not <pb n="193"/>impervious to the charm of fine garments, and to-day she has that very important business on hand&#x2014;in most women's estimation&#x2014;a long interview with her dressmaker in Exeter. Taking a hasty breakfast she drives off to the station, and no sooner do Cecil and Bell find out she is gone, than they rush downstairs like a couple of children.</p>				<p>The day is deliciously fine, a soft breeze, yet in its babyhood, comes whispering through the elm branches, making their tall heads wave backwards and forwards like plumed warriors guarding the domain. The sky is clear as crystal, the flowers&#x2014;harbingers of summer&#x2014;send out great whiffs of perfume, in gratitude to Dame Nature for having made them so marvellously fair and sweet. Big dragon-flies <pb n="194"/>with filmy wings, flit like jewels from blossom to blossom, and altogether it is a wonderfully beautiful world&#x2014;so Cecil thinks as she surveys it through the rose-coloured spectacles that Cupid has slipped on her eyes.</p>				<p>The Honourable John sits at the breakfast-table. In one hand he holds the <hi rend="italic">Sporting Life</hi>&#x2014;the old companion of his bachelor days&#x2014;with the other he absently breaks off bits of toast, which instead of conveying to his mouth, he lays down again on his plate, while Bell&#x2014;taking advantage of his chronic condition&#x2014;steals the morsels for her pet sparrows.</p>				<lg>					<l>"Dust unto dust&#x2014;what must be must,</l>					<l>If you can't get crumbs&#x2014;you'd best eat crust,"</l>				</lg>				<p>she says laughing to one of her <hi rend="italic">passerine</hi> friends who perches tamely on the sill, <pb n="195"/>staring at her with a pair of wise little eyes.</p>				<p>The Honourable John has grown greyer and more wrinkled since he has become a rich man. He is not more sociable than of yore, and, with the exception of his niece and his youngest child, he seldom addresses anyone&#x2014;even Melville, favourite as he is with his host, sees little of him.</p>				<p>Bell, tired of ministering to the wants of the sparrows, steals up behind his chair, blindfolding him with her small hands. She is his pet, and, in Claire's absence, the two grow very demonstrative in their affections.</p>				<p>"Kiss me, Bell, and take your arms away&#x2014;you are strangling me, child."</p>				<p>"Only with affection," and she hugs him <pb n="196"/>closer. "Isn't it nice when Claire is away, papa?"</p>				<p>"Hush, she is your sister, little one, and Claire is a wonderful creature, and so handsome. Titian would have gone mad over her. I was thinking what a splendid couple she and Melville would make!"</p>				<p>Cecil who is hanging out of the open window, turns a white face round, and Bell frowns unmistakably.</p>				<p>"Is Lord Melville going to marry Claire?" she says.</p>				<p>"I don't know. Both your mother and I should like it, and it would be a first-rate match for him, as Claire will be so well off by and bye&#x2014;the Melvilles are so <hi rend="italic">very</hi> poor, you know."</p>				<p>"And is Lord Melville likely to sell himself?" Bell persists.</p>				<pb n="197"/>				<p>"Why not?&#x2014;if he cares for Claire. Of course, if he doesn't, he would be more interested and mercenary than I think him."</p>				<p>"I don't believe you know a thing about the matter, dear," Bell says positively. "You have heard mamma talk about it, and that's all. Now Cecil has gone upstairs, I'll tell you a secret. Papa, I hate keeping things from <hi rend="italic">you</hi>, but it is a real secret and you must promise faithfully to keep it."</p>				<p>"I promise, but stay a minute, I just want to see the betting on the Lincolnshire Handicap&#x2014;Grey Leg, Le Nicham, Victor Wild&#x2014;100 to 7, I'll have a couple of sovs on him&#x2014;well, puss, what's the secret?"</p>				<p>"Lord Melville is going to marry&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">Ceicl</hi>!"</p>				<pb n="198"/>				<p>"Cecil?"</p>				<p>"Yes."</p>				<p>"Won't your mother be angry?"</p>				<p>"Are you?"</p>				<p>"No, not a bit. It proves that I was right in thinking Melville an upright fellow, with no mercenary ideas. Cecil is a lucky young woman."</p>				<p>"Now remember it is a profound secret; don't let it out for goodness' sake in one of your absent fits!"</p>				<p>"No fear; I always do what you want, Bell. You <hi rend="italic">can't</hi> say I am a tyrannical parent."</p>				<p>"You are the dearest, best old parent in the world," she answers lovingly, with another big kiss, and then she runs off to find her cousin.</p>				<p>Cecil has sunk into an easy chair in her <pb n="199"/>own room. She has been crying her eyes out, and looks ashamed of herself as Bell comes in.</p>				<p>"Oh, Bell, you heard what Uncle John said! I feel a wretch&#x2014;a good-for-nothing wretch! How can I let him marry me, when I haven't a penny in the world, while he can marry Claire with all her money? And Uncle John said the Melvilles are so poor. It is base of me, selfish of me, Bell. I'll give him up. I shall never forgive myself if I stand in his way to wealth and the luxury he has been accustomed to, but it is hard&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">very</hi> hard," she says.</p>				<p>"Cis, I am surprised at you!" Bell says in a solemn voice. "Do you consider it right for a man to sell himself? No, and no more does Lord Melville. He has chosen between you and Claire, and I <pb n="200"/>think you are most ungrateful to Providence!"</p>				<p>Cecil dries her tears at this.</p>				<p>"Ungrateful! oh, if you only knew how grateful I am, how much I think of his goodness in caring for me! and I can give him nothing in return&#x2014;<hi rend="italic">nothing</hi> but my whole, whole heart."</p>				<p>"You have made your eyes red, and you don't look half as pretty as usual, and you have to meet him this evening, you know."</p>				<p>"I wonder if I am as pretty as Claire. I should like to be for <hi rend="italic">his</hi> sake," she murmurs passionately, "but you see Claire is so much more brilliant and fashionable. I wish I did not look so childish, perhaps I should have more power over his heart if I looked older."</p>				<pb n="201"/>				<p>"You have plenty of power over him, Cis, darling, and you must keep it; you must not throw him into Claire's hands, from silly ideas about your poverty, if you do you will ruin his happiness, for I know what Claire is. I <hi rend="italic">know</hi> she is not <hi rend="italic">true</hi>, Cis, and if a woman is not true, she is worth nothing."</p>				<p>Cecil grows more satisfied as she listens, and by and bye the two go out in the garden, and the fresh air removes the traces of tears from Cecil's face, and she looks lovelier than ever as she remembers that there is a delicious hour in prospect after the sun goes down.</p>				<p>"I was afraid you might not be able to come," Melville says, and there is such a <pb n="202"/>ring of happiness in his voice that Cecil <hi rend="italic">feels</hi> she is right in not giving him his freedom. "I have been out at the golf links all day, and so have not caught a glimpse even of my darling's face."</p>				<p>Cecil's heart thrills under his words, and she clasps his arm unconsciously closer to her, but he feels it and he stoops and kisses her.</p>				<p>"You <hi rend="italic">do</hi> love me, my sweet! I am <hi rend="italic">sure</hi> you do!"</p>				<p>To this she answers nothing, her heart is too full for words, but she looks up at him with such adoring eyes, that words are quite unnecessary.</p>				<p>Suddenly his glance falls on her right hand. The moon has risen, and its light touches the third finger, on <pb n="203"/>which a large opal burns and flashes prismatic hues.</p>				<p>"Why, what is this?" he asks, in surprise, seizing her hand rather roughly. Cecil is not given to jewellery, and this costly ring is very much out of place with her simple dress and child-like appearance.</p>				<p>"I found it," she says quietly. "I found it in a corner of a drawer this evening just before I came out. I thought perhaps it might belong to Lady Melville or some friend who had stayed with her. No one here owns it&#x2014;at least, I have never seen it before."</p>				<p>"Never?" he asks a little sternly." It is odd such a costly ring should be a waif, that no one should have made an effort to find it, No, it is <pb n="204"/>not my mother's, she eschews jewels of all sorts, and thinks them temptations to vanity sent by the Devil. Take it off, Cecil, and let me examine it properly."</p>				<p>She draws it off her finger at once, but something in his tone has made her nervous, and her features look agitated and her cheeks pale. He glances at her suspiciously. He strikes a fusee and regards the ring carefully.</p>				<p>"There is an 'M' on it," he says. "Strange&#x2014;but it is familiar to me&#x2014;the opal is of unusual size and shape, and the setting is Florentine. I have seen it&#x2014;or its double&#x2014;on Prince Colonna's finger, when I was in Italy three years ago. Strange how this ring comes here&#x2014;some rascally valet must have stolen it, and <pb n="205"/>been punished for his dishonesty by losing it!"</p>				<p>He gives her back the ring, saying, "Don't wear it," and she drops it into her pocket. Then Melville forgets about it, and begins talking of a thousand things that draw them into closer knowledge of each other.</p>				<p>"My heart went out straight to you, love," he says in a low voice which wears its softest accent now. "The first moment I saw you sealed my fate. But I ought to make a free confession of everything&#x2014;may I?"</p>				<p>She smiles in assent, and nestles closer to his shoulder.</p>				<p>"I did not wish to give way to the feelings you awoke in me&#x2014;I struggled against them even, for I felt that they were <pb n="206"/>against common-sense and self-interest. More than that, I knew my mother would be disappointed. You see, darling, I am a poor man, and money is a - great desideratum, so great a desideratum that I am ashamed to say I had fully made up my mind never to marry any but a wealthy woman, and when Delaval invited me here and suggested that he already liked me as a son, I had half a mind to try my chance wTith Claire Delaval. She is very beautiful, and more fascinating than most women, so that after all I ought not to have found my wooing very distasteful!"</p>				<p>Cecil turns away a shade further from him, and her little fingers relax their clasp, feeling which, Melville flings one arm round her, and with <pb n="207"/>just the shadow of a smile on his lips, goes on.</p>				<p>"At first, darling child&#x2014;may I tell you the whole, whole truth?"</p>				<p>She bends her head, and even by moonlight he can see the cruel crimson blood sweep right over the delicate face, and a dreadfully piteous quiver at the corners of her mouth.</p>				<p>"At first&#x2014;I am afraid&#x2014;I was rather taken by her, not, however, without a serious feeling of disappointment meeting me at every turn. She is wonderfully lovely and intelligent, but I like something more tender and womanly and refined, something at any rate, not quite so imperial and <hi rend="italic">prononc&#x00E9;e</hi>, even what the French call <hi rend="italic">bizarre</hi> at times. Still, if things had gone on as they commenced, <pb n="208"/>if I had never had that game of tennis, I dare say Mr. and Mrs. Delaval's wish might have been accomplished."</p>				<p>Cecil turns her face full upon him as he says this&#x2014;her face is still very white, and there is a mute question in her eyes.</p>				<p>Melville understands it perfectly. Poor little Cecil is jealous.</p>				<p>"Not because I loved her, you know, but from a wretched mercenary motive, and from the idea that people have that love is sure to come after marriage, provided one's wife is passably good-looking and not a shrew. But that game of tennis played the&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>"The what?" asks Cecil innocently.</p>				<p>"Don't be shocked, my lily&#x2014;the <hi rend="italic">Devil</hi>, I was going to say. I found that Delaval's niece was all my fancy painted a woman <pb n="209"/>should be, and I succumbed. Still the contest was rather a hard one; my dear proud old mother has but one desire on earth, it is to see High Towers in my possession once more, and I felt that my love for you was in absolute opposition to her wish, so I tried to resist the influence your sweet face had over me bravely for awhile. I flung myself recklessly into the society of Miss Delaval, I strove to force myself into love for her&#x2014;I admired her without reservation, and finally&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>"Finally?" whispers poor Cecil with tremulous lips.</p>				<p>"I hardly dare tell you, my child. Bell said truly that you are a lily in your pure whiteness. Still, there should be no secrets between us if we are to be man andwife. We must bare our hearts com-<pb n="210"/>pletely to one another, or there will be an end to love. Can you listen to my folly&#x2014;I might call it dishonour even&#x2014;without taking away from me the glory of my life&#x2014;your love? Remember, Cecil, that at the time I speak of, I had never held you in my arms, or touched your lips!"</p>				<p>"Tell me everything, except that you will ever again care for anyone but me!"</p>				<p>She says it gently, piteously, there is not a flash of jealousy or anger in her face, her dove eyes full of tears, but brimful of worship for him as well, although she knows now that her Bayard is not <hi rend="italic">sans peur et sans r&#x00E9;proche</hi>.</p>				<p>"My darling! Thank God that women's lives are not like men's. Their past is usually clear and unsullied, no shadow of <pb n="211"/>remorse or regret hangs over their future. If a woman came to me stained by another man's caresses, I would fling her aside, even her memory would not find a place in my heart. Yet I am asking you to forgive me something, asking you to forget even, something that occurred. Heaven knows it left no impression on me, save a good deal of shame and self-scorn. If I could, I would wipe away the thing from the tablets of memory willingly."</p>				<p>He pauses, glances at her, then with the red blood surging over his face, goes on hurriedly:</p>				<p>"One evening Miss Delaval and I were alone. That, however, was not extraordinary, for somehow&#x2014;either by accident or design&#x2014;our evenings were seldom anything but t&#x00EA;te-&#x00E0;-t&#x00EA;tes. This identical <pb n="212"/>evening, your cousin surpassed herself in beauty, and I had never admired her so much before. Her toilette was perfection, and enhanced the loveliness of her skin and her figure, and more than all, there was a soft light in her eyes, a soft look on her face. The room was full of warmth and fragrance. She was full of warmth too, her very words dropped slowly and tenderly, her singing was exquisite, her manner bewildering, and her touch&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>Cecil starts visibly&#x2014;the pallor of death creeps over her features even to her half-parted lips&#x2014;the little fingers Melville still clasps tremble as if palsy had struck them, and her eyes widen into a scared look.</p>				<p>Melville hesitates, but a strong feeling urges him to go on. He is determined that nothing in his past shall rise up <pb n="213"/>like a grim Nemesis on some future day to mar the happiness with which Cecil will crown his life. But he loves her tenfold as he notes how her feelings for him have the power to blanch her cheek and chill her whole frame.</p>				<p>"Her touch had an influence over me&#x2014;in one moment of blind unreasoning feeling I yielded to that influence, and saying words that I ought never to have uttered&#x2014;I kissed her."</p>				<p>Not a murmur&#x2014;not a reproach breaks from her colourless lips&#x2014;but Cecil shivers a little, and a half sob breaks from her.</p>				<p>Melville bends his face close to hers.</p>				<p>"It was only my lips that were given her&#x2014;my own! The heart in my breast was yours&#x2014;even then. The feelings I had for you were dominant over all. It was <pb n="214"/>that which made me recoil with almost repulsion from the mad caress. Miss Delaval is clever, beautiful, bewildering, but I do not care for her. It is you whom I love with heart and soul, body and strength."</p>				<p>As he says this, the colour flies back to her cheek, and a faint smile to her mouth. She never thinks of doubting him, especially not now, with his grave blue eyes looking down into her own.</p>				<p>"Cecil, you told me I was like a picture of Bayard."</p>				<p>"Yes."</p>				<p>"And now, since you have found out I am not sans reproche?"</p>				<p>"I love you all the same," she whispers.</p>				<p>"Thank God for that," he answers fervently.</p>				<pb n="215"/>				<p>He tells her of Bell's waylaying him the evening before.</p>				<p>"I cannot understand her wishing all this secrecy&#x2014;she is quite a paradox with her childish manners and ways&#x2014;and her solemn eyes and aphorisms."</p>				<p>Cecil laughs.</p>				<p>"We used to tease Bell and tell her that her eyes and her talk were as solemn and wise as an owl's. Even now, Claire looks upon her as quite a child, and disapproves of her having opinions of her own."</p>				<p>"Which she has, and holds to, I fancy. I should like to gratify her whim and keep our own counsel, if I could."</p>				<p>"Oh, Alan, this secret way of meeting has been so delicious I should love to let it be a little longer," she says shyly.</p>				<pb n="216"/>				<p>"But surely you would wish your relatives to be told soon&#x2014;wouldn't you?"</p>				<p>"No! I believe it would be better if no one knew yet," and then, fearful he should think her deceitful, she grows embarrassed.</p>				<p>A cloud passes over his face and he regards her in amazement&#x2014;her embarrassment troubles him, for he is naturally rather suspicious and jealous.</p>				<p>What on earth can it mean? he wonders&#x2014;her strange, disturbed manner.</p>				<p>There is such a wistful look in her eyes that he is softened in spite of his doubts.</p>				<p>"What makes you so nervous, my child? You have nothing to be frightened of&#x2014;we need no one's consent to our love, <pb n="217"/>and I don't think any earthly power could part us now!"</p>				<p>Cecil is not quite so sure since she heard of that episode with Claire&#x2014;she has lost confidence&#x2014;not in him&#x2014;but in herself. Claire is such a paragon of beauty and so worldly-wise that, if she knew about Melville and herself, she would move Heaven and earth to separate them.</p>				<p>"Still, <hi rend="italic">don't</hi> tell anyone," she pleads earnestly. "Claire will set you against me&#x2014;she will tell you things perhaps which will take away your love from me, Alan&#x2014;oh, don't tell anyone!"</p>				<p>"This is very strange," Melville says again, his face grave to sternness.</p>				<p>"At any rate give me time to think what is best," she suggests in a low voice, frightened at his expression.</p>				<pb n="218"/>				<p>Melville shakes off his doubts as he regards her. There could not be any arri&#x00E8;re pens&#x00E9;e behind that candid brow&#x2014;that truthful look.</p>				<p>"I won't tell anyone for an eternity, sweet&#x2014;since you wish it. Now smile upon me&#x2014;I feel like a poor fellow out in the cold when you look like that."</p>				<p>She smiles upon him at once, and smiles with such childlike love and trust, that she is reinstated in his heart.</p>				<p>"Claire will be coming back," she says presently, "and I had better go back to the house. Alan!"</p>				<p>"Yes, my darling."</p>				<p>"Shall you pass your evenings alone with Claire again?"</p>				<p>"No&#x2014;but if I do&#x2014;you can trust me, <pb n="219"/>Cecil. I shall be <hi rend="italic">sans r&#x00E9;eproche</hi> for ever now."</p>				<p>She is silent for a moment.</p>				<p>"Child, have I shaken your faith in me for always by my confession?" he asks reproachfully.</p>				<p>"No&#x2014;oh, no!&#x2014;but&#x2014;&#x2014;"</p>				<p>"But what?"</p>				<p>"Claire is so beautiful, and she loves you."</p>				<p>"How do you know that?"</p>				<p>"Because it would not be possible for her to do otherwise."</p>				<p>Melville bursts out laughing.</p>				<p>"My little sweetheart, don't go and stick me on a pedestal for all women to fall down and worship. Heaven knows I am no Paladin, and besides&#x2014;even if I could evoke love, I don't wrant it&#x2014;except from <pb n="220"/>you. Oh, my darling, you little know how you have crept into my heart to the exclusion of everybody else."</p>				<p>"Have I&#x2014;really and truly?"</p>				<p>"Really and truly. Joking apart, don't you know you are just as beautiful as Miss Delaval, and ten times more beautiful in expression? She would do for a Jael or a Delilah&#x2014;a couple of amiable women I dare say you know nothing about&#x2014;but you, my white-souled pet, have a face like our blessed Madonna."</p>				<p>And Melville crosses himself devoutly, for he is an earnest Eoman Catholic&#x2014;earnest in his religion as he is in most things.</p>				<p>Cecil's eyes light up with pleasure at his words, and now the smiles come in shoals, dimpling her mouth.</p>				<pb n="221"/>				<p>"Good-bye, Alan&#x2014;till to-morrow."</p>				<p>Gathering her in his arms, he says "good-bye" on her lips.</p>				<p>She runs back by one path to the house while he slowly pursues another and more circuitous one, whistling softly as he walks. He would not be so light-hearted perhaps, if he had marked a malignant look on a woman's face, a few minutes before&#x2014;a woman dressed in black, who had crept stealthily behind a laurustinus bush to listen to the sweet words he spoke to Cecil&#x2014;to mark his passionate good-bye</p>			</div>		</body>	</text></TEI.2>